RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
THE STORIES AND CHARACTERS DEPICTED
HERE WERE INSPIRED BY OUR HISTORY
NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED DURING
THE FILMING OF THIS PRODUCTION.
Father?
-Are you fine? Do you have any pain?
-Do not worry.
I am awake now. I will be up in no time.
Thank God.
Get well soon.
If you need anything Yigit can inform us.
Ertugrul. Yigit told me everything.
You and the people who raised
you are valiant people.
You saved and protected us.
We did what our customs order us to do.
There is no debt for that.
The people in these lands have long
forgotten their customs.
We must be God’s loved subjects for
someone like you to be there for us.
Please don’t say that.
I should go. And you should rest.
Listen to me, Halime.
Find us some horses immediately.
Get prepared with your brother.
Don’t let anyone get suspicious.
What is happening, father?
What will we do?
We are going.
Halime, there is no other way.
If we stay for one more day,
we would endanger their lives as well.
I am going to the stable.
Right before the headquarters,
where is this coming from, Gundogdu?
I am going to look at
the new horse they brought.
And you can start preparing
for the Aleppo journey.
I can make everything ready but...
...is it confirmed that
you will be going to Aleppo?
Don’t say that.
I was the one who put forth
the idea at the headquarters.
It is my right to be the envoy.
-Of course but...
-Of course but what?
Why are you worked up
so early in the morning, Selcan?
I don’t know whether I should worry about
the fact that you will be going or...
...the disappointment you will feel
if your father does not choose you.
Of course he will send me.
Who else can he send?
Hatun, look, if you are feeling sad
that I will be going...
...during the time I go and come back,
you can greet me with two lives.
When you are dealing with the horses in
the stable and me preparing you...
...provisions for the journey, you'd be
waiting for a very long time, Gundogdu.
I can check the horses after
the headquarters then.
Bey, do we have permission?
Come in, Hamza, come in.
-What happened?
-Bey, Suleyman Shah wants to see you.
In the name of God. In the name of God.
In the name of God.
I have decided that...
...Ertugrul will go to Aleppo.
Gundogdu.
I have some things to discuss with you.
Stay here.
Ertugrul, you go and prepare yourself.
Tell Ilyas Fakih that
he will be coming with you.
Come on!
Come on! Quick!
Faster, Turgut, faster! Come on!
Come on!
-I won!
Don’t be ridiculous, I won!
I passed the line first!
-What are you saying?
-I was the first to pass the line!
Ask Aykiz!
Aykiz cannot be the referee.
She is your sweetheart.
How can you say this, Bamsi Beyrek?
When did I ever lie?
-I told you not to do that!
-What would you do if I do?
-Your brain is as big as a walnut.
-But I am a hard nut to crack!
Don’t be afraid! Come on then! Come on!
Stop right there! Stop!
What is wrong with Ertugrul?
Suleyman Shah called him to his tent.
-I wonder what the problem is.
-He is probably going gazelle hunting.
That gazelle deserved to be hunted.
Get ready. We are going to Aleppo.
Bamsi! We are going to Aleppo, Bamsi!
I was getting fat sitting all day!
Tell Ilyas Fakih as well,
he is coming with us.
I brought up the Aleppo idea.
I told you that El Aziz needed soldiers.
Why him and not me, father?
Because of this, son.
“I know. I can do. I said.”
When did arrogance grew inside you?
Am I the arrogant one?
The whole tribe is starving.
Famine is everywhere.
We could not even go on a foray.
Why?
-Because our Bey has a boil problem.
-Know your place!
Let it go, father. The whole tribe
complains about your old age.
-Brother?
-Get your hands off me!
Do you think it is your brother’s right
to be the ambassador?
Yes.
Why me and not my brother?
Because he started to worship
the flame of power. His soul is captured.
So I put out the flame.
Now, let us talk about
the flame within you.
Our guests will stay
with the tribe until you come back.
I am telling you this so that
you can focus on your mission.
Do not come back empty handed from Aleppo.
The future of Kayi is on your shoulders.
Your failure will mean
the calamity of all of us.
For the land El Aziz is going to give us,
we shall accept any price.
But not a single Oguz
is a sacrificial lamb.
Don’t you ever forget.
As much as you need a home near Aleppo...
...Ameer  of Aleppo needs Kayi’s Alps.
Do not ever bow your head down.
Show them that you are a real Oguz...
...who knows what he wants and
is ready to make a just deal.
May God help you.
I shall succeed in my duty
even if the cost is my life, father.
I shall be back to make you proud.
What happened?
Gundogdu!
-Gundogdu, stop! Stop!
-Leave me alone!
Friends, Alps!
Stop! Please!
Out! Get out!
Aren’t you going to talk?
Ambassador.
Ertugrul became the ambassador.
-I told you!
-Enough!
Take it! Drink.
Drink this.
This must be Mother Hayme’s doing.
I don’t care less. It does not matter.
I know what I am going to do.
No! Please do not act in fury.
Those who act with fury always lose.
Enough, woman!
For the love of God, enough!
Finish your business.
Be ready with your Alps.
When that tactless brother of yours
messes everything up...
...you will get what you deserve.
And do not forget.
Angels of death wait for
the big day in the Bey’s marquee.
The news got stuck in my throat, Turgut.
I cannot swallow it...
...nor can I spit it out.
You talk like this is the first time
we will be apart, Aykiz.
When did we ever be together, Turgut?
Is waiting for the road at your father’s
tent and waiting for your man...
...in your husband’s tent be the same?
It is not the sorrow of separation
that is stuck in my throat...
...it is not being able to come together.
Anytime we talk about getting married,
it gets delayed for some reason.
I promise.
There will be no delay this time.
I don’t know whether
Aleppo will be a success or not but...
...the first wedding in our new land
will be ours. I promise you.
The drummers will cry out “Aykiz and
Turgut are finally getting married.”
All the girls in the weaving area
will say, “the most beautiful girl...
...of the tribe is getting married,
from now on it be our turn.”
When you leave Wild  Demir’s tent,
even the Sultan’s daughters will...
...get jealous of your beauty.
I wanted to say how sorry I am.
I do not know the words...
...that can describe this pain.
-Only you can understand me, Elanora.
Your father’s killers were
Muslims as well.
May you have a good journey, Titus.
Be careful.
I will be back, Elanora. See you soon.
You have witnessed a good commander
transform into a real Templar knight.
Revenge.
That was the only thing lacking in Titus.
If there is no revenge, a hay soldier
and a knight are no different.
Bisol’s death became Titus’ miracle.
May God forgive Bisol’s sins.
Looking at the presents, I can say that
Suleyman Shah realized the mistake he did.
Our Bey likes the Seljuk,
he respects them.
But only I can solve this issue,
Karatoygar.
The time limit I have put down
expires in the morning, Kurdoglu.
Or else the Seljuk’s wrath will burn
the whole Kayi tribe.
-You would burn with us, Karatoygar.
-How dare you?
Don’t tell me that
the Sultan knows about this.
Your manpower is not enough
to take them from Kayi by force.
You need to raise a whole army.
I am aware that you have armies
that are strong enough to crush Kayi.
You can do that. But first,
the Sultan would have to be informed.
And this would not suit you.
It would not suit us either.
I shall come to the point. For you and
the tribe to win at the same time...
...you need to hear what I have to say.
If you aim to cooperate...
...tell me. Who did this?
Was it Suleyman Shah?
Suleyman Shah’s son Ertugrul.
Bamsi, Dogan.
The word is out about a journey.
When?
We shall set on the road to Aleppo
at the morning prayer.
Are you prepared?
The Alps are always ready for anything.
True. Everything seems easy
when you get used to it.
Sometimes it gets harder
May you have a good journey.
May the sun not burn you.
May you don’t get cold.
May your feet don’t touch a stone.
May you go like water...
...return to your tribe like water.
My horse shall fly me to
my destination and back to my tribe.
Your father and mother would be happy.
What about you?
Me?
I would be long gone.
You cannot go...
...before I come back.
Your father would not recover fully.
May you have a good journey, Ertugrul Bey.
All of us.
There is something I wonder.
Our involuntary guests...
...are they relatives of
Sultan Aladdin or something?
-That does not concern you!
-True. It does not concern me.
Come to the point. What is on your mind?
If you want to take what you want,
I shall have one small condition.
Ertugrul...
...whatever my late wife and Aykiz are...
...Halime and her family are the same
for me. Don’t you worry about them.
May God bless you, Wild  Demir.
May God bless you instead.
Trust makes a man grow.
You trusted me in this tribe,
you came to my door, you confided in me...
...that is why, may God bless you. Halime
and her family are my responsibility.
You can be rest assured.
Come on, may God be with you.
My son. My life.
My dear son...
...may your road
and fortune be always open.
The weight of Kayi is on your shoulders...
...never bow your head
nor give a promise you cannot keep.
May God give you a clear road.
You may be going and not coming back.
You may come back but not see me.
I will ride tirelessly to see you again.
May you have a clear road, Ertugrul.
While you were being punished for
rebelling against your father...
...the little Bey became the ambassador.
I knew you would come.
Welcome.
I don’t care about the prisoners,
Karatoygar.
They ran away in your territory.
We did our part.
Give me the name of the person
who killed my brother.
You are impatient to become a hangman.
Be careful, don’t let the noose of
the hangman get around you neck.
Don’t try to delegate
your own inaptitude to me.
The knights you brag about could not
deal with a few trifling Alps.
What do you want from me to give his name?
I will give you more than you want.
I will deliver him directly to you.
This is not an issue of business.
Do you understand me?
It is an assistance to a friend in pain.
We never let ourselves stay indebted
on any help we receive.
Alright.
Who?
Suleyman Shah’ son...
...Ertugrul.
Aykiz...
...can you look at these patterns as well?
I won’t be long.
When are you leaving?
When my father says so.
Do not try to stand strong.
People do not stay in a place
where they are not wanted.
If you have some sense of shame,
go at once.
It is customary.
You cannot say go to a guest.
That is why everyone keeps quiet.
And...
...will you paying your debt
to these people like this?
Is this what you deem proper for people
who gave you bread, their own tent...
...and dressed your wounds?
-I...
-You...
While you try to flirt around,
blood will be spilt in the tribe.
Blood. Go your own way.
Halime. Halime!
Selcan!
What did you tell the girl?
What she needed to hear.
Is it your duty to tell her
what she needs to hear?
I am thinking about
the future of the tribe.
That girl should have heard this long ago.
Such a shame.
Daugther of a Bey forgets our customs.
She talks on top of the words
of her forefathers.
Come to your senses, Selcan.
Otherwise, you might find yourself
under the stones you thought you crushed.
-What happened?
-Mind your own business!
Ertugrul has gone on a journey
with four Alps.
Eye for an eye. Devine justice.
-Where is he going?
-To Aleppo.
I shall take revenge with my own hands.
I can never let you do that, Titus.
Why?
These lands are my jurisdiction.
In my borders, only I can use force.
If it is heard that I made an alliance
with the crusaders to spill blood...
...our plan would fail.
This man killed my brother, Karatoygar.
I want you to bring him to me alive.
I shall take his life with my own hands.
Don’t you worry. I will present him to you
like a sacrificial ram.
Karatoygar is convinced, Bey.
He wanted us to look after them
until they get better.
Did you manage to learn who they are?
The pig’s son did not even utter
a single word about it.
If they made the great Seljuks stand up,
the issue must be serious.
Our part should be to benefit from this.
You asked for me, Bey.
If you don’t have anything else to say,
you must be very tired, go and rest.
Save me from this pest of a boil,
Akcakoca.
If God permits, Bey.
My death will be from this.
-Inform me of all developments.
-As you wish, Bey.
Everything is ready, father.
I have all the provisions ready,
we will be going tonight.
Don’t worry about your wound, I watched
Akcakoca very closely to see what he does.
Halime, calm down, my girl.
We will be running away from a place
we took refuge, as usual. That is all.
Is that all, father?
Is it only that for you?
I don’t know what goes through
your mind but...
...what makes this place
different for you?
Is there anything you are not telling me?
I am very tired, father.
I am tired of running away.
Let us start a new life.
Go some place where no one will find us.
Let us go beyond deserts and seas
but go from here, that is all I want.
Father?
What happened, son? What happened, Yigit?
We have a guest. He wants to come in.
Let him in.
-Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you.
Please.
Father, look. Wild  Demir made
a sword for you and my sister.
He is the best ironsmith in the region.
He makes the best swords.
Please don’t exaggerate, son.
Ours is only a pastime.
-These are yours.
-Thank you.
Don't mention it, my girl.
As Ertugrul Bey is not here,
I did not want you to be without weapons.
He would feel more comfortable.
I would do too.
Anyway, I am at my workshop
but my eye is on your tent.
If you need anything,
please do not hesitate.
What could happen in a big tribe?
Look, my girl.
Ertugrul Bey is like a son to me.
So I would never turn back his request.
This was not called for.
We will go this way.
Tell Ertugrul that horses should
rest a bit. They are exhausted.
His mind is with Halime.
He wants to return before they go.
If you have the courage, you tell him.
Bey.
Us being exhausted is not an issue
but the horses are very tired.
Bey, shall we rest a bit
beside the stream?
We can set camp down there.
We will set off before sunrise.
-Dogan, light a fire.
-As you wish, Bey.
Follow me quietly.
Peace be upon you.
And peace be upon you.
What happened to the gazelle?
We found it like this. It was probably
wounded while running away from a hunter.
I think that hunter was me.
If you let this game get away,
you must be a bad hunter.
I guess so.
Look at that beautiful face. So you
managed to escape from this big valiant.
Well done to you.
In the name of God, may you recover soon.
Come on now. Go. Go on.
Where do you come from and
where do you go?
We come from nowhere, to go anywhere.
What about you?
We are going to Aleppo.
Then you should always be alert.
Don’t become a hunt for
wolves and vultures.
The air here is very hazy.
Don’t be lost in the haze.
Will you grant me your name?
Ibn Arabi from Andalusia.
Translation: Suzan Mıhladız