Revival
The inspiration of the story and characters in this series is our history.
No animals were harmed in the making of this film.
Translated by Balistic, Emre Sahin, Emin Pala, Ammama3434
1225 Kayi Clan Camping Side.
[They get strength from Allah's name while forging iron]
Even the iron couldn't resist our words and gained faith.
Wait a bit...
Take a look at this, if you'd like, eh?
how magnificent! (maşallah)
I feel sorry for the enemy whom's life will be taken by this sword.
May a brave man like you be the voice and wrath to those who act unfairly. (inşallah)
(note: inşallah means hoping something with God's will)
There is no sword like the Zulfiqar... and there is no soldier like Ali was...
(note: Ali ibn Abu Talib is an Islamic historical person, known as a great soldier with his famous sword the Zulfiqar.)
I love the God who created a man like you.
It will be honor to carry this sword for the love of Allah
and in the name of my ancestor Oğuz.
(note: Oğuz are ancient Turkic and/or Uygur tribes. meaning literally "tribe".)
Come on, show me your hands.
What's up? Your men are acting all energetic again.
We're going out hunting.
They are getting ready.
Is there any animal left to become prey in this land?
You are right, but...
What makes warriors united is hunting.
It would be better if we could find a solution to keep the tribe united.
That solution will only come from tomorrow's meeting.
If we don't migrate from this highland before winter,
we all will be in great trouble.
But, if you have a solution, let us know as well. Eh?
My brother Gündoğdu is better with these subjects.
You can talk with him, if you want to.
Gündoğdu?
(sniggering)
No way. He doesn't breathe a word of it.
So this is what you spend 40 akçes on?
This is called a map.
What is it good for?
Now look...
We are here.
...right where these mountains are.
This is Aleppo.
This is Bagdat.
And this is Damascus.
And this is Konya where Sultan's palace is located.
Nevermind where sultans' or the nobles' palaces are...
Just tell me where this tribe will migrate, Gündoğdu.
Beys can't think clearly. Your father hasn't said anything.
He just perches like a sad owl in his tent.
(note: a Bey is a title used as a chieftain, or a leader of a tribe. but can also mean something like sir/mister/lord. Which one of the meaning is used can also vary per situation. )
Where is this place?
Everyone will learn at the meeting tomorrow.
You found it, didn't you?
Come on, tell me where is it? Huh?
Ertuğrul!
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
I AM GOING HUNTING.
COULDN'T YOU PICK ANOTHER TIME?
WE HAVE A MEETING TOMORROW.
THE MEETING IS YOURS, AND THE HUNT IS MINE, BROTHER!
THANK YOU. DON'T GO TOO FAR...
GO FAST! COME BACK QUICKLY.
What's up, Bamsı? What's with that pastrami?
We are going hunting. Have you forgotten that?
We won't let you starve during the hunting; don't you worry.
Turgut, you can't call a man as a brave man
if he starves during the hunting.
It is just to boost our ego's during our trip.
We're screwed if we are going to boost your ego.
Come on warriors!
Yours (crush) is leaving.
Amanos Mountains
Knights Templar Castle
THE WATCH...
... IS YOUR HONOR!
THE WATCH IS YOUR HONOR!
IF YOU WALK OVER YOUR HONOR AND VIRTUE,
INSTEAD OF YOUR ENEMY...
YOU WON'T DIE BY THE ENEMY'S HAND, BUT BY MINE!
It's an honor to have you here Grand Master.
The honor is ours...
Elenora...
Commander Titus...
I hope you had a good trip.
Is everything alright, Titus?
We are safer than ever before, sir.
Your rooms are ready, sir,
Would you like to get some rest before the dinner?
Elenora can get some rest but we have things to do, Commander.
As you wish.
If you'll excuse me...
What is the status of the prisoners?
I put my brother Bisol in charge.
They will deliver Numan and his family to Kara Toygar.
I've been waiting for you for the rest.
That's great...
Where are they taking us, dad?
To our palace, son.
Then, we will be freed there, right?
Forever, son, forever...
It seems, it was our destiny to return to Konya like this.
To die in the palace where were born and raised... by our uncle's hand.
Daughter, I will not allow anything to happen to you and your brother.
Kara Toygar will be tied to us entirely after this move.
It is very important that he wins Sultan Alaaddin's favor.
We will be able to catch our breath once Kara Toygar
is assigned to a high level position in the Selçuk' palace.
KARATOYGAR CARAVANSARY
We did everything as you requested, sir.
OK!
Commander!
Are Turkmen Tribes paying their taxes?
We can't control them, sir. They are constantly moving.
Which tribe is the largest?
Kayi Tribe, sir.
They were driven here because of the Mongolian invasion.
- Who is its leader?
- Suleyman Shah.
- How many tents?
- 2000. But, they are very well maintained.
- Do they pay their taxes?
- They do, sir.
Great.
Then, have them pay their taxes early this year.
But, sir...
You heard what I said.
How will this country stay on it's feet otherwise?
Inform all the tribes within the region right away!
Yes, my commander.
Why are these Knights Templar so late?
STOP!
Let's get some rest here.
Stay on watch around.
We have to break the strength of the Selçuks before the crusade.
Titus, you need to place more men into the Selçuk' Palace.
You can be sure that we will get hold of the entire palace.
Some people in the Vatican don't want to start the crusades.
I am not suprised at all.
We have to make a plan to bring entire Europe into action.
We have to succeed in this.
The crusaders must unite and act to capture Jerusalem.
To do this, we must provoke Muslims and incur their anger.
I have very precious prisoners.
We can start with them.
Shush... Calm down boy.
Yiğit.
Filthy runt.
Go to hell.
Just get us there as soon as possible...
Do you want to die so soon, eh?
I feel sorry for your beautiful daughter and your young şehzade (prince).
Don't get so upset for us.
If you allied with us, you could have become the Selçuk' sultan.
And we were going to move on.
You offered me to be pope's slave.
We offered you peace and a new world order.
We wanted to be together.
But...
Muslim blood will shed.
You won't be able to escape this.
And it will be our allied muslim friends, who will help us shed your bloods.
You won't succeed.
We will see how it ends.
By the way, tell the men of yours I send to hell...
my regards.
The area is safe, sir.
Good, give the horses water.
...and them, too.
You two... Sit somewhere else.
I brought you water. Take it.
Take it...
Come on...
- There is nobody coming,
- The key... Take the key...
Come on daughter...
Hurry up!
Look, this is our fortune.
The prisoners are escaping!
- Run!
- Catch them!
- Father!
- Father, are you alright?
- Father?
Hurry up! Take your brother and go!
No!
Father!
Hurry up! Run!
- Go!
- Father!
I said,take your brother and run...
Father...
Come on father, get up! Come on!
Escaping, eh? I'll show you!
Father...
Father!
Help God, Help!
- Father!
-We need to stop the bleeding!-
Your fortune was the crusaders.
Hold on... Hold on, father.
Turgut... Oak leaves... - Yes my bey.
If we succeed, the borders of this entire geography will change.
We shouldn't hesitate to spend fortunes of our brethren for our liberation of Jerusalem's.
We are ready to spend all the wealth.
An expedition to Jerusalem is the easiest way to get rich for young men.
They will massively join the crusaders army to be its soldier
Catalans... Venetians,.
People of Marseilles...
All of them will want to be a part of this carnival.
Well... These spoiled princes of Europe...
How will we trust them?
While muslims are fighting with each other...
...our job will be easier this time, Titus.
What about the Selçuks, my master?
Anatolia... is having its best days under the rule of Sultan Alaaddin.
We will reach our goal once we play the Turks against Selahaddin Eyyubi's descendants.
Jerusalem will be ours.
Okay, father. It's nearly done father.
Okay.
Let's head out as soon as possible.
You go.
We can take care of ourselves.
It's going to get dark soon.
Probably, coyotes have already smelled the blood.
Bamsı Beyrek... ... Doğan.
Bring the horses.
It's easy to defeat a couple of crusaders. Here we go...
Ertugrul is really going to get in trouble now.
God watches over those in trouble my brother.
He is in great trouble.
Come on.
What can you even do on your own?
I said we are not coming.
We owe you our lives.
We will pay back one day. Tell me your name.
Ertuğrul from the Kayi tribe.
As you wish.
May God help you. Good luck.
Please, let's go with them.
Is your encampment too far?
(hammering)
We are out of our (critical) reserve money, brother Afşin.
We set up our shop here. If our business doesn't sell, then we will depart as soon as possible.
- Peace be upon you. Have a nice day,
- Peace be upon you too, Welcome.
Welcome, Gazanfer Ağa. (Ağa meaning senior)
It's a pleasure to see you here at the Kayi's.
Hey, my brother Kurdoglu.
You seem to be in good shape, how wonderful (thank God).
This environment doesn't keep people alive. How can I look alive, Gazanfer?
No, don't say that. You look good, wonderful (note: maşallah means praise be to God) .
- Where is your caravan?
- My caravan is waiting at Karakaya.
I came here to get permission from Süleyman Shah to set up a shop at the bazaar.
- How is your business,
- I thank for what God bestowed.
I just wanted to meet the needs of Kayi before it migrates.
Thank you Gazanfer. I hope you find what you expected.
Thanks.
I want to visit Suleyman Shah if he is available.
Let him know that Gazanfer Aga is here!
- How many akçe is this? - He is mute sir, let me help you.
80 akçe.
You are very familiar.
This is my first visit to your encampment. I guess you confuse me with someone else.
Peace be upon you Süleyman Shah.
And peace be upon you, trader.
Welcome. It's a pleasure to see you. Come in.
Suleyman Bey, just let me say how happy my eyes are to see you once again.
Please accept my gifts, my bey.
I brought these for you from Constantinople.
Why did you bother?
Kurdoğlu...
Give these to those who need them.
Yes, my bey.
And?
Tell me what those eyes of yours saw in other lands.
If wish I was deaf and didn't hear what happened.
I wish my eyes were carved out and didn't see what happened, sir.
What's wrong, I hope it's fortunate ?
Sultan Alaaddin has created order in Konya .
However, he is afraid that runaway princes can cause trouble.
The Latins ruined Constantine.
All of the Orthodoxes are leaving the city.
There is corruption and no peace... And on top of that, people are very desperate because of the drought.
We've heard that surviving crusaders were on the boil.
Obviously, they are up to no good.
Well...
What about the crusaders?
They will be on the move again to fill their needs.
Sir, there are rumors that the Pope is calling all princes in Europe for the crusades.
And we, Muslims, are busy with fighting with each other and sowing discord among us.
And add fuel to the fire of sedition.
There is fire everywhere from Anatolia to Basra.
This fire will affect us as well, my bey.
Sir, please don't say "fire". It makes me fee unwell.
I am here to get your approval to sell my goods in the encampment, my bey.
I approve it.
Thank you.
Kara Toygar has come to the region to knock some sense into Turkmen nomads.
So, difficult times are ahead of us.
This girl is from Venice; Rosalina.
She is a noblewoman. White skin... Green eyes...
Women like her are very rare, Commander.
On top of that, she is a bargain. I am hard pressed these days.
This is a golden opportunity for both of us.
What about her, Commander?
She was kidnapped from Greek Islands.
She is very young and beautiful.
She is like a wild mare.
I trained her myself. She is for masters with refined taste.
What about that blonde one?
I have to say that you are very tasteful, Commander.
I bought her from the survivors of the crusaders
They brought her on a ship. She is Serbian. She knows very well how to serve men.
Silence.
Come here.
You don't have to be afraid of me.
I am your master now.
Commander, you chose the most expensive one.
But she's worth it.
- My lord...
- What happened?
The crusaders...
The crusaders were attacked.
And you did not save them?
We were too late, my lord.
You couldn't save them, eh???
Akçakoca!
We have a wounded!
Bamsı!
Take the wounded.
My Turgut, what happened?
- There is nothing to worry about,
- You're alright, right?
Thank God, all of us are fine.
Ertugrul...
What's going on, brother?
We were attacked, brother.
I'll tell you later.
Hamza, keep an eye on them.
Yes, sir.
Who are they, Gundogdu?
I don't know, our bey (sarcasm) said he will tell it later.
We'll find out soon.
Sister, what happened? Who are they?
We will find out very soon.
The sword cut is right under his rib.
Luckily, the oak leaf stopped the bleeding.
Otherwise, he could have died.
Midwife, bring hot water immediately.
Right away, Akçakoca.
His leg is bad, too.
But, let's take care of this wound first.
Akçakoca will handle the rest.
Let's wait at the other room.
Sister, let's not leave our father alone.
Don't worry.
Your father is in safe hands.
Thank you very much.
God has send you to us.
We have caused a lot of trouble to you.
Don't mention it.
It was not your time yet.
Where were the Crusaders taking you to?
I don't know.
They did not tell us.
They were probably going to sell us at the captives market I think--
My father.... is a tradesman ,we were captured at the Mediterranean Sea.
Your father must be a good tradesman.
Since so many crusaders were taking you.
Yes.
We were rich.
But we don't have anything anymore.
Well....
What is this encampent?
You are at the Kayi tribe encampment.
I am the son of the Bey (chief) of our encampent: Süleyman Shah.
We owe you three lives.
Do you want to be freed from slavery?
(nodding yes)
Then kill this man.
No!
I will buy you and free you.
My commander, you are upset.
Please calm down.
---Shut up!
Don't make me kill you too!
Sir!, Forgive me, my wife and child.
Clumsy Asshole!
Do it!
I can't do it!
I said DO IT!
(stabbing)
(laughing)
I am setting you free. -Ah!
To be freed...
...The slave who kills a man....
...The day will come....
...He will kill his/her lord.
Get yourselves ready! We're taking off!
My Bey (lord).
It's ready. Come and have a seat.
(music - Ney instrument)
Dündar.
Come my son, join us too.
Let me finish this job, one minute mother.
Always be like this my lion.
Don't start new things before finishing your current task.
-Selcan. -Yes mother.
bring the molasses my girl. -On it's way mother.
Where's Gündoğdu?
Eh.. He went to visit the Shepherds. He'll come soon.
Add one more plate to the table.
It's for Sungur Tekin.
If the kid returns one day, he should know he has a place at this table.
Come now.
What is taking Gündoğdu so long?
He will be here soon mother.
Heh!
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim. (In the name of Allah)
Well child, you came back with a great hunt again.
Yes my Bey, that sort of happened.
Wonderful of you my brother.
You're like a tree attracting lightning in the middel of a plain.
You're attracting all kinds of trouble.
The oppressed were being attacked.
We did everything we could do.
Who are they? Whose people are they?
They were captured by the crusaders.
Apparently, the man is a tradesman.
My Bey, they are probably from the crusaders' county in Antakya.
Knights, on the Selcuk's lands....
....would not randomly carry captives.
So?
So I mean....
The Selcuk's must know about these captives.
There was no Selcuk' Soldier among them.
Sooner or later we will figure out what kind of trouble you got in.
What should I have done brother? Should I just have let them be?
Shush, both of you.
You have to welcome them in a befitting manner to the Kayi's.
Let's see how it will turn out.
(Howling wolf)
It's over, you will get better.
Do I have permission?
Feel welcome, my Bey.
How is he doing?
From now on it's God's will.
With your permission.
Come Aykız.
Aykız, Turgut's beloved.
I wanted to ask if you needed something.
Thank you.
We are already enough of a burden to you.
What are you talking about?
Bamsı Beyrek and Doğan, are preparing their tents for you.
You will spend your night there.
I......
It's better if I stay beside my father.
Rest a bit tonight. You seem distraught.
When your father wakes up tomorrow, he will need you a lot more.
Do not worry, I will stay beside your father.
Yah! my Bey, Yah!
how did you grow this boil all this time?
These boils are no big deal to us Hayme.
Should I get afraid of such a small betrayal now?
But if you just had crushed this problem from the beginning, then now you would've...
The coyotes were on the mountains in the past, now they came as close as to our homes.
They wait for my slightest error to sweep down on me.
I hide this boil so they do not see and know my weakness.
Rather than becoming their gossip subject....
I prefer being silent and broiled in pain.
You should have told Akçakoca at least.
I did tell him my wife. I did.
He is preparing a healing ointment.
We will apply it this evening if it's fortunate.
Ohh!
What's wrong? Are you thinking about our guests?
I wonder which one of the sleeping dogs we woke up Hayme.
(music - Middle Eastern)
(coughing in distance)
(clicking noises)
(drawing sword)
-(Aykız) Did you wear it? -(Halime) Yes.
-(Aykız) How is it? -(Halime) Very beautiful , Aykız.
Wait a minute.
Oh my God! You're like an angel from a palace Halime.
You look really beautiful.
What's wrong?
Did I say something wrong?
No.
It just felt a bit weird hearing you say that.
Wait let's put on this headgear too.
Turgut Alp (title: Brave, Hero) bought me this.
Oh my, then why are you giving it to me now?
Because I knew it would look very great on you.
Let me see.
It really fits you.
When is your wedding?
Hopefully after we migrate from the highlands, (with the will of God)
Aykız, isn't it hard to be the wife of an Alp (hero)?
If his heart only beats for me, then the hardship has no importance to me.
Let him come back to his room unharmed, I do not need anything else.
If he just does not die.
Come let's braid your hair too if you want, he?
Yes, let's do it.
Do you have a lover?
After my mother died, I had to be a parent for Yiğit....
and a companion for my father, nothing else happened in my life.
And besides, what guy would like someone like me.....
A aaa! Are you crazy!
Guys would kill each other for you.
They would bring you all the gold in the world.
When was the last time you looked in a mirror?
Wait.
Isn't this the brother of the Giaour (infidel) named Titus?
Yes my lord, Bisol.
Send these bodies to the templars.
Now we have to deal with Titus too.
You, you, come here.
Take these and load them on the horses.
To which tribe does this weapon belong to?
The Kayi's, my lord.
The Kayi's huh.
It's going to be a problem, if they are in the hands of Süleyman Shah .
He's a shepherd chief. You think he will oppose a Selcuk' ?
(sheep and pigeon noises)
Good morning Ertuğrul.
You too.
I brought you food.
You did bother, sister Gökçe.
How is our wounded doing?
Good, he will be able to get up soon inşallah (hopefully with God's will).
Inşallah (hopefully with God's will).
May God give curing, so that at least he will not be troublesome to us.
(Aykız) I'll come too in a minute, then from there we will go to the household.
(Halime) Okay Aykız.
-How is my father doing Ertuğrul Bey (chief)? -Good. Very good.
You will see it too when you go inside. His fever reduced.
We will move him to your tent this evening inşallah (with Gods will).
Did you see the girl, she already has Ertuğrul in the palm of her hand.
From now on, you will only see him in your dreams.
Did you sleep comfortable?.
I haven't slept so comfortable in years.
In the forest, you said templars too me.
Yes?
Who are they?
A sect fighting to gain Jerusalem.
They are very strong and ruthless.
They want nothing except avenging Jerusalem.
If they are so strong, then what do they want from you?
-Is this land of the Selçuks? - Yes.
Do you have an issue with the Selçuks, Halime?
Ofcourse not.
What would the Great Selçuks want from people like us?
enjoy.
Ahh!
What happened my girl?
It's nothing dad, I just didn't see it.
Haa, even so, mind if you tell me whatever is on your mind anyway he?
If you want something really bad, it doesn't happen dad..
I learned this.
Who taught you that?
Turgut Alp and I were going to marry if we migrated...
...We have been waiting patiently to migrate.
Winter is coming.
And we still don't know where we are going to migrate to.
I understand. You've become as impatient as your late mother was.
Just look around you, winter will never pass in the highlands of these great mountains.
Why do you think we gather in the meetings?
Why do you think all the Beys (chiefs) are crowding into Süleyman Shah's tent?
We're going to sit, talk and solve this issue inşallah (with God's will).
Come now, don't worry. give me my waistcoat, I shouldn't get late.
Oh my sweetest Aykız.
The gathering for the meeting will start soon Kurdoğlu.
Nobody knows what they should do.
With God's trust we will handle this.
Kurdoğlu, the mountains have become quiet...
...the rivers wont gurgle, the sky stopped raining.
We're cornered in this plain.
If this continues, our animals are going to go to waste even more.
Babies will die.
Well then, what do you think of?
Whatever suits you best Kurdoğlu.
Our commitment is to you. Show your value from now on.
Süleyman Shah is weak. He cannot even claim one horse.
You must understand Kurdoğlu...
....The one who rides the horse owns it, the one who wields the sword owns it.
Mother.
I came to get some healing herbs from Akçakoca.
He went out.
Tell me what you need, I'll go get it for you mother.
No No. I'll get some later.
Our guest.
Numan Bey's daughter, Halime.
Welcome to our encampent my girl.
- How is your father? Good I hope? - Good.
Very glad to hear. May God help him heal.
You're always welcome to us.
If you have worries, do not hesitate to tell us. Okay?
May God bless you, lady Hayme.
(Small gathering prayer)
Neither on land, nor in the sky, will you find the one carried in the heart of a pure believer...
...For he is the Most merciful and most compassionate, the names of God.
Between the blue sky and the dark sky...
there are our descendants!... tribes!... homes!... sons!... daughters!...
Let them be one!... be free!... be alive!...
...let this meeting, led under the justifying head-chief, be blessed!
Amen!
He who creates in instances...
and fill's our hearts with faith, with the Great Allahs 99 names...
Ya Bismillah. (In the name of God)
(Translators note: Bismillah is being said before starting any action, as prayer for support )
(The chiefs are thanking him)
My chiefs, my brave ones...
...the elders of my tribe...
I welcome you all, I'm happy to see all of you.
(thanking him again)
Thank God, right before we were going to move our wares, a tradesman showed up.
I say, let's sell our wares for what they are worth.
This way, traveling without wares will be a lot easier for us.
If only our only concern were the wares, then it would have been great.
There are no grassfields left in our neighbourhood to let our animals graze in.
They don't drink water or give milk anymore. They've gone to waste because of their hunger.
We must find a solution as soon as possible.
I know our situation very well too.
We contacted all the chiefs in the neighbourhood, asking for a new home.
However, the dryness is everywhere.
And the Türkmen tribes who fled from the Mongolian bandits split up everywhere.
What do you want me to do? Cross swords with our brothers to gain land?
Did God stop giving us his mercy, my bey?
We have been waiting here for months.
We're not finding a solution. Since when did the Kayi's become so helpless?
Isn't there a place we can move to?
If we cannot find a solution,... How will we keep the tribe standing?
Really? Since when did God who always provided us, abandon us?
We have always acted with patience..... We only get, whatever comes to us.
I learned what patience is ever since we are traveling without a place to go to. Deli Demir.
But the next generations shouldn't live without a home.
Don't you tell me what patience is!
When have I ever left you without clothes?... Left you in hunger?...
...that you have become so desperate for sustenance?
Far from it, my lord! I did not mean it like that.
My lord, you have never left us without food nor clothes.
However, we too have never left you without soldiers nor defense.
My bey, our thoughts are...
...Let's find a new place and migrate.
Where?
Anywhere the majority of us can survive at.
Let's migrate back to our fatherland. They say the Mongolian bandits have weakened.
Whoever said that, it's a lie.
The mongolian bandits are monsters like hungry wolves.
My bey, don't we have any solution at all?
Aleppo. (note: Halep, ancient city in north Syria)
I heard that Aleppo's authority, El Aziz....
...is gathering force to oppose the crusaders.
What is it you're thinking of, nephew?
I say, let's send El Aziz a messenger.
let him ask for land to let us settle at, and in return we will offer him protection/strength.
This way, he will fight the crusaders, where we will become war veterans...
...and will we finally get to gain our own home.
Aleppo.
Let's act immediately my bey.
Since when do we act before I said so?
I appologize my bey. (Estağfurullah)
Do we accept Gündoğdu’s idea, chiefs?
(bowing, hand placed on heart) We accept. It's fitting. (note: gesture means you answer with your heart)
I too find it suitable.
It will be fortunate with God's will.
(Inşallah) With God's will!
Well, then who will go as our messenger my bey?
(drum sounds)
(music - Action)
Ertuğrul.
Süleyman Shah, your thoughtless people have broken our honor.
The honor of a sultan who gave us this land, is also my honor Kara Toygar.
What have we done to Sultan Alâaddin....
...and his commander that we broke their honor?
This axe, was inside the back of the man you killed.
Did you forget your axe there?
It seems I did.
you ambushed and slaughtered the crusaders who came as messengers.
And as if it was not enough...
...you kidnapped three convicts they were bringing to the sultan.
Give us back those captives.
You talk as if you don't know our tradition Kara Toygar.
We will not hand over our tribe's guests. Especially if they are injured.
I came here as the representive of the Sultan of the Selcuk's.
Just as how you have to follow the Sultan's orders, you have to follow my words.
You know what will happen on the contrary, Süleyman Shah.
We live with our tradition, we will die with our tradition, Kara Toygar.
We know that the Sultan is a man of a state.
But first comes our ancestor Oğuz's tradition. Thats how you build a throne.
A man who knows no tradition, cannot become a Sultan.
Neither can he become a Bey (chief)
Nor a man!
And we don't do business with someone who cannot become a man.
You should know that as a commander of the gigantic Selcuk empire.
That's the last thing I will say to you.
Now go away.
We asked you this with our concern Süleyman Shah.
You have 2 days to decide.
If you don't hand them over, then I will know how to come and get them.
(throws axe)
Do not oppose the Selcuk empire. Or you know what will happen to you.
What is my father trying to do?
He doesn't know what he's doing anymore, due to his age.
I told you whatever they were hiding, it wouldn't last long.
You just wait, there's more to come.
You stay here.
(saying the Islamic creed. note: in this case they are words of martyrdom)
The head-assistant of the Selcuk' Sultan Alâaddin Keykubat.
The commander of the Khwarazmians.
The Caliphates' right hand, Ömer.
Now let the whole Islamic world pursue revenge.
And then, it will be the pope's turn.
Bisol!!
Who did this?!
They were ambushed when they were bringing the captives.
I said who!
The Kayi's.
But we don't know who either.
Ertuğrul!
You got us in trouble!
Don't push me brother.
When are you going to stop being so stubborn, ha?!
Nobody cares about them. Neither your father, nor the whole tribe.
If it were you, what would you do? He? What would you do?
Would you just let them go and walk away?
The Gündoğdu I know is not a man like that.
The Gündoğdu I know, is a man of a state and a man of mercy.
"A state" he says!..
"Mercy" he says!..
What state he?! What mercy?!
Look at our tribe's situation! It's crumbling!
There's hunger everywhere.
Winter is coming! And we don't even know where we will migrate to.
The animals have gone to waste because of their hunger.
But "state" he says...
"Mercy" he says!..
Now open your eyes... open your eyes!
Take a look around you!
Just right when we were in the middle of the meeting...
...we were discussing vital subjects, and look what you have done!
How is this tribe going to stay on it's feet, Ertuğrul? How?
Forgive me, father...
... I couldn't protect him.
I couldn't protect him.
The world is too big to reign over, so why would we be meant to reign over it Aktolgalı.
Why do we have to live in this fake world?
Why do we have to ride horses?
Why do we have to carry swords?
Why do we have to settle a home?
a so called state, tradition, settlement,... why do they exist huh?
How cruel, if we don't hand over the guests, he claims he will break us down.
Who says we won't break down if we do hand them over?
What should I do Aktolgalı?
For this world, where we cannot even afford to breath...
...should we just lower our heads?
Should we just let the cruelties be?
Then won't it be our traditions end?
Then won't our fireplace get extinguished?
Well, Aktolgalı?
Kara Toygar is a cruel man, he wil probably do all kinds of evil things.
You thought well about Aleppo, Gündoğdu.
You like how demonstrated your intelligence to everyone...
...you also demonstrated who will be our next leader, when the time comes.
We should first get rid of this troublesome Kara Toygar.
When my father mentions the traditions, he will not back down.
Oh, Ertuğrul, Oh!
Look what you have got us into.
We need to persuade my father.
If we can convince him, then we will win over Ertuğrul too.
You talk as if you don't know your father.
Even if the world crumbles, he won't hand over the captives.
Then what do we do?
Your father told me he is going to send me to Kara Toygar as his messenger.
I'll handle the rest.
Ertuğrul Bey.
Do you have a moment?
What's wrong, did something bad happen?
No.
I wanted to talk about today.
I'm listening.
I heard Kara Toygar came today.
He demanded us.
Yes he did.
Don't put your tribe in danger because of us.
We will take care of ourselves.
My father is recovering fast. We will leave as soon as possible.
Even if the world would collapse...
...we wouldn't hand you over to those cruel men.
If you engage in a bloody fight with Kara Toygar, this won't end well.
Don't worry.
We Kayi's are good at confronting all sorts of difficulties.
(Hayme) What's wrong?
I can't sleep mother.
Come sit down.
What's keeping you awake?
I fell into a burning pit mother, and it's a big one.
I wouldn't mind if it were just me.
I threw this whole tribe into the fire with me.
In the end, did you know this was going to happen?
Would you know that you would oppose those infidel bandits....
...or about that joke of a commander working together with the crusaders?
Well, how about that sweet girl...
...could you have walked away from their screams of help?
How could I ever do that, mother?
You could never do that, ofcourse.
You wouldn't do that, son.
You couldn't.
You couldn't neither possibly know what would happen when you went hunting...
...nor that you would throw us all into the fire.
You did throw into the fire.
Yes, you did.
some fires turn everything into ash.
and some fires mold their content into something strong.
The fire you fell in is the latter one.
Neither you nor the tribe has the right to riot.
This is an exam from God.
This exam can result in turning into ash, or getting stronger.
That's why you need to make sure your delusions...
...and the people in this tribe who don't know their place, are being ignored.
Be the soldier of our tribe, son.
Stay beside your fathers orders.
May God always let us have you and my father with us.
And may God protect you, son.
Now go take this water and put it next to your father.
I came to bring you water, father.
Give it, give it.
It should have been me instead of you.
I will continue to fight the ones who did this to you, until there's no one left among them.
I will fight until they all lie burried under the earth.
Your death will not be in vain, little brother.
I promise you.
If God will not support my revenge...
I'll turn towards the devils.
I will carry the Hell towards the Türkmens.
Until I die, I will become their wrath.
I promise you.
Forgive me father.
(Prayer in Latin)
(Süleyman Şah) This is how it is, scholar İlyas.
I don't know how to react to this dream.
But I've been feeling unwell since yesterday night.
There are two possible meanings my bey.
The first one is: there are difficult times awaiting us.
The second: It's a spiritual/moral command of who has to be the messenger.
Dad?
Are you alright? Do you have any pain dad?
Dont worry. I am awake now.
I will recover very quickly.
Thank goodness.
Get well soon.
If you need something, send Yiğit to us.
Ertuğrul, Yiğit told me everything.
You and the ones who raised you are great people.
You embraced us, protected us.
We do whatever our tradition requires us to do. Without debts.
It's been a while since the people on this land forgot their traditions.
God must love us, if he allowed us to meet people like you.
Estağfurullah (Don't mention it).
I should leave. And you should rest.
www.tvsubtitles.net