RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
THE STORIES AND CHARACTERS DEPICTED
HERE WERE INSPIRED BY OUR HISTORY
NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED DURING
THE FILMING OF THIS PRODUCTION.
If something happens to me...
...Shahzade's daughter Halime,
her brother who is our prisoner...
...and your Alp Turgut...
...may turn up dead.
I already took my precautions, Ertugrul.
I have so many men in this palace
who will take the life of Halime...
...where Titus' arrow had failed.
I am not even counting
the ones in Kayi.
What happened, Ertugrul?
Did you abandon the idea of killing me?
Go on, kill me.
Why did you stop? Kill me, Ertugrul!
I will expose the people
who made you do this one by one.
Then...
...may God be my witness that I shall
kill you with my own hands, Nasir.
Guards!
Catch him!
Don't let him escape! Bring him to me!
I saw him, he is running away.
He went that way! Catch him!
Please...
...do not get up.
How is the sunlight of my palace?
I am better, thank you.
This is great.
I talked with the physician as well.
He says that you are better.
May God bless him.
He went into a lot of trouble to cure me.
Governess Ummulhayr was always by my side.
All thanks to you.
I was waiting impatiently
for you to get well.
I was waiting so that instead of talking
about health in this gloomy room...
...we can walk in the gardens of Aleppo.
And talk about nice topics.
Poetry for example.
Do you like poetry, Halime?
I would have liked to read you
some of the poems I wrote.
As I am recovered now,
I will need to leave the palace soon.
I would like to be with my loved ones
as soon as possible.
Moreover, I have been a burden on
Leila Sultan for some time.
Governess? Where is Leila?
You are safe here.
No one knows this hideout.
Who are you?
I am the niece of the man who you saved.
Vizier Sahabettin's.
So you are El Aziz's sister.
I saw how you risked your own life
to save my uncle from...
...the foolish decree of my brother.
I am not your enemy.
It is unclear who is
a friend or foe in Aleppo.
Only my uncle can save our city from
this state. That is why I am helping you.
My uncle's friend is my friend as well.
What if you are also a foe
who looks like a friend?
Spend the night here. I will get you
out of here when the palace calms down.
I don't think I have another choice.
All the exits are blocked, sir.
We will find him sooner or later.
Look in all holes, all cracks, understood?
No one shall know
that Ertugrul has escaped.
Especially his highness,
the Ameer El Aziz.
Get out!
I still see Ertugrul being taken
when I close my eyes, Aykiz.
We have to find a way and reach them.
My Turgut...
...if he is still alive...
...only Ertugrul can save him.
Dogan?
Shall we pray, Yigit?
I am going to ask you something.
That man Turgut...
...do you think he speaks the truth
about my father's death?
He never lies.
Alright.
Now repeat everything I do.
When you are going to pray,
go to your room and close the door.
Pray to our Father secretly.
Everything that is done secretly
shall be rewarded by our Father.
Do not pray with empty words,
like the infidels.
They only try to be heard with verbiage.
Do not be one of them.
Because our Father would know what we need
even before we say and bless it to us.
Pray like this:
Our Holy Father up in the sky.
Thou name shall always be sacred.
Amen.
Welcome.
Why do you say welcome
as if we have good news to give them.
Do not be agonized.
We know about the things that happened.
So you know.
We wouldn't have liked to
greet you with our heads down...
...but we faced many troubles.
-Turgut Alp is our flesh and blood.
-I said I know what happened.
We should talk about
what we need to do now.
Aleppo has gone out of control.
Vizier Sahabettin.
He is a fugitive.
We brought him here,
as the lodge was the most secure place.
He needs to return to his post
for all the problems to be solved.
How does this concern Turgut?
As I said, Baci.
Here, everything is a tangled mess.
But Ertugrul Bey has a idea
to put everything into order.
And for this idea, he sacrificed himself.
You must be hungry.
You have to regain your strength.
Thank you.
Please do not endanger yourself
for me anymore.
I want my uncle to return to the palace
where he belongs, as soon as possible.
That is all.
The guards are still running about.
Try to manage with this until the morning.
I will find a way to get you out of here.
My problem is not getting out of
the palace, it is Nasir.
He is the one who sold out
your uncle and us.
Do you understand?
In this cold weather, drink so that you
can warm up a bit, my son.
Thank you.
With this holy duty, you deserve a place
in the heaven kingdom of our Father.
You come and drink some as well, my son.
We have to show this sinner soul
that has collaborated with the devil...
...the path of our Messiah, Jesus Christ.
-Here you are, son.
-Thank you.
Share with the others,
they should warm up a bit as well.
May God protect you.
My brave, how are you?
Drink, drink up.
I will get you out of here as soon as
possible, try to bear it, alright?
Recite the patience invocation,
I promise that I will get you out of here.
Don't. I won't leave Yigit to them.
Yigit and you will go out of
this castle safe and sound, trust me.
With God's permission, in this castle...
...I will be a martyr.
If the road takes you...
...to my tribe...
...to Kayis...
...one day...
...find Aykiz...
...tell her that...
...Turgut...
...for even one second...
...did not forget you.
That I bore all the pain...
...by thinking her love at all times.
Find Aykiz...
...and...
...tell her that I love her very much.
Alright, Alfin Bey?
You will tell all these to Aykiz yourself.
I promise you, I will get you out of here.
Drink some more.
Recite patience.
Patience.
Dear God...
May God protect you, my sons.
Ertugrul did what he always does again.
Is it a lie?
Ertugrul Bey messes everything up...
...and you end up worrying for him.
What should I have done, Hatun?
Should I have said, nothing that happens
in the tribe concerns me?
All I am saying is that you are being
the Bey of the tribe at the moment and...
...that your father should know this.
Will you abide them turning a blind eye
to whatever he does once again?
Ertugrul should pay the price of
the damage he caused for these people.
The great Kayi tribe. We don't have
a home, we don't have land...
...we don't have plentiful food...
...instead of thinking about these,
you still think of evil, Hatun.
Is it a lie?
As if these were not enough...
...you stick your nose into things
that don't concern you even when pregnant.
What more can I say to you, Hatun?
What can I say?
The letter you have written to
the Pope and Emperor Frederic...
...is not an ordinary letter anymore,
Thomas.
I was just thinking what you might give...
...to see what I have written,
my dear friend Petruccio.
You have learned our power.
Out network of spies...
...our financial sources...
...and the opportunities
we can present for a new crusade.
Especially for you, my dear friend.
What if you fail at the crusade?
Would that be important after you became
the Pope, my dear friend Thomas?
Yigit, listen to me very well.
You have to be very careful, alright?
Did you understand what I said?
You have to get that key from Marcus
at all costs.
We will overcome and
solve everything, alright?
You are a strong man.
That is obvious.
But you came out stronger than we thought.
You did not collapse
after everything you went through.
Well done.
You are like a raging bull.
Like a bull challenging his toreador.
You are not very talkative...
...but I can find a topic
that might interest you.
Aykiz.
The name you blabber while being tortured.
Is she your lover?
I don't think you will talk to me.
Shame.
Then I am going.
What do you want from me?
Your father's killer?
My father.
In this state?
I cannot go into the dungeon...
...but I know that there is a prisoner
in there called Giovanni.
There is only...
...a Muslim man called Omer in there.
I want you to ask something to that man.
Whether she knows a girl called Isadora.
If you can give me a reply...
...I would do anything I can
for you to escape from here.
How will I give you the answer?
Shahzade Yigit will help us.
Vizier is trapped. Turgut is far away.
Ertugrul Bey is away in the dungeons.
Aykutluk became a martyr.
We are left all alone here.
-Where are they?
-They are here, sir.
Ertugrul?
I am waiting outside.
Vizier...
...I know how much
you tried to help Kayis...
...thanks to Dogan and Bamsi.
They also told us
the conspiracy against you.
If you find it suitable as well...
...you should be taken somewhere
where no one can reach you.
Let us take you to Kayi tribe.
Not only the Templars, even if
the 70 kings of the Roman cities...
...unite to attack us,
they cannot take you out from there.
Suleyman Shah, your offer
made me more than happy but...
...I am afraid to bring more disasters
to your already distressed tribe.
Let disaster come to a brave,
while he is being brave...
...it would be an honor.
Rahman...
...Ilyas Fakih...
...take our vizier to the tribe
without attracting attention.
Just like written
in the letter to the Jews...
...in a way to please God...
...with fear and respect...
...let us pray.
My holy brother, if you accept as well...
...participating in a sermon by a monk
like you, who has devoted his life...
...to the Messiah, would be
a great honor to all Templar knights.
By sitting in the shelter of the Creator,
the One who has the power...
...to do anything,
he takes refuge in His shadow.
He is my shelter, my fortress!
I say for God.
He is my God, I trust Him.
Because He protects you from the traps
of the hunters and all deadly diseases!
He takes you under His wings.
You take shelter under them.
His loyalty becomes
your shield and shelter.
Amen.
Do not forget...
...some non believers who reject
the Messiah Jesus Christ...
...have secretly infiltrated amongst us.
It has been written long ago that
they shall be tried!
Amen!
Nasir...
...hasn't Esma been found yet?
Your highness, most probably the Templars
who are collaborating with Sahabetttin...
...have kidnapped her as well.
Come with me, let us interrogate Ertugrul.
When I think that my brother is in their
hands, I am about to lose my mind, father.
Ertugrul?
Halime?
Leila, my girl,
what do you think you are doing?
How can you help this man?
How can you bring him to this room?
I had to.
They are looking for him everywhere.
This is the only place
where I can hide him.
That is what I was saying.
They are looking for this man everywhere.
And you brought him to your own room.
Did you ever think what would happen to us
if your brother finds out that he is here?
If my brother finds out that he is here,
I would commit suicide.
-Do you understand me?
-God, Great God.
I am Kayi tribe's Bey Suleyman Shah.
I came to talk to you.
As you took the trouble to come all
the way here, I am listening, Turkmens.
Free my son whom
you have imprisoned unjustly.
And rehabilitate the dignity of the Kayis
whom you slandered with plague claims.
What would happen
if we don't do what you say?
We would still settle
in the lands you had promised us before.
But if my son Ertugrul is not freed...
...while a tribe is being settled there,
a city would be burnt down here.
Aleppo would be wasted!
Alright, Suleyman Shah but what would
you do if I raise my army and come to you?
Whom do you trust to talk like this?
When you put us in the edge of
the Crusader countship...
...we said yes putting our trust in Him
and we trust Him again!
Do now forget, your highness Ameer...
...us Kayis believe in God,
we trust Him and take refuge in Him.
If your army is greater than Him, come.
We shall be waiting in our tribe.
Nasir...
...if Sahabettin is with them,
our job is very difficult.
Your highness, give me permission
to put them in their places.
I want to be informed about
every step Kayis take.
Alright?
I have a feeling that
we can find my uncle if we follow them.
The rear side of our Bey's marquee
shall always be protected strongly.
The tents of the Alps shall be
distributed in the outer rings.
We can make this flat area ahead
our training ground.
The people have started to put up
their tents. Shall we wait for our Bey?
We didn't come here
to scratch the soil, Alpargu.
We will of course set up our tents.
Make sure that your Alps are ready
at all times.
An infidel might come out
from behind those mountains...
...or an attack from our so called
religion brothers may come any minute.
That is why you should be alert
at all times.
Hatun...
...you are carrying two lives...
...put it down. We can carry them.
There is still a long time, Gundogdu.
I cannot sit around empty handed
while there is so much work to do.
-Peace be upon you, Gundogdu Bey.
-And peace be upon you.
God bless you all,
you have settled so quickly.
Thanks to God, Fakih. Thanks to God.
Aleppo vizier, Sahabettin Tugrul.
Welcome, we are happy to see you.
My brother Ertugrul
always spoke highly of you.
Thank you, I am grateful.
May your new homeland be a blessing.
Thank you.
Bey...
...and about the identity of
the woman at the back...
...we should ask the devil.
Please.
Shahzade, I will save Turgut from
the dungeon in the first chance I get.
You stay in the courtyard or the corridor
in order not to attract attention, okay?
We will have only one chance.
God willing, you should not need
to use this but you should...
...have it.
Translation: Suzan Mıhladız