RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
THE STORIES AND CHARACTERS DEPICTED
HERE WERE INSPIRED BY OUR HISTORY
NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED DURING
THE FILMING OF THIS PRODUCTION
I don't want my darkened and defiled soul
to dishonor my husband's bed
and my parent's tent.
I want you to punish me twofold
in the same way I treated did Aykiz.
I must be punished equally as Kurdoglu.
I am grateful to Ibn Arabi
for not letting me kill myself
out of grief and commit a bigger sin.
He told me to tell you everything
and so I did, without keeping any secrets.
I am ready for any punishment you see fit.
Our beloved prophet, peace be upon him
said in a hadith that
all men are sinners
but the most favourables
among sinners are repentants.
Selcan wants to repent in the Nasuh way.
She regrets for those she had done before.
She is determined
to renounce her sins immediately
and not to repeat them in the future.
Our beloved prophet, peace be upon him
describes Nasuh repentance as
regretting all your sins,
fully committing yourself to God
and never going back to your sins.
Just like the milk, which never returns
to the breast once it flows.
Selcan submits to any punishment
you decide.
When all secrets were about to be covered
under a veil of lies
Selcan chose to confide her sins
instead of covering them up.
I advice you to listen to her pure heart.
Let Gundogdu decide.
I went to bed with you as my woman!
How could you do this to me?
I gave into temptation, Gundogdu.
Forgive me for God's sake.
Forgive me!
Get up, get up.
I went against my mother and
father for you.
What have you done?
You collaborated with that
traitor Kurdoglu.
How can I forgive you? How?
We wanted to have a baby!
We tried for years!
How could you do this to us?
God, oh my God! You...
How could you do this
to the baby inside of you
out of your greed and ambition?
How am I supposed to take you in my bed
as my woman!
You will leave this tent tomorrow!
I will not go to bed with you
as my woman again!
I am divorcing you!
No! No!
Please, kill me! Please, kill me
if you are going to say that word!
Kill me if you would say it, Gundogdu!
Take it and kill me!
Kill me!
Go to hell.
Peace be upon you.
And peace be upon you, Ertugrul.
Is Turgut Alp well?
He has always been well, son.
He always fought with the monsters
that wanted to take away his soul.
He was imprisoned within himself.
He was alone.
He could never ask for help or guidance.
The conflict between him and his enemy
that wanted to take his soul was so strong
he prayed to God, chanting his name
in the dungeon they put him.
He has already been one of
the victors, my son.
Now God will have mercy on him once again
as "The Healer" is one of his many names.
I would like to talk to you about Omer.
My daughter.
Are the rumours true, father?
Has Dundar really healed?
He got up as if nothing has happened.
He is like a blade quenched in water.
-Thank God.
-Father.
-Tell me, my daugther.
They say that the evil eye on the marquee
was lifted after Selcan's confession.
Not only the one on our marquee
but also the evil eye on our nomad tent
was lifted with God's will.
Turgut will get better, too.
If God permits, father.
What about her? What will they do to her?
Can they forgive her
after all the harm she has done?
Nobody knows what will happen,
my daughter.
Thank God, Ibn Arabi is here,
if it wasn't for him...
Gundogdu Bey's situation is
very difficult.
Even thinking about it is agony.
May God help them.
-Amen.
-How is Turgut?
-He is the same, my Bey.
Bey.
My lad.
My brother.
Turgut, my son.
Aykiz.
Thank God for his mercy.
I will leave tonight with your permission.
If you are still alive
know that it is thanks to Arabi.
Do whatever you want.
Be away from me and closer to God.
Sister.
Don't you hate me?
You were my mother...
...father and sister.
You were everything to me.
But I feel like you ripped
everything away from me.
I lost Ertugrul. I lost my heart.
Yet you killed a human being
inside of you.
My dear sister.
Gokce.
Don't you still trust me?
What kind of a stubbornness is that, Alps?
I do not know what you said
to convince Ertugrul Bey.
But you cannot convince me.
Even your stubbornness is nice.
I cannot get mad at you.
But...
...I don't know what do you have
against me, Dogan?
I do not trust you, Afsin Bey.
I trust Selcan Hatun
but I do not trust you.
She confessed everything one by one
out of regret.
But you are not like her.
I am afraid that some day
you will bring us together with Titus
claiming that he is
important to the state.
You showed up when our nomad group was in
deep trouble.
But heaven knows why
Halime Sultan's father was murdered
after couple of days.
You were nowhere to be found.
Dogan, Bamsi.
Afsin Bey has my and Ertugrul Bey's
full confidence.
You know that he was an
important commander in Seljuk Empire.
We do not want bad blood between you.
Besides, Suleyman Shah asked him
to come with us. Do I make myself clear?
I understood, my Bey.
Not quite, but so be it, my Bey.
Alright then.
Where is Ertugrul?
He went to visit Turgut Alp.
He will be back soon.
How is Turgut?
Thank God, he woke up.
Shall we?
Do you have time, mother?
Yes, Selcan.
Gundogdu cast me out from his tent.
I will look for another tent.
You should be thankful
that he did not divorce you.
Can Gokce stay with you?
Please do not judge my sister by my deeds.
We know what to see in a person very well.
Don't worry about it.
Come on, sisters! Hurry up!
Water is boiling!
Throw in the flowers! Hurry!
-Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you, Ertugrul Bey.
Brother, meet Omer.
Ibn Arabi said that he is a brave warrior
honored with Islam.
-Welcome.
-I am honored.
I am honored, Omer.
Cardinal Thomas wants to take
Shahzade Yigit to Constantinople.
I wanted to break him out of the dungeon
but it was not possible.
What about Isadora?
Unfortunately, The Master killed her, too.
She was a brave woman.
I will avenge her father and sister.
Cardinal will replace
The Master with Titus
with the help of the
members of the council.
Both of them do not want Kayi tribe
to get in their way before the Crusade.
They will attack your nomad tribe.
Will they cross the border
and attack the tribe?
Yes.
-May the faster one win.
-Exactly, brother.
We should hurry up and
raze that castle to ground.
Isadora drew everything we need
to get inside the castle.
We know how to get inside the tunnels
and navigate through the castle.
And most importantly,
you will be inside, Omer.
Do not worry, my Bey.
I will do whatever it takes.
Have your fill, my son, eat.
Mother, I will explode
if I take one more bite.
Son, we have fed you
with water for months.
Eat to put some muscle on you.
Eat, come on.
He will be his mother's Alp, my brave son.
Father, I would like to see the
new nomad tents with your permission.
Alright son, you may go.
You would burn what you ate too.
Thank you, father.
Dundar, take it easy and
hold onto what you ate. Alright?
Son, did you hear me?
-Alright, mother.
Bey, what are we going to do about Selcan?
Gundogdu told her to leave his tent.
What did you say to him?
I told him to give us some time
for things to settle down.
What do you say?
I don't know what to do
or what to say, Hayme.
I do not know after all these years
if we have been raising
a traitor or a dutiful child.
I would have killed her in my marquee
if it was not for Ibn Arabi.
I am not that merciful.
Maybe she was behind everything
that happened to Turgut and Dundar.
Gundogdu is devastated.
He does not know what to do.
Let us wait and hope for the best.
You should rest, sir.
I will represent you in the best way.
Yes, Titus.
What do you have to say about
the recent events?
It was a very big mistake trying to banish
Kayi tribe to where they came from.
We should have killed them all
when we had the chance.
Do you have any suggestions, Knight Titus?
Yes, I do.
We will not rest until Kayi tribe
drowns in their own blood.
They will perish to the last man,
including the babies in their cradles
so that our sacred duty will come to life.
What does Cardinal Thomas say about this?
He would like to host you in his
chambers and discuss that matter.
If you deem appropriate that is.
Dogan. Tell Wild Demir
to come to the marquee.
Yes, my Bey.
Do you have any news from Omer?
-Yes, my Bey.
-Good news?
The news are not good, my Bey.
Ertugrul Bey summons you
to the marquee, Wild Demir.
-What is the matter?
-News are not good, Wild Demir.
How is my brother, Aykiz?
My dear friend, Petruchio.
Such a great, divine man.
But the crusaders need a young
and inspiring hero
to rally us all around him instead of a
hero in deathbed like him.
And that hero is...
...Titus himself.
That castle must be razed down
on the crusaders
if we are going to ensure
our tribes future.
There is no other way.
They wanted to banish us from these
heavenly lands by using Kurdoglu.
Thank God, they failed.
From now on, their only goal
will be to kill us all.
Wild Demir.
Bey, I took a look at the drawings
Isadora brought.
What you ask is possible.
It can be done, but I do not know
how much it is going to take
to open that blocked tunnels.
If we are going to do this
those in the castle
must be completely unaware of it.
Is this possible, Ertugrul?
If we lay siege to the castle,
we can do it.
If we do it they cannot get out
or send message to
their wretched brothers.
While the castle is under siege
we can dig the tunnels secretly
and infiltrate the castle.
The number of our knights are not as much
as the Alps of Kayi tribe.
A sudden raid will surely
provide us a big advantage
but I don't want to put the war
in jeopardy.
What are you suggesting, Titus?
I will call for a legion
from Principality of Antioch.
A legion of 800 archers
will ease our cavaliers'
and footmens' work.
I will also muster
300 knights from Cyprus.
Where will you find the ships from, Titus?
They are also ready, sir.
I know that 15 galiots
Emperor Frederick sent
are located at the Kyrenian Harbor.
The navarch is going to do
what is necessary.
The ships will be in Alexandretta
in a week.
There are cliffs at the backside
of the castle, Bey.
Access is possible only through the front.
Accesses to the tunnels are
from the left and right sides.
If we surround the castle...
...from here and here, we have a chance
to get in from the tunnels.
Can we get inside of this castle,
Wild Demir?
Bey, I need to see the tunnels
with my own eyes.
You and Afsin go and take a look
at the castle.
Yes, my Bey.
Ertugrul...
...we must prepare our Alps for battle.
They are probably preparing
to attack us, too.
Reinforce the defences of the tribe also.
You want us to be ready for
attack and defence, Bey.
Gundogdu, you will try to find
coin for the battle.
We need gold for weapons and subsistence.
We can get the necessary weapons
with the gold we found in the tents
of Kurdoglu and his Beys, father.
Our goal will be to kill them all
using their own gold.
May God grant us victory.
The war has begun.
We will move after Turgut Alp's wedding.
I told you that Ertugrul
would cause trouble.
We had a big opportunity.
We should have killed him and his Alps
when we had the chance in the forest.
We could have gotten rid of them all.
But what have you done?
You missed the opportunity
for the chest of Ibn Arabi.
If Ertugrul had died
you would be alive now.
You would be in your office.
It is too late now.
That chest, we do not even know
what's inside of it
has already defeated us.
Only because of your stupidity.
Go to hell, Petruchio Manzini.
I met with Ibn Arabi, sir.
He said that he would go to Damascus
in a couple of days.
He wants me to go with him.
-Will the chest be with him?
-Yes, sir.
That is good.
I will go to Constantinople
with the little Shahzade.
I will meet you there.
Halime Sultan buried the chest here.
I did not touch it. I wanted you to know.
Thank you, son.
I knew that it was in safe hands.
That chest, I do not know
what is inside of it
and I do not wonder about it.
But both Black Priest Thomas
and The Templars are after it.
They quarrel among each other
because of it.
Our chest saved you
and your Alps' life, son.
Titus wanted to kill me
when they caught us
but The Master did not let him do it.
We are alive thanks to your chest.
If you wonder what is inside of it
I would say it is something
that has been entrusted to me.
As I told you, leave it here
until I leave the tribe.
As you wish.
I heared that you will lay siege
to the castle.
May God grant you victory.
May God give you strenght, son.
Amen.
I want to know something.
Didn't you have a twinge of conscience
when you did all those evil things?
I would not be able to if I did.
My father kept coming to me.
I wanted to avenge him.
Now everyone will ostracize me
as if I have the plague, because of you.
Gokce!
You defiled our honor
just like our father did.
You are right.
But from now on my tongue will be mute
and my eyes will be blind.
From now on, nobody will be harmed
because of me.
I do not want to see you
for a while, sister.
I don't want to ponder about
your evil deeds and hate you even more.
Translation:Losa Translation Services