-Haydır Allah!
-Haktır Allah!
-Ever-Living God!
-Righteous God!
Bekle bakalım.
Wait a bit!
Bir de buna bak istersen ha?
Take a look at this one.
gazap olsun inşallah.
wrath to the tyrants, if God permits.
Oy seni veren Allah'a kurban olayım ben.
I’m ready to sacrifice myself for God, who gave you to us.
atam Oğuz adına şerefle taşıyacağım.
in the name of my forefather Oguz, I’ll gird it with honor.
Uzat bakalım elini.
Reach me your hands.
Hayrola?
What is the matter?
Hazırlanıyorlar.
They are getting ready.
O zaten ser verip sır vermez.
No, he never breathes a single word about.
Ne işe yarar?
What is it used for?
Öyle gamlı baykuş gibi tüner,
durur otağında.
He is sitting in his tent
just like a groomed owl.
Ertuğrul!
Ertugrul!
Tamam, fazla uzaklaşma. Tez git, tez dön.
Alright. But don’t go too far. Go quickly, come back quickly.
Hadi alpler.
Come on, Alps.
Seninki gidiyor.
Your man is going.
Ya Allah!
-Ha ha!
şerefinizdir!
is your pride!
Ya! Ya!
O şeref bize ait.
That honor belongs to us.
Müsaadenizle.
With your permission.
Güzel.
Good.
Sarayımıza evlat.
To our palace, son.
Sonsuza kadar.
Until eternity.
Tamam.
-Alright!
Subaşı.
Exciseman!
Güzel.
Good.
Nerede kaldı bu Tapınakçılar?
Where are those Templars?
Etrafı kolaçan edin.
Check the surroundings.
Yiğit.
Yigit.
Bisol!
Bisol...
Hıh.
Bunlara da verin.
These too.
Ya hadi!
Oh God!
Siz ikiniz, gidin başka yerde oturun.
You two, go and sit somewhere else.
Sana su getirdim, al.
I brought you water. Take it.
Hadi.
Come on.
Ah! Ah!
Anahtar, anahtarı al.
Key! Take the key.
Çabuk.
Quickly.
Kısmete bak.
We are in luck.
-Kaçma!
-Koşun! Koşun!
-Escape!
-Run! Run!
-Çabuk kardeşini al ve gidin buradan.
-Olmaz! Olmaz!
-Quick, take your brother and get out of here.
-No way! No way!
-Kardeşini al, kaçın diyorum size!
-Baba.
-Take your brother and get the hell out of here!
-Father.
Hadi baba kalk! Hadi!
Come on, father! Get up! Come on!
Kaçmak ha? Şimdi görürsün!
So you tried to run away! You will pay for this.
Baba!
Father!
Medet ya Rabb, medet!
Please help us, God.
Burada.
Here.
Ya Allah!
Great God!
Aa aa!
Ya aa!
Baba dayan tamam.
Ah! Ah!
Aa aa!
Dayan. Dayan baba.
Stay with us. Be strong, father.
-Turgut, meşe yaprağı.
-Tamam beyim.
-Turgut Alp quick, bring some oak leaves.
-Yes sir.
Peki,
Well...
Anadolu,
Anatolia.
hedefimize ulaşacağız.
...we will be victorious.
Kudüs bizim olacak.
Jerusalem will be ours.
Ah! Ah!
Tamam. Bitiyor baba.
OK. It ends, father.
Tamam.
OK
Tez yola düşelim.
We have to be on our way as soon as possible.
Atları getirin.
bring the horses.
Hadi.
Come on.
Uzak mı obanız?
Is your tribe far?
Hoş geldiniz.
Welcome.
Eyvallah.
Thank you.
Beyimize Gazanfer Ağa'nın
geldiğini haber verin.
Tell our Bey that
Gazanfar Aga is here.
80 akçe.
80 coins.
Birine benzettiniz herhâlde.
You probably took me for someone else.
sefalar getirdin. Gel buyur.
You bring joy to us. Come and sit.
Zahmet etmişsin.
You did not have to bother.
Hayırdır?
What happened?
Eyvallah.
Thank you.
Desene zorlu günler bekler bizi.
So, we have difficult days ahead.
Ya şu sarışın?
What about that blond one?
Gel buraya.
Come here.
Benden korkmana gerek yok.
You don’t need to be afraid of me.
Artık efendinim.
I am your master now.
Ama buna değer.
But she is worth it.
Ne oldu?
What happened?
Alın yaralıyı.
take him in.
Hepimiz iyiyiz Allah'a şükür.
We all are, thank God.
Anlatırım.
I will tell you later.
Emrin olur beyim.
As you wish, my Bey.
Yakında çıkar ortaya.
We will find out soon.
Anlarız.
We will see.
Baban emin ellerde.
Thank you very much. You are God sent.
Söylemediler.
Yes.
Akdeniz'de esir düştük.
But we don’t have anything left now.
Evet.
You are in Kayi tribe.
bu oba neresi?
-Then, kill this man.
-No!
Size üç can borcumuz var.
Shut your mouth.
Hı hı.
Sir, please spare me for my children.
Beceriksiz herif!
Get ready, we are going!