-Haydır Allah!
-Haktır Allah!
God is alive. God is truth.
Bekle bakalım.
Wait a bit.
Bir de buna bak istersen ha?
Take a look at this one.
gazap olsun inşallah.
wrath to the tyrants, if God permits.
Oy seni veren Allah'a kurban olayım ben.
I’m ready to sacrifice myself for God, who gave you to us.
atam Oğuz adına şerefle taşıyacağım.
I will carry it with honor on behalf of my ancestor Oğuz.
Uzat bakalım elini.
Extend your hand.
Hayrola?
What is the matter?
Hazırlanıyorlar.
They're getting ready.
O zaten ser verip sır vermez.
He doesn't give a secret anyway.
Ne işe yarar?
What does it do?
Öyle gamlı baykuş gibi tüner,
durur otağında.
He is sitting in his tent just like a groomed owl.
Ertuğrul!
Ertugrul.
Tamam, fazla uzaklaşma. Tez git, tez dön.
Okay, don't go too far. Go fast, go back fast.
Hadi alpler.
Come on, alps.
Seninki gidiyor.
Yours is leaving.
Ya Allah!
Ya God.
-Ha ha!
Ha ha. Ha ha.
şerefinizdir!
is your honor.
Ya! Ya!
Ya Ya.
O şeref bize ait.
That honor belongs to us.
Müsaadenizle.
With your permission.
Güzel.
Beautiful.
Sarayımıza evlat.
To our palace, son.
Sonsuza kadar.
Forever.
Tamam.
OK.
Subaşı.
Exciseman.
Güzel.
Beautiful.
Nerede kaldı bu Tapınakçılar?
Where are these Templars?
Etrafı kolaçan edin.
Check around.
Yiğit.
Valiant.
Bisol!
Bisol.
Hıh.
Huh.
Bunlara da verin.
Give them too.
Ya hadi!
Come on.
Siz ikiniz, gidin başka yerde oturun.
You two, go sit elsewhere.
Sana su getirdim, al.
I brought you water, take it.
Hadi.
Let's.
Ah! Ah!
Ah Ah.
Anahtar, anahtarı al.
Key, get the key.
Çabuk.
Quickly.
Kısmete bak.
Look at the fortune.
-Kaçma!
-Koşun! Koşun!
Escape. Run Run.
-Çabuk kardeşini al ve gidin buradan.
-Olmaz! Olmaz!
Quick take your brother and get out of here. No way not.
-Kardeşini al, kaçın diyorum size!
-Baba.
Take your brother and run away. Father.
Hadi baba kalk! Hadi!
Come on dad, get up. Come on.
Kaçmak ha? Şimdi görürsün!
Run away, huh? You will see it now.
Baba!
Father.
Medet ya Rabb, medet!
Medet ya Rabb, medet.
Burada.
Here.
Ya Allah!
Ya God.
Aa aa!
Aa aa.
Ya aa!
Ya aa.
Aa aa!
Aa aa.
Baba dayan tamam.
Dad hold on, okay.
Ah! Ah!
Ah Ah.
Aa aa!
Aa aa.
Ah! Ah!
Ah Ah.
Dayan. Dayan baba.
Hang on, Daddy.
-Turgut, meşe yaprağı.
-Tamam beyim.
Turgut, oak leaf. OK sir.
Peki,
Well,.
Anadolu,
Anatolia,.
hedefimize ulaşacağız.
we will achieve our goal.
Kudüs bizim olacak.
Jerusalem will be ours.
Ah! Ah!
Ah Ah.
Tamam. Bitiyor baba.
OK It's over, dad.
Tamam.
OK.
Tez yola düşelim.
Let's get on the road.
Atları getirin.
Bring the horses.
Hadi.
Let's.
Uzak mı obanız?
Are you far away?
Hoş geldiniz.
Welcome.
Eyvallah.
Thank you.
Beyimize Gazanfer Ağa'nın
geldiğini haber verin.
Our Bey is Gazanfer Ağa. let me know you are coming.
80 akçe.
80 coins.
Birine benzettiniz herhâlde.
You probably looked like someone.
sefalar getirdin. Gel buyur.
You brought joy. Come on.
Zahmet etmişsin.
You have bothered.
Hayırdır?
What's up?.
Eyvallah.
Thank you.
Desene zorlu günler bekler bizi.
Hard days await us for the pattern.
Ya şu sarışın?
What about that blonde?
Gel buraya.
Come here.
Benden korkmana gerek yok.
No need to fear me.
Artık efendinim.
I'm your master now.
Ama buna değer.
But it's worth it.
Ne oldu?
What happened?.
Alın yaralıyı.
Forehead the injured.
Hepimiz iyiyiz Allah'a şükür.
We are all fine, thank God.
Anlatırım.
I will explain.
Emrin olur beyim.
You have your order, sir.
Yakında çıkar ortaya.
It will be revealed soon.
Anlarız.
We understand.
Baban emin ellerde.
Your father is in good hands.
Söylemediler.
They didn't say.
Akdeniz'de esir düştük.
We were captured in the Mediterranean.
Evet.
Yeah.
bu oba neresi?
where is this oba?
Size üç can borcumuz var.
We owe you three lives.
Hı hı.
Uh huh.
Beceriksiz herif!
Incompetent dude.
Yap dedim!
I said do it.
-Seni azat ediyorum.
-Ah!
I set you free. Ah.