Sir, come on.
Beyim. Hazır. Hadi buyur.
Dündar.
Come on, son, come to the table.
Hadi oğlum, sen de gel sofraya.
Let me finish this, I'm coming, Ana.
Şu işimi bitireyim, geliyorum ana.
Always be like that, lion.
Her daim böyle ol aslan parçası.
Don't go to work before you finish your duty.
Vazifeni bitirmeden başka işlere koyulma.
Selcen. Here, mother.
-Selcan.
-Buyur ana.
Selcen. Here, mother.
Bring the molasses, girl. I'm bringing you home.
-Pekmezi getir kızım.
-Getiriyorum ana.
Bring the molasses, girl. I'm bringing you home.
Where is Gündoğdu ?.
Nerede kaldı Gündoğdu?
He went to look at the shepherds, now he comes.
Çobanlara bakmaya gitmişti, gelir şimdi.
Put another plate on the table.
Sofraya bir tabak daha koyun.
For Sungur Tekin.
Sungur Tekin için.
If he comes back one day, he's at the table. Let the child know that there is a place.
Bir gün geri gelirse sofrada
yeri olduğunu bilsin çocuk.
If he comes back one day, he's at the table. Let the child know that there is a place.
Here you go.
Hadi bakalım.
Where is Gündoğdu ?.
Nerede kaldı Gündoğdu?
Come soon, master.
Gelir birazdan ana.
Haha.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
So, son, you're back with a big game.
Ee evlat, yine büyük bir avla dönmüşsün.
It's kind of like that, mister.
Biraz öyle oldu beyim.
Mashallah, brother.
Maşallahın var kardeşim.
In the middle of the plain. You're like a lightning tree.
Ovanın ortasında
yıldırım çeken ağaç gibisin.
In the middle of the plain. You're like a lightning tree.
You're taking all kinds of trouble.
Her türlü belayı üzerine çekiyorsun.
The oppressed were attacked.
Mazlumlar saldırıya uğramışlardı.
We did our best.
Biz de elimizden geleni yaptık.
Who? What are they like?
Kimmiş? Neyin nesiymiş bunlar?
Crusaders have been captured.
Haçlılara esir düşmüşler.
He was a merchant.
Adam tüccarmış.
It must be from the Antioch Crusaders, sir.
Antakya Haçlı Kontluğundan olmalı beyim.
Knights in Seljuk soil.
Şövalyeler, Selçuklu toprağında
hands on your arms. they do not carry prisoners.
böyle ellerini kollarını
sallaya sallaya esir taşımazlar.
hands on your arms. they do not carry prisoners.
So?.
Yani?
I mean, I wouldn't say.
Yani demem o ki
The Seljuks surely. he has knowledge of these prisoners.
Selçuklu'nun mutlaka
bu esirlerden haberi vardır.
The Seljuks surely. he has knowledge of these prisoners.
There were no Seljuk soldiers in them.
İçlerinde Selçuklu askeri yoktu.
How you got into trouble. Ertugrul will be released in late ayyuka.
Nasıl bir belaya bulaştığın er ya
da geç ayyuka çıkacak Ertuğrul.
How you got into trouble. Ertugrul will be released in late ayyuka.
What should I do?
Ne yapsaydım abi?
Should I just leave them?
Onları öylece bıraksa mıydım?
You both shut up.
İkiniz de susun.
To them. entertain
Onları Kayılara
yaraşır bir şekilde ağırlayın.
To them. entertain
Let's see what the day shows.
Bakalım gün neyi gösterecek.
It's okay, Dad.
Geçti baba.
You'il be fine.
Geçti. İyi olacaksın.
Excuse me?
Müsaade var mı?
Here you go, sir.
Buyur beyim.
How's he doing ?.
Durumu nasıl?
After that, the admiration is divine.
Bundan sonrası takdiri ilahi.
With permission.
Müsaadenle.
Come, Aykız.
Gel Aykız.
Aykız, Turgut's youngster.
Aykız, Turgut’un yavuklusu.
I just wanted to ask you if you need anything.
Bir ihtiyacınız var mı diye sorayım dedim.
Thanks.
Sağ olun.
We've already had a lot on you.
Zaten çok yük olduk size.
Would that ever happen?
Olur mu hiç öyle şey?
Dogan Beyrek and Dogan. They are preparing their tents for you.
Bamsı Beyrek’le Doğan
çadırlarını sizin için hazırlıyorlar.
Dogan Beyrek and Dogan. They are preparing their tents for you.
You stay there for the night.
Gece orada kalırsınız.
I'd better stay with my dad.
Ben babamın yanında kalsam daha iyi.
Get some rest tonight. You look so miserable.
Bu gece biraz dinlenin.
Çok perişan görünüyorsunuz.
Get some rest tonight. You look so miserable.
When your father wakes up. you will need more.
Baban uyandığında
size daha çok ihtiyacı olacak.
When your father wakes up. you will need more.
Don't worry, I'il stay with your dad.
Merak etme, babanın yanında ben kalırım.
Oh, mister ah.
Ah beyim ah!
How did you raise it all this time? This boils on your back ?.
Bunca zaman nasıl büyüttün
bu çıbanı sırtında?
How did you raise it all this time? This boils on your back ?.
What boils we have grown. Hayme on our backs.
Biz ne çıbanlar büyüttük
sırtımızda Hayme.
What boils we have grown. Hayme on our backs.
Are we gonna be afraid of betraying Shunc?
Şuncağızın ihanetinden mi korkacağız?
But if you had it in the first place. Get out of this mess, now it's already.
Ama en başında ezseydin
başını bu belanın, şimdi çoktan...
But if you had it in the first place. Get out of this mess, now it's already.
The jackals used to be in the mountains. Now they landed in our oba.
Çakallar eskiden dağlardaydı.
Şimdi obamıza kadar indiler.
The jackals used to be in the mountains. Now they landed in our oba.
A slight mistake. they wait to operate.
En ufak bir hatamda üzerime
çullanmak için beklerler.
A slight mistake. they wait to operate.
Know my weakness. I keep them so they don't see.
Zayıflığımı bilip
görmesinler diye saklarım.
Know my weakness. I keep them so they don't see.
Rather than talk to their mouths.
Ağızlarına laf vermektense
to be silent and roast with pain is the greatest child.
susup acımla kavrulmak en büyük evladır.
At least you should have told Akcakoca.
Bari Akçakoca’ya söyleseydin.
I did, lady, I did.
Söyledim hanım, söyledim.
He's preparing an ointment for me.
Bana şifa olacak bir merhem hazırlıyor.
We'il drive it tonight.
Akşama süreriz hayırlısıyla.
Ohh.
What happened? You think about our guests?
Ne oldu? Misafirlerimizi mi düşünürsün?
Which is the tip of this wick. Hayme has burned the oil lamp ?.
Bu fitilin ucu hangi isli
kandili yakmıştır Hayme?
Which is the tip of this wick. Hayme has burned the oil lamp ?.
Are you dressed? Yeah.
- Giyindin mi?
- Evet.
Are you dressed? Yeah.
How was it?. Very good, Aykız.
- Nasıl oldu?
- Çok güzel, Aykız.
How was it?. Very good, Aykız.
Let me see.
Dur bakayım.
It's like a palace. You became like a melike.
Aman Allah'ım! Sanki saraylı
bir melike gibi oldun Halime.
It's like a palace. You became like a melike.
You look beautiful.
Çok güzel oldun.
What happened?.
Ne oldu?
Did I say something wrong?.
Yanlış bir şey mi söyledim?
No.
Yok.
That sounds weird.
Tuhaf geldi sadece öyle demen.
Wait, let's put this on.
Dur, şu başlığı da takalım.
Turgut Alp bought it for me.
Turgut Alp almıştı bunu bana.
Gosh. Why did you give it to me now?
Hay Allah!
Niye verdin ki şimdi bunu bana?
Gosh. Why did you give it to me now?
Because I knew it would look good on you.
Çünkü sana çok yakışacağını biliyordum.
Let me see.
It looks good.
Yakıştı da.
When is your wedding ?.
Ne zaman düğününüz?
When we move from this plateau, I hope.
Bu yayladan göçtüğümüzde, inşallah.
Aykız, isn't that hard. to be such an alpine wife ?.
Aykız, zor değil mi
böyle bir Alp'in karısı olmak?
Aykız, isn't that hard. to be such an alpine wife ?.
If his heart beats for me at any moment. What is the importance of difficulty ?.
Yüreği her an benim için atıyorsa
zorluğun ne önemi var?
If his heart beats for me at any moment. What is the importance of difficulty ?.
Let him return to his room unharmed. I wouldn't want anything else.
Sağ salim odasına dönsün,
başka bir şey istemem.
Let him return to his room unharmed. I wouldn't want anything else.
As long as there's no death.
Yeter ki ölüm olmasın.
Come on, let's braid your hair, huh?
Gel bu saçlarını da örelim istersen, ha?
Let's weave.
Örelim.
Do you have a pup?
Yavuklun var mı?
Mother after Yigit after my mother died.
Annem öldükten sonra Yiğit’e annelik
companionship to my father. nothing else happened in my life.
babama yoldaşlık etmekten
başka bir şey olmadı hayatımda.
companionship to my father. nothing else happened in my life.
Besides, which male is like me.
Hem zaten hangi erkek benim gibi...
Oh, look at the madman.
Aa! Delinin zoruna bak!
Men get into each other for you.
Erkekler senin için birbirlerine girerler.
They bring the world to gold.
Dünyanın altını üstüne getirirler.
When was the last time in a mirror. You looked at yourself?
En son ne zaman bir aynada
kendine baktın sen?
When was the last time in a mirror. You looked at yourself?
Stop.
Dur.
Isn't that the brother of Titus fuss?
Titus gavurunun kardeşi değil mi bu?
Yes, sir, Bisol.
Evet efendim, Bisol.
Send these carcasses to the Templars.
Tapınakçılara gönderin bu leşleri.
Now we'il deal with Titus.
Şimdi bir de Titus’la uğraşacağız.
You, you, come here.
Sen, sen, gelin buraya.
Get it and upload it to the horse.
Alın bunu ata yükleyin.
Which tribal is this stamp ?.
Hangi aşiretin bu damga?
Apricots, sir.
Kayılar, efendim.
Apricots.
Kayılar demek.
If they're in the hands of Suleiman Shah, it's hard.
Süleyman Şah’ın elindeyseler işimiz zor.
That shepherd's head. Seljuk?
O çoban başı,
Selçuklu’ya kafa mı tutacak?
That shepherd's head. Seljuk?
Get your daylighted Ertuğrul.
Günün aydın olsun Ertuğrul.
You too.
Sizin de.
I brought you some.
Aş getirdim sana.
You bothered me, Gokce.
Zahmet etmişsin Gökçe bacım.
How's our wounded?
Yaralımız nasıl?
Well I hope it will rise in a few days.
İyi. Birkaç güne ayaklanır inşallah.
God willing.
İnşallah.
May God heal. We shouldn't have any trouble.
Allah şifa versin de
başımıza bela olmasın yeter.
May God heal. We shouldn't have any trouble.
I'il be right back, too. from there we pass to the rugs household.
Birazdan ben de gelirim,
oradan kilim haneye geçeriz.
I'il be right back, too. from there we pass to the rugs household.
Okay, Aykiz.
Tamam Aykız.
Is my father OK? Good very good.
-Babam iyi mi Ertuğrul Bey?
-İyi. Çok iyi.
Is my father OK? Good very good.
When you go in, you'il see. His fever's down.
İçeriye girince sen de görürsün.
Ateşi düştü.
When you go in, you'il see. His fever's down.
I hope we carry it to your tent in the evening.
Akşam çadırınıza taşırız inşallah.
See her, girl. Already in the palm of his hand Ertugrul.
Gördün mü kızı,
şimdiden avucunun içine almış Ertuğrul’u.
See her, girl. Already in the palm of his hand Ertugrul.
From now on, you can only dream.
Bundan sonra anca rüyanda görürsün.
Did you sleep well?
Rahat uyudunuz mu?
There are years that no. I didn't sleep as well.
Yıllar var ki hiç bu
kadar güzel uyumamıştım.
There are years that no. I didn't sleep as well.
You called me Templars in the woods.
Ormanda bana Tapınakçılar demiştin.
Yeah?.
Evet?
Who are they?.
Kim onlar?
A sect that fought for Jerusalem.
Kudüs için savaşan bir tarikat.
They are very powerful and cruel.
Çok güçlü ve acımasızlardır.
Avenging Jerusalem. they don't know anything else.
Kudüs’ün intikamını almaktan
başka bir şey bilmezler.
Avenging Jerusalem. they don't know anything else.
If they're so strong, what do they want from you?
Bu kadar güçlülerse sizden ne istiyorlar?
Is this the Seljuk lands? Yeah.
-Burası Selçuklu toprakları mı?
-Evet.
Is this the Seljuk lands? Yeah.
Is there a problem with the Seljuk?
Selçuklu’yla bir mesele mi var Halime?
No dear.
Yok canım.
What would Big Seljuk do with us?
Koca Selçuklu’nun bizimle ne işi olur ki?
Is Kesgin.
Keşgir.
Ahh.
Ahh!
What's going on, girl?
Kızım ne oluyor?
Nothing, Dad, I didn't see it.
Yok bir şey baba, görmedim.
Oh, but you still.
Haa, ama sen yine de
under the tongue. If you want to take the beans, huh?
dilinin altındaki
baklayı çıkar istersen ha?
under the tongue. If you want to take the beans, huh?
It doesn't happen when you want something, Dad.
Bir şeyi çok isteyince olmuyormuş baba.
I found out.
Bunu öğrendim.
Who did you learn from?.
Kimden öğrendin?
We were supposed to marry Turgut Alp when he emigrated.
Göç edince Turgut Alp’le evlenecektik,
rope.
iple çektik göç etmeyi.
In winter, the hand in the ear.
Kışın eli kulağında.
We still don't know where to migrate.
Hâlâ nereye göç edeceğimizi bilmiyoruz.
Roger, your life. he threw up as your deceased mother.
Anlaşıldı. Senin de canın
rahmetli anan kadar tezmiş.
Roger, your life. he threw up as your deceased mother.
Bre, take a look. Is the winter on the high mountain high?
Bre bir bak bakalım,
şu ulu dağın yaylasında kış geçer mi?
Bre, take a look. Is the winter on the high mountain high?
Why is he gathering toy he ?.
Niye toplanıyor toy he?
All gentlemen flock. Why is Suleiman coming to our Shah's seat?
Bütün beyler akın akın
Süleyman Şah’ımızın otağına niye geliyor?
All gentlemen flock. Why is Suleiman coming to our Shah's seat?
We'il sit down, talk. I hope we will solve this issue.
Oturacağız, konuşacağız,
bu meseleyi çözeceğiz inşallah.
We'il sit down, talk. I hope we will solve this issue.
Come on, don't worry. Give me the vest, let's not be late.
Hadi, sen tasalanma.
Ver yeleği, geç kalmayalım hadi.
Come on, don't worry. Give me the vest, let's not be late.
Oh, my moon, my sweet Aykiz.
Hay benim aydan tatlı Aykız’ım.
Kurdoğlu will be gathered soon.
Birazdan toy toplanacak Kurdoğlu.
Nobody knows what to do.
Kimse ne yapacağını bilmiyor.
We'il do it.
Evelallah hallederiz.
Kurdoğlu, the mountain fell silent.
Kurdoğlu, dağ sustu
The rivers cannot grow,. it didn't rain.
ırmaklar çağlamaz,
yağmurlar yağmaz oldu.
The rivers cannot grow,. it didn't rain.
We're stuck in this plain.
Kısıldık kaldık bu ovada.
If it goes like this, our animals. Babies will die too.
Böyle giderse hayvanlarımız daha
çok telef olacak. Bebeler ölecek.
If it goes like this, our animals. Babies will die too.
So, what's on your mind?
Peki, ne geçiyor aklınızdan?
Horse, according to the owner of the culinary Kurdoğlu.
At, sahibine göre kişner Kurdoğlu.
Put our weight on you now.
Sözümüz sanadır. Ağırlığını koy artık.
Suleyman Shah is irrelevant. Not even a horse.
Süleyman Şah mecalsizdir.
Bir ata bile sahip çıkamaz.
Suleyman Shah is irrelevant. Not even a horse.
You see, Kurdoğlu ;.
Anlayacağın Kurdoğlu;
horse building, sword.
at binenin, kılıç kuşananın.
Mother.
Ana.
I came to Akçakoca to buy medicinal herbs.
Akçakoca’ya şifalı ot almaya gelmiştim.
Output.
Çıktı.
I'il get you whatever you want, mama.
Ne istiyorsan alıp getireyim sana ana.
No, I'il buy it later.
Yok. Daha sonra alırım.
Our guest.
Misafirimiz.
Numan Bey's daughter Halime.
Numan Bey’in kızı Halime.
Welcome to our obama, girl.
Obamıza hoş geldiniz kızım.
How is your dad? Is it good?. Good.
-Baban nasıl? İyi mi?
-İyi.
How is your dad? Is it good?. Good.
I'm so glad God bless you.
Çok sevindim. Allah şifasını versin.
Our quarry is always open to you.
Ocağımız size her zaman açık.
If you have a problem, don't hesitate, come tell me. Okay?.
Bir derdin olursa hiç çekinme, gel söyle.
Tamam mı?
If you have a problem, don't hesitate, come tell me. Okay?.
May Allah be pleased with you, Mrs. Hayme.
Allah sizden razı olsun Hayme Hanım.
No place, no sky.
Ne yerde, ne gökte
in the hearts of a believer.
halis bir müminin gönlünde olan,
There is one,.
biri var,
There is one who is most Gracious. and in the name of Allah, the Womb.
varı bir eden Rahman
ve Rahim olan Allah’ın adıyla.
There is one who is most Gracious. and in the name of Allah, the Womb.
Blue sky, swampy ground.
Mavi gök, yağız yer arasında
our lineage, height, obam, hearth,.
soyumuz, boyumuz, obamız, ocağımız,
Our sons, our daughters.
oğullarımız, kızlarımız
get one, get free, get alive.
bir olsun, hür olsun, diri olsun.
Our distributor of justice. happy birthday in the presence of.
Adalet dağıtan beyimizin
huzurunda toyumuz kutlu olsun.
Our distributor of justice. happy birthday in the presence of.
Amine.
Amin!
When you say, kill.
Ol deyince olduran,
Filling our hearts with faith,. ninetynine names of Allah Almighty.
gönüllerimizi imanla dolduran,
yüce Allah’ın doksan dokuz adıyla
Filling our hearts with faith,. ninetynine names of Allah Almighty.
or Bismillah.
Bismillah.
Thanks.
Sağ ol.
My Bey ,.
Beylerim,
my valiants, the height of my height;
yiğitlerim, boyumun uluları;
Welcome, you have brought pleasure.
hoş gelmişsiniz, sefalar getirmişsiniz.
Thank you.
Eyvallah.
Thank goodness before we set off the goods. before a trader came to our oba.
Çok şükür ki malları yola çıkarmadan
önce obamıza bir tüccar geldi.
Thank goodness before we set off the goods. before a trader came to our oba.
I say the goods. Let's sell to the merchant.
Derim ki malları
değerince tüccara satalım.
I say the goods. Let's sell to the merchant.
Thus, travel costs. We will be saved.
Böylelikle yol masraflarından
da kurtulmuş oluruz.
Thus, travel costs. We will be saved.
Well, all we care about is goods, mister.
Tek derdimiz mal olsa iyi beyim.
Our animals in the surrounding plains. we're out of pasture.
Civar ovalarda hayvanlarımızı
otlatacağımız mera kalmadı.
Our animals in the surrounding plains. we're out of pasture.
They can't drink water or milk. They're starving.
Su içemez, süt veremez oldular.
Açlıktan telef oldular.
They can't drink water or milk. They're starving.
Thesis is a case. We need to find a solution.
Tez vakitte bir hâl
çaresi bulmamız gerek.
Thesis is a case. We need to find a solution.
I see the oba.
Obanın hâlini ben de görürüm.
We sent news to all the gentlemen around. we wanted a dorm.
Tüm civar beylere haber saldık,
yurt istedik.
We sent news to all the gentlemen around. we wanted a dorm.
But drought is everywhere.
Lakin kuraklık her yerde.
And the Mongolian. fleeing
Bir de Moğol
eşkıyasından kaçan
And the Mongolian. fleeing
Turkmen tribes are scattered all around.
Türkmen boyları her bir tarafa dağılmış.
What shall we do? For grassland. Shall we draw swords to our friends?
Ne yapalım? Otlak için
gardaşlarımıza kılıç mı çekelim?
What shall we do? For grassland. Shall we draw swords to our friends?
God's mercy, sir?
Allah’ın rahmet hazinesi mi kesik beyim?
We've been waiting here for months.
Aylardır burada beklemekteyiz.
We can't find a cure. How long has Kayi been so desperate?
Bir çare bulamamaktayız.
Ne zamandır Kayı, böyle çaresiz kalmıştır?
We can't find a cure. How long has Kayi been so desperate?
No dormitories for us?
Bize gidecek yurt mu yok?
If we don't find a cure. How do we keep the object?
Bir hâl çare bulmazsak eğer,
obayı nasıl tutarız ayakta?
If we don't find a cure. How do we keep the object?
And how long has El Rezzak? God, who becomes forgotten ?.
Ya ne zamandır El Rezzak
olan Allah, unutulur olur?
And how long has El Rezzak? God, who becomes forgotten ?.
. Our yeast was patiently kneaded.
Bizim mayamız sabırla yoğrulmuştur.
What descends from the sky and falls to us.
Gökten ne iner, bize de o düşer.
We are patriotic about what patience is. We learned by visiting Deli Iron.
Biz sabrın ne olduğunu yurtsuz
gezerek öğrendik Deli Demir.
We are patriotic about what patience is. We learned by visiting Deli Iron.
Let our informal generation not be homeless.
Gayrı neslimiz yurtsuz kalmasın.
Don't tell us what your patience is.
Sabrın ne olduğunu anlatma bize.
When did I leave you naked. I left hungry.
Ben ne vakit sizi çıplak bıraktım,
aç bıraktım ki
When did I leave you naked. I left hungry.
You are so anxious for sustenance ?.
rızık için bu kadar telaşlanırsınız?
I didn't mean him.
Haşa beyim. Onu kast etmemiştim.
Sir, you us. You did not leave hungry or naked.
Beyim, sen bizi
ne aç bıraktın ne de çıplak.
Sir, you us. You did not leave hungry or naked.
But what a waste we have left you.
Lakin biz de seni ne ersiz bıraktık
nor pussate.
ne de pusatsız.
Sir, we say.
Beyim, biz deriz ki
Let's find a new homeland and emigrate.
yeni bir yurt bulup göç edelim.
Where?. Wherever the white sheep find their lives.
-Nereye?
-Ak koyunların can bulacağı her yere.
Where?. Wherever the white sheep find their lives.
Let's emigrate to our lands. They say the Mongol bandit is broken.
Ata topraklarımıza göç edelim.
Moğol eşkıyasının da gücü kırılmış derler.
Let's emigrate to our lands. They say the Mongol bandit is broken.
Whoever says it's a lie.
Kim derse yalan der.
Mongolian bandit hungry wolf. monstrous
Moğol eşkıyası aç kurt
gibi canavarlaşmış.
Mongolian bandit hungry wolf. monstrous
We never thought of a cure, sir?
Hiç mi bir çare düşünmedik beyim?
Halep.
I have heard that the Emir of Aleppo, El Aziz.
Duydum ki Halep Emiri El Aziz
Against the crusaders. gathering force.
Haçlı ordularına karşı
kuvvet toplamaktaymış.
Against the crusaders. gathering force.
What is your nephew?
Nedir yeğen gönlündeki?
I say to El Aziz.
Ben derim ki El Aziz’e
Let's send an ambassador.
bir elçi gönderelim.
Say, &quot;You give us oba, and we will give you a compass.&quot;
Desin ki "Sen bize oba ver,
biz de sana pusatlı er verelim."
Say, &quot;You give us oba, and we will give you a compass.&quot;
And so the Crusaders. We fight, we rejoice and become veterans.
Hem böylece Haçlı ordularıyla
savaşır, cenk eder gazi oluruz
And so the Crusaders. We fight, we rejoice and become veterans.
and finally we have a home.
hem de sonunda bir yuvamız olur.
Halep.
He must act now, sir.
Hemen harekete geçmeli beyim.
How long have I told you? action was taken ?.
Ne zamandır ben söylemeden
harekete geçilir oldu?
How long have I told you? action was taken ?.
Well, gentlemen.
Estağfurullah beyim.
Is Gundogdu's idea acceptable?
Gündoğdu’nun fikri kabul mü ağalar?
It is true. Suitable.
Doğrudur.
Uygundur.
It is true. Suitable.
I think it's appropriate.
Bence de münasiptir.
I hope it's good.
Hayırlı olur inşallah.
God willing.
İnşallah.
Well, who's going to be the ambassador, sir?
Peki, elçi olarak kim gidecek beyim?
Deh.
Deh!
Ertugrul.
Suleyman Shah, those without the oban. they've paid our dignity.
Süleyman Şah, obandaki densizler
şerefimizi iki paralık ettiler.
Suleyman Shah, those without the oban. they've paid our dignity.
Obama is a sultan of honor. My honor, Kara Toygar.
Obama yurt veren bir sultanın şerefi
benim de şerefimdir Kara Toygar.
Obama is a sultan of honor. My honor, Kara Toygar.
What have we done to Sultan Alaaddin.
Ne yapmışız da Sultan Alâaddin’in
And the honor of his commander. We've got two bucks.
ve de komutanının şerefini
iki paralık etmişizdir?
And the honor of his commander. We've got two bucks.
It's an ax.
Bu balta
He came out of the back of the man you killed.
öldürdüğünüz adamın sırtından çıktı.
You left the ax there?
Baltayı orada mı unuttun?
I forgot.
Unutmuşum.
Ambush to the unit as ambassador. and threw knights.
Elçi olarak gelen birliğe pusu
atıp şövalyelerini katletmişsiniz.
Ambush to the unit as ambassador. and threw knights.
Not content with that.
Bununla da yetinmeyip
unity You've kidnapped three prisoners.
birliğin Sultan'a getirdiği
üç mahkumu kaçırmışsınız.
unity You've kidnapped three prisoners.
Give these prisoners back.
Bu esirleri geri verin.
He doesn't know our custom. You sound like Black Toygar.
Töremizi bilmez
gibi konuşursun Kara Toygar.
He doesn't know our custom. You sound like Black Toygar.
We don't turn over the guest from our oba. Especially if he's hurt.
Obamıza gelen misafiri teslim etmeyiz.
Hele ki yaralıysa.
We don't turn over the guest from our oba. Especially if he's hurt.
Here, the Seljuk Sultan. I came to represent.
Buraya Selçuklu Sultanı'nı
temsilen geldim.
Here, the Seljuk Sultan. I came to represent.
How to obey the Sultan's order. so is my word.
Sultanın emrine nasıl uyulursa
benim de sözüme öyle uyulur.
How to obey the Sultan's order. so is my word.
What else would happen. you know Süleyman Şah.
Aksi hâlde neler olacağını
bilirsin Süleyman Şah.
What else would happen. you know Süleyman Şah.
We live by our tradition. We die with our ceremony Black Lark.
Biz töremizle yaşar,
töremizle ölürüz Kara Toygar.
We live by our tradition. We die with our ceremony Black Lark.
We know that the Sultan, the state man.
Biliriz ki Sultan, devletli adamdır.
But first, my ancestor says Oguz's custom. throne.
Ama önce atam Oğuz’un töresi der,
tahtına öyle kurulur.
But first, my ancestor says Oguz's custom. throne.
There's no sultan than a man who doesn't honor.
Töre bilmeyen adamdan sultan olmaz.
No gentlemen.
Bey de olmaz!
No man.
Adam da olmaz!
It's not our business with no man.
Adam olmayanla da bizim işimiz olmaz.
A commander of the Great Seljuks. as you need to know.
Koca Selçuklu’nun bir komutanı
olarak bunu bilmen gerekir.
A commander of the Great Seljuks. as you need to know.
I told you my last word.
Sana son sözümü söyledim.
Come on, go.
Hadi var git.
We asked you in our literature Suleyman Shah.
Sana edebimizle sorduk Süleyman Şah.
You have two days.
İki gün mühletiniz var.
If you don't. we know how to come and take.
Sen vermezsen
biz gelip almasını biliriz.
If you don't. we know how to come and take.
Don't confront the Seljuks. Or you'il know what's gonna happen to you.
Selçuklu’yu karşına alma.
Yoksa başınıza neler geleceğini bilirsin.
Don't confront the Seljuks. Or you'il know what's gonna happen to you.
What is my father trying to do?
Babam ne yapmaya çalışıyor?
He won't know what he's doing. husband until now.
Ne yaptığını bilmeyecek
kadar kocadı artık.
He won't know what he's doing. husband until now.
I told you I could smell it soon.
Yakında kokusu çıkar demiştim sana.
See what's going to happen.
Gör bak daha neler olacak.
Stay here.
Kalın burada.
Deh.
Deh!
Ibrahim en la ilahe illallah and Ibrahim enne. Muhammad abdühü and his Messenger.
Eşhedü en la ilahe illallah ve eşhedü enne
Muhammeden abdühü ve resulühü.
Ibrahim en la ilahe illallah and Ibrahim enne. Muhammad abdühü and his Messenger.
The Seljuk Sultan. He is the masterpiece of Alaeddin Keykubad.
Selçuklu Sultanı
Alâeddin Keykubad’ın başyaveri.
The Seljuk Sultan. He is the masterpiece of Alaeddin Keykubad.
The commander of the Khorezm.
Harzemşahlar’ın komutanı.
The caliph's right arm is Omar.
Halifenin sağ kolu Ömer.
Now the whole Islamic world. Let him seek revenge.
Şimdi tüm İslam dünyası
intikam peşine düşsün bakalım.
Now the whole Islamic world. Let him seek revenge.
Then it's the pope's turn.
Sonra da sıra Papa'da.
Bisoli.
Who did this?.
Kim yaptı bunu?
They were ambushed as they brought prisoners.
Esirleri getirirlerken pusuya düşmüşler.
I said who.
Kim dedim!
Kayi on.
Kayılar.
But we don't know who he is.
Ama kim olduğunu biz de bilmiyoruz.
Ertugrul.
You made this trouble for us.
Bu belayı sen açtın başımıza.
Don't come at me, man.
Üzerime gelme abi.
Going high. when will you give up?
Kafanın dikine gitmekten
ne zaman vazgeçeceksin sen?
Going high. when will you give up?
Ha? Nobody cares. Neither your father nor your oban.
Ha? Hiç kimse umurunda değil.
Ne baban, ne oban!
Ha? Nobody cares. Neither your father nor your oban.
What would you do if it was you? Ha? What would you do if it was you?
Sen olsaydın ne yapardın?
Ha? Sen olsaydın ne yapardın?
What would you do if it was you? Ha? What would you do if it was you?
Would you just leave them and walk away?
Onları öylece bırakıp çekip gider miydin?
I know Gündoğdu. he is not such a man.
Benim tanıdığım Gündoğdu
öyle bir adam değildir.
I know Gündoğdu. he is not such a man.
I know Gündoğdu ,. it does not violate justice and mercy.
Benim tanıdığım Gündoğdu,
adaleti de insafı da çiğnemez.
I know Gündoğdu ,. it does not violate justice and mercy.
What justice? What mercy?
Hangi adalet ha? Hangi insaf?
Look at that oban. It's crackling.
Şu obanın hâline bir bak.
Çatır çatır çatırdıyor!
Look at that oban. It's crackling.
Hunger everywhere.
Açlık her yerde.
Door at winter. It's not clear where we're going to migrate.
Kış kapıda.
Nereye göçeceğimiz belli değil.
Door at winter. It's not clear where we're going to migrate.
The animals were starving.
Hayvanlar açlıktan telef oldu.
It was justice.
Adaletmiş! İnsafmış!
Open your eyes now Open your eyes.
Aç gözlerini artık. Aç gözlerini!
Look around you.
Şu etrafına bir bak.
Right in the middle of the toy.
Tam da toyun ortasında
vital issues for oba. Look at what you're doing talking.
oba için hayati meseleler
konuşulurken şu yaptıklarına bir bak.
vital issues for oba. Look at what you're doing talking.
How will this oba survive? How?.
Bu oba nasıl ayakta kalacak Ertuğrul?
Nasıl?
How will this oba survive? How?.
Forgive me, Dad.
Affet beni baba
I couldn't protect him.
onu koruyamadım.
Onu koruyamadım.
I couldn't protect him.
Who the hell is this whole world? Let us keep Aktolgalı.
Bu koca dünya kime kaldı ki
bize kalsın Aktolgalı.
Who the hell is this whole world? Let us keep Aktolgalı.
Why should one live in this lying world?
Bu yalan dünyada niye yaşamalı insan?
Why should he ride?
Niye at sürmeli?
Why the sword?
Niye kılıç kuşanmalı?
Why should he go abroad?
Niye yurt tutmalı?
It was a state, a reproduction, a country, why?
Devletmiş, töreymiş, yurtmuş, niye var ha?
Cruel, unless we give a man. The sky will destroy the dome.
Zalim, adam vermezsek
gök kubbeyi başımıza yıkacakmış.
Cruel, unless we give a man. The sky will destroy the dome.
If we give it to the sky dome. Is it indestructible?
Eğer verirsek gök kubbe
başımıza yıkılmaz mı?
If we give it to the sky dome. Is it indestructible?
If I don't, the oba's in trouble.
Vermezsem obanın başı belaya girecek.
What should I do?
Ne yapmalıyım Aktolgalı?
Not even a breath. for this world we cannot rule.
Bir nefesine bile
hükmedemediğimiz bu dünya için
Not even a breath. for this world we cannot rule.
Will we bow?
boyun mu bükeceğiz?
Do we say thank you to the tyrant?
Zalime eyvallah mı diyeceğiz?
Then he won't be silent?
O vakit töre susmaz mı?
Then won't our furnace go out?
O vakit ocağımız sönmez mi?
Ha Aktolga?
Ha Aktolgalı?
Black Lark is a cruel. it will do all sorts of evil.
Kara Toygar tam bir zalim,
her türlü kötülüğü yapacaktır.
Black Lark is a cruel. it will do all sorts of evil.
You thought Aleppo well, Gündoğdu.
Halep’i iyi düşündün Gündoğdu.
Like you showed everyone your intelligence.
Herkese zekânı gösterdiğin gibi
Whose gentleman when the time comes. You showed that you would.
vakti geldiğinde kimin bey
olacağını da gösterdin.
Whose gentleman when the time comes. You showed that you would.
We need to get rid of Black Lark trouble.
Kara Toygar belasından kurtulmalıyız önce.
My father won't back down when he says honor.
Babam töre dedi mi geri adım atmaz.
Ah Ertuğrul ah.
Look at the trouble you're causing us.
Başımıza açtığın derde bak.
We have to convince my father.
Babamı ikna etmeliyiz.
If we can convince him. Ertugrul will come to the string.
Onu ikna edersek
Ertuğrul da dize gelecektir.
If we can convince him. Ertugrul will come to the string.
You talk like you don't know your father.
Babanı tanımazmış gibi konuşursun.
If the world collapses, it will not give captives.
Dünya yıkılsa vermez esirleri.
What are we gonna do then?
Ne yapacağız o vakit?
Your father is my ambassador to Black Lark. would send as.
Baban beni Kara Toygar’a elçi
olarak göndereceğini söyledi.
Your father is my ambassador to Black Lark. would send as.
I'il do whatever it takes.
Gereği neyse yaparım.
Mr. Ertugrul.
Do you have time?
Vaktin var mıdır?
What's up? Something bad happened?
Hayırdır? Kötü bir şey mi oldu?
No.
Yok.
I was gonna talk for today.
Bugün için konuşacaktım.
I'm listening.
Dinliyorum.
Black Lark is here.
Kara Toygar gelmiş.
He wanted us.
Bizi istemiş.
Yes, he did.
Evet, istedi.
Don't jeopardize your obani for us.
Bizim için obanı tehlikeye atma.
We can take care of ourselves.
Biz başımızın çaresine bakarız.
My father's recovering. We'il be on our way in two days.
Babam kendine geliyor.
İki güne kalmaz yol alırız.
My father's recovering. We'il be on our way in two days.
If the whole world came together.
Bütün cihan bir araya gelse
yet we will not surrender you to those oppressors.
yine de sizi o zalimlere teslim etmeyiz.
Black lark and bloody knife. If you do, it will be plague heavy.
Kara Toygar’la kanlı bıçaklı
olursanız bunun vebali ağır olur.
Black lark and bloody knife. If you do, it will be plague heavy.
Do not worry.
Merak etme.
We challenge all kinds of Apricots. we know how to stretch.
Biz Kayılar her türlü zorluğa
göğüs germeyi iyi biliriz.
We challenge all kinds of Apricots. we know how to stretch.
What's up?.
Hayırdır?
I can't sleep, Ana.
Gözüme uyku girmiyor ana.
Sit down.
Otur hele.
What do you keep in the ass?
Neyi eşeler durursun içinde?
Both fall into a fire when the main fall.
Bir ateşe düştüm ana. Hem de ne düşmek.
Only if I fall, I don't eat scum.
Sadece ben düşsem gam yemem.
I threw the whole oboe on fire.
Koca obayı da ateşe attım.
That's when you get where you fell. Did you know it would be?
Düştüğün yere vardığında böyle
olacağını bilir miydin?
That's when you get where you fell. Did you know it would be?
That you're going to get that bandit from bandits?
O gavurun eşkıyasını karşına alacağını?
What about that commander's crap. Did you know you'd be one with the Crusaders?
Ya o komutan bozuntusunun
Haçlılarla bir olacağını bilir miydin?
What about that commander's crap. Did you know you'd be one with the Crusaders?
Well.
Peki
Or that gazelle eyed.
ya o ceylan gözlünün
howl his back. Could you go back?
feryatlarına sırtını
dönüp gidebilir miydin?
howl his back. Could you go back?
How would I do, master ?.
Nasıl yapardım ana?
You couldn't.
Yapamazdın ya.
You wouldn't, son.
Yapmazdın oğul.
You can not.
Yapamazdın.
You knew what it would be like when you went hunting.
Ne ava giderken böyle olacağını bilirdin
nor with you. oboe
ne de kendinle birlikte
obayı ateşe atacağını.
nor with you. oboe
You threw it on fire.
Ateşe attın.
Yeah, you threw it on fire.
Evet, ateşe attın.
There is a fire, the nut burns to ash.
Ateş vardır, somunu yakar kül eder.
There's fire, he cooks the loaf.
Ateş vardır, somunu pişirir.
He showed you where you fell.
Senin düştüğün yeri o gösterdi.
What a rebellion. nor does it fall to obadaki.
İsyan etmek ne sana
ne de obadakilere düşer.
What a rebellion. nor does it fall to obadaki.
This is a test of God.
Bu cenabı Allah’ın bir sınavı.
In this exam, there is ash and cooking.
Bu sınavda kül olmak da var, pişmek de.
For him, the vesves inside.
Onun için içindeki vesveselere de
petty For those who do not know, never listen.
bu obadaki haddini
bilmezlere de hiç kulak asma.
petty For those who do not know, never listen.
You be the soldier of our custom, son.
Sen töremizin neferi ol oğul.
Your father's decisions. Stand firmly behind.
Babanın kararlarının
arkasında sımsıkı dur.
Your father's decisions. Stand firmly behind.
God and you and my father. Let us not miss the main.
Allah seni de babamı da
başımızdan eksik etmesin ana.
God and you and my father. Let us not miss the main.
God bless you, son.
Allah da seni korusun oğul.
Come on, get the water. Put it on your father's bedside.
Hadi al şu suyu da
babanın başucuna koy.
Come on, get the water. Put it on your father's bedside.
.
I brought water, Dad.
Su getirmiştim baba.
Give give.
Ver ver.
I should have been you instead.
Senin yerine ben olmalıydım.
It's the descendants of those who did this to you. I will fight until it is exhausted.
Bunun sana yapanların soyu
tükenene kadar savaşacağım.
It's the descendants of those who did this to you. I will fight until it is exhausted.
They're at the bottom. I will fight until I leave.
Onlar toprağın dibine
gidene kadar savaşacağım.
They're at the bottom. I will fight until I leave.
Your blood won't be down, brother.
Kanın yerde kalmayacak kardeşim.
I promise you.
Sana söz veriyorum.
Unless God is with me for revenge.
Tanrı intikam için yanımda olmazsa
I'il turn my face to demons.
şeytanlara döneceğim yüzümü.
On the Turkmens. I will carry hell.
Türkmenlerin üzerine
cehennemi taşıyacağım.
On the Turkmens. I will carry hell.
I will be their wrath until I die.
Ben ölene kadar onların gazabı olacağım.
I promise you.
Sana söz veriyorum.
Forgive me, Dad.
Affet beni baba.
.
That's it, Ilyas Fakih.
İşte böyle İlyas Fakih.
How this dream. I didn't know I would interpret it.
Bu rüyayı nasıl
yorumlayacağımı bilemedim.
How this dream. I didn't know I would interpret it.
But since last night. A fire fell into me.
Ama dün geceden beri
içime de bir ateş düştü.
But since last night. A fire fell into me.
There are two idiots, mister.
İki ahval var beyim.
The first is the hard time awaits us.
Birincisi zor günler bizi bekler.
Second, who will be the ambassador. There are spiritual orders.
İkincisi elçinin kim olacağına
dair manevi emir vardır.
Second, who will be the ambassador. There are spiritual orders.