The sooner the person intends.
Er kişi niyetine.
Allahu akbar.
Allahu ekber.
Esselamu aleyküm and mercy.
Esselamu aleyküm ve rahmetullah.
our brothers.
Kardeşlerimiz
they want the last time halallik.
sizlerden son kez helallik isterler.
Do you make your right halal ?. Good job.
-Hakkınızı helal ediyor musunuz?
- Helal olsun.
Do you make your right halal ?. Good job.
Are you halal? Good job.
-Helal ediyor musunuz?
-Helal olsun.
Are you halal? Good job.
-Helal ediyor musunuz?
-Helal olsun.
Are you halal? Good job.
God willing, they will also halal their rights.
İnşallah onlar da haklarını helal ederler.
The Prophet Muhammad sallallahu alayhi. and wa sallam for the intercession of our master.
Hazreti Muhammed sallallahu aleyhi
ve sellem efendimizin şefaati için
The Prophet Muhammad sallallahu alayhi. and wa sallam for the intercession of our master.
For the soul of our brothers.
kardeşlerimizin ruhu için
for the obedience and abundance of our oba.
obamızın dirliği ve bereketi için
For God's sake.
Allah rızası için
Al Fatiha.
El Fatiha.
My Bey.
Beylerim.
My Yigit.
Yiğitlerim.
Sons of my height.
Boyumun oğulları.
From the hearts of each of you. I know what's going on.
Her birinizin gönlünden
neler geçtiğini bilirim.
From the hearts of each of you. I know what's going on.
It's on that bastard. We have the right to blood.
Bu şerefsizin üzerinde
kan hakkımız vardır.
It's on that bastard. We have the right to blood.
Your bloodshed.
Döktüğü kanların
the sins.
aldığı ahların
he shouldn't stay with him.
onun yanında kalmaması gerekir.
Not that.
Lakin
it's not our place to execute this shitty man.
bu rezil adamı infaz etmek bize düşmez.
His punishment.
Onun cezasını
Sultan Alaeddin will appreciate.
Sultan Alâeddin takdir edecektir.
I'm Suleyman Shah.
Süleyman Şah'ım
How many main stone presses the bosom.
kaç ana taş basar koynuna
Kara Lark's got it. thinks of the lost soul.
Kara Toygar'ın elinde
yiten canını düşünür.
Kara Lark's got it. thinks of the lost soul.
Such a promise. You will burn our hearts.
Öyle bir söz
edersiniz ki yüreğimiz yanar.
Such a promise. You will burn our hearts.
Unaware of our master Kayi. When did you see him?
Gafiller! Beyimizin Kayı'yı
ezdirdiğini ne zaman gördünüz?
Unaware of our master Kayi. When did you see him?
Of course, for all of us. knows the right thing.
Elbet beyimiz hepimiz için
en doğru olanı bilir.
Of course, for all of us. knows the right thing.
My Bey.
Beylerim
No doubt the right to blood falls to us.
kan hakkı bize düşer şüphesiz.
But.
Ama
It does not belong to us to apply the short.
kısası uygulamak bize düşmez.
Collaborate with the Crusaders.
Haçlılarla iş birliği yapıp
the punishment of that despicable betrayer of his state.
devletine ihanet eden o soysuzun cezasını
Sultan Alaeddin should give.
Sultan Alâeddin vermelidir.
Anyone have any objections?
İtirazı olan var mıdır?
Commander Saru Börü.
Kumandan Saru Börü
Take Kara Toygar to Konya. The Sultan.
Kara Toygar'ı Konya'ya götürüp
Sultan'a teslim edecektir.
Take Kara Toygar to Konya. The Sultan.
That dog.
O köpek herif
He'll know before he takes his last breath.
son nefesini vermeden önce anlayacaktır ki
no betrayal remains with the traitor.
hiçbir ihanet hainin yanında kalmaz.
Commander, you're a lucky man.
Kumandan kısmetli adammışsın.
This black pig's in his own blood. you see it drown.
Bu kara domuzun kendi kanında
boğulduğunu görmek sana nasipmiş.
This black pig's in his own blood. you see it drown.
To Aleppo now. We have to leave in two days.
Halep'e hemen
iki gün içinde yola çıkmalıyız.
To Aleppo now. We have to leave in two days.
Are the preparations complete?
Hazırlıklar tam mıdır?
We've done the balances, sir.
Denkleri tamam ettik beyim.
Only one kilim. the tents remained dismantling.
Bir tek kilimhaneyle
çadırların sökülmesi kaldı.
Only one kilim. the tents remained dismantling.
Herds of animals are on their way, sir.
Hayvan sürüleri de yola çıktı beyim.
We trust with the shepherds. I put one of the guys in.
Çobanların yanına güvendiğimiz
adamlardan bir ikisini de koydum.
We trust with the shepherds. I put one of the guys in.
Then don't take the berate to El Aziz.
O hâlde beratı El Aziz'e götürme
stables
ahırlarla ağılların yapım işini de
I give you.
sana veriyorum Gündoğdu.
Dad, if you'll excuse me.
Baba eğer müsaaden olursa...
Father. Suleiman.
-Baba!
-Süleyman!
Father. Suleiman.
Suleiman.
Süleyman!
Suleiman. Bey.
- Süleyman!
-Beyim!
Suleiman. Bey.
Ah.
It's up to you now.
Artık iş sana kaldı.
Go to Sultan Alaeddin. one by one.
Sultan Alâeddin'e gidip
tek tek anlatacaksın.
Go to Sultan Alaeddin. one by one.
You'll tell him.
Ona diyeceksin ki
Kayi on.
Kayılar
the one you took to Konya. they kidnapped those rebellious princes.
senin Konya'ya götürdüğün
o isyankâr şehzadeleri kaçırdılar.
the one you took to Konya. they kidnapped those rebellious princes.
Then using their name.
Sonra onların adını kullanarak
other Turkmen obas.
diğer Türkmen obalarından
They gathered allegiance.
biat topladılar.
Rebellion to the palace.
Saraya isyan edip
They wanted to overthrow Sultan Alaeddin.
Sultan Alâeddin'i devirmek istiyorlardı.
Not willing to.
Buna razı gelmeyip
rebellious princes.
isyankâr şehzadeleri
again.
tekrar
I set out to take him to Konya.
Konya'ya götürmek için yola çıktım.
They ambushed me.
Beni pusuya düşürdüler.
They slaughtered my soldiers.
Askerlerimi kılıçtan geçirdiler.
My most trusted commander is Saru Börü.
En güvendiğim kumandanım Saru Börü
his head.
onun kellesini
they tore it right in front of me.
gözümün önünde kopardılar.
An army from Sultan Alaeddin. you will come here.
Sultan Alâeddin'den bir ordu
alıp geleceksin buraya.
An army from Sultan Alaeddin. you will come here.
Apricots, your wrath. They will see you have fever.
Kayılar, senin nasıl bir gazap
ateşi olduğunu görecekler.
Apricots, your wrath. They will see you have fever.
Then you'll come back again.
Sonra tekrar geri döneceksin
you are the only savior of the Sultan.
biricik kurtarıcısı olduğun Sultan'ın
You will be the right hand.
sağ kolu olacaksın.
I did everything I could.
Ben elimden geleni yaptım.
Unfortunately, his fever doesn't fall.
Maalesef ateşi bir türlü düşmüyor.
After this.
Bundan sonra
none of us but pray. nothing to do.
dua etmekten başka hiçbirimizin
yapacağı bir şey yok.
none of us but pray. nothing to do.
Our brain.
Beyimiz
whatever happens.
her ne olursa olsun
He wants us all to be in his power.
hepimizin işinde gücünde olmasını ister.
We all know our work and our strength.
Hepimiz işimizi gücümüzü biliyoruz.
When he opened his eyes.
O gözlerini açtığı zaman
Let no one see us missing.
hiçbir eksiğimizi görmesin.
We have a long way to Aleppo.
Halep'e kadar çok uzun yolumuz var.
And none of us will give up.
Ve hiçbirimiz pes etmeyeceğiz.
Welcome, sheik.
Hoş safa geldin şeyhim.
We're welcome, grandson of piracy.
Hoş bulduk pirimin torunu.
May the Lord intercede with us.
Rabb'im şefaatini üzerimizde kılsın.
Your grandfather had commanded heaven.
Cennet mekân deden buyurmuştu
each bird flies with its own genus.
her kuş kendi cinsiyle uçar
eagles with eagles.
kartallar kartallarla
lest the crows.
kargalar kargalarla diye.
Aleppo was hardly a crowd.
Halep, pek bir kalabalık oldu.
The eagles held a head. A head of crows.
Kartallar bir başı tutmuş,
kargalar bir başı.
The eagles held a head. A head of crows.
All of them are different.
Hepsinin de derdi başka.
Some are after the vaccine, without saying haram halal.
Kimisi aşının peşinde, haram helal demeden
some in the future.
kimisi istikbal derdinde
Allah's will in this business. without thinking.
Allah'ın bu işte rızası
var mı yok mu düşünmeden.
Allah's will in this business. without thinking.
If they have an account, traps.
Onların bir hesapları, tuzakları varsa
God also has an account.
Allah'ın da bir hesabı var.
Certainly, Allah is the Trapper.
Şüphesiz ki Allah, tuzak kuranların
is the best. God.
-en hayırlısıdır.
-Allah.
is the best. God.
Thank you.
Eyvallah.
Good news, Selcan Hatun.
Müjdeler olsun Selcan Hatun.
Your feelings are true.
Hislerin doğruymuş.
Not just for your husband anymore.
Artık sadece kocan için değil
You will live for your son.
oğlun için de yaşayacaksın.
With Ertugrul. a long way awaits us.
Ertuğrul'la beraber
uzun bir yol bekler bizi.
With Ertugrul. a long way awaits us.
And we'd be dying to go.
Hem gitmek için can atarız
both this way ,. will be the most difficult way of my life.
hem de bu yol,
ömrümün en zor yolu olacak
both this way ,. will be the most difficult way of my life.
I know.
bilirim.
He's my confidant.
Sırdaşım o.
He's my comrade, Sultan.
Yoldaşım o, Sultan.
I wish everything else was different.
Keşke her şey başka olsaydı.
If only.
Keşke.
I heard that.
Duydum ki
Our Suleiman Shah is not good at all.
Süleyman Şah'ımız hiç iyi değilmiş.
He was wandering around Azrael.
Azrail yöresinde gezinirmiş.
On his deathbed. they wait.
Ölüm döşeğinde zamanının
dolmasını bekler, derler.
On his deathbed. they wait.
We got you into trouble.
Derdine dert kattık.
We became a burden for Suleyman Shah.
Çok yük olduk Süleyman Şah'a.
May God help you.
Allah yardımcısı olsun.
Amine.
Âmin.
Suleyman Shah said.
Süleyman Şah'ımız demiş ki
Mr. Gundogdu is going to Aleppo.
Halep'e Gündoğdu Bey'im gidecekmiş.
He's going to take you, Halime.
Sizi de o götürecekmiş Halime.
Mr. Gündoğdu?
Gündoğdu Bey mi?
Don't forget to remove it.
Bunu sökmeyi unutmayın.
Connect tightly Our way is challenging.
Sıkıca bağlayın. Yolumuz zorludur.
So you came, Kurdoğlu.
Demek geldin Kurdoğlu.
I'll tell you what. You will be surprised when you hear.
Sana söyleyeceklerimi
duyduğunda şaşıracaksın.
I'll tell you what. You will be surprised when you hear.
The one who got us into trouble.
Başımızı belaya sokan
other than adding trouble to trouble. Our guests do not work.
dert üstüne dert eklemekten başka
işe yaramayan misafirlerimizin
other than adding trouble to trouble. Our guests do not work.
it became clear why it was so valuable.
neden bu kadar değerli olduğu belli oldu.
Yourself to us.
Kendini bize
Numan introduces my merchant.
tüccarım diye tanıtan Numan
It turned out that the Seljuk prince.
meğerse Selçuklu şehzadesiymiş.
Well, that.
Peki, bunu
telling me. What is your aim Selcan Hatun ?.
bana söylemekteki
amacın nedir Selcan Hatun?
telling me. What is your aim Selcan Hatun ?.
What happens with a little piece of information. Kurdoğlu.
Küçük bir bilgi kırıntısıyla neler
yapabileceğini gördüm Kurdoğlu.
What happens with a little piece of information. Kurdoğlu.
My father and Kurdoğlu Uncle.
Babamla Kurdoğlu Amcam
One day they went hunting. they were both our age.
bir gün ava çıkmışlar. O vakitler
ikisi de bizim yaşlarımızdaymış.
One day they went hunting. they were both our age.
My uncle Kurdoğlu fell off the horse.
Kurdoğlu Amcam attan düşmüş.
Why?.
Niye ki?
Did something happen to the horse? The horse is startled.
-Ata bir şey mi olmuş?
-At ürkmüş.
Did something happen to the horse? The horse is startled.
Because they came up with a huge bear.
Çünkü karşılarına kocaman bir ayı çıkmış.
What did Kurdoğlu do?
Kurdoğlu ne yapmış?
My uncle couldn't do anything. Because his leg is broken.
Amcam hiçbir şey yapamamış.
Çünkü ayağı kırılmış.
My uncle couldn't do anything. Because his leg is broken.
That's when he was about to tear my uncle right out.
O ayı amcamı tam parçalayacağı sırada
my father came and killed the bear with his spear.
babam gelip mızrağıyla ayıyı öldürmüş.
Wow, your father was very brave.
Vay. Baban çok cesurmuş.
That's when they became blood brothers.
İşte o vakit kan kardeşi olmuşlar.
Valiant, you will go tomorrow.
Yiğit, yarın gideceksiniz.
When you go Kayi is in the ob. Don't forget you have a brother.
Gittiğinizde Kayı obasında
bir kardeşin olduğunu sakın unutma.
When you go Kayi is in the ob. Don't forget you have a brother.
Let's go.
Hadi gidelim.
Valiant.
Yiğit.
Look.
Bak.
Run.
Koş.
Allah is the secret to Lokman Hekim.
Lokman Hekim'e sırrı veren Allah'ım
You protect us from irreplaceable troubles.
sen bizi onulmaz dertlerden koru.
The above cost.
Yukarıdalar.
Welcome, Nasir.
Hoş geldin Nasır.
You ordered me, sir.
Beni emretmişsiniz efendim.
Go to El Aziz immediately.
Derhâl El Aziz'e gidip
to the borders of those Apricots. Tell him to stop it from settling.
şu Kayıların sınırlarımıza
yerleşmesine engel olmasını söyle.
to the borders of those Apricots. Tell him to stop it from settling.
But, sir, Titus.
Fakat efendim Titus--
On Titus' stupidity. I can't talk and waste time.
Titus'un aptallıkları üstüne
konuşup vakit kaybedemem.
On Titus' stupidity. I can't talk and waste time.
It's just that.
O sadece
mistaken pawn
kendini vezir zanneden
bir piyondan ibaret.
mistaken pawn
It is very difficult to deter El Aziz from his decision.
El Aziz'i kararından caydırmak çok zor.
He really loved apricots.
Kayıları gerçekten sevdi.
El Aziz's love for the Kayi.
El Aziz'in Kayılara olan sevgisi
all Aleppo.
bütün Halep'e
infect the plague. Enough to afford?
veba mikrobu bulaştırmayı
göze alacak kadar çok mu?
infect the plague. Enough to afford?
Spies coming to kill Ertugrul.
Ertuğrul'u öldürmeye gelen casusları
Did you find out who sent it?
kimin yolladığını bulabildiniz mi?
According to the information I received, the Templars. has spiked everywhere.
Aldığım bilgilere göre Tapınakçılar
her yerde casuslarını harekete geçirmiş.
According to the information I received, the Templars. has spiked everywhere.
His contacts at the palace. Trying to solve.
Saraydaki irtibatlarını
çözmeye çalışıyorum.
His contacts at the palace. Trying to solve.
Come, Nasir, come.
Gel Nasır gel, gel.
Sir, it's important.
Efendim, mesele mühim.
I didn't want to wait for the morning.
Sabahı beklemek istemedim.
The correspondence is the plague of Anatolia. he would tell you it was broken.
Muhaberat Anadolu'nun vebadan
kırıldığını bildirir dururdu.
The correspondence is the plague of Anatolia. he would tell you it was broken.
Me too to be sure. our future allies.
Ben de emin olmak için
müstakbel müttefiklerimiz
Me too to be sure. our future allies.
Is this infected. I wanted to know if it was infected.
bu illete bulaşmış mı
bulaşmamış mı öğrenmek istedim.
Is this infected. I wanted to know if it was infected.
Sorry.
Efendim
I know you like apricots.
biliyorum, Kayıları çok sevdiniz.
A new Crusade attack.
Yeni bir Haçlı saldırısı olursa
cut to keep our limit. I believe they are caftan.
sınırımızı tutmak için biçilmiş
kaftan olduklarına ben de inanıyorum.
cut to keep our limit. I believe they are caftan.
Not that.
Lakin...
But, Nasir? What?.
Lakin, Nasır? Hı?
Sir, unfortunately. Many of their animals perished.
Efendim maalesef
hayvanlarının birçoğu telef olmuş.
Sir, unfortunately. Many of their animals perished.
Quiet.
Sakın!
Do not return apricots from the border, Nasser.
Kayıları sınırdan geri döndürmeyin Nasır.
Did you understand? Quiet.
Anladın mı? Sakın!
When you get the certificate.
Beratı getirdiğinde
Ertuğrul and myself. I want to meet.
Ertuğrul'la bizzat kendim
görüşmek istiyorum.
Ertuğrul and myself. I want to meet.
Come on, Gundogdu.
Hadi bakalım Gündoğdu.
All the gentlemen gathered in the tent.
Bütün beyler çadırda toplandı.
Today is the day.
Gün bugündür.
Don't talk like my father's dead.
Babam ölmüş gibi konuşma Kurdoğlu.
As much as you are your father's son.
Sen babanın evladı olduğun kadar
You are also the son of oba Gundogdu.
obanın da evladısın Gündoğdu.
When Oban was in charge.
Oban müşkül durumdayken
such as avratlar. Will you sit in your tent?
böyle avratlar gibi
çadırında mı oturacaksın?
such as avratlar. Will you sit in your tent?
As you descend from the plateau to the plain. the burden disappears.
Yayladan düzlüğe indikçe
müşkül ortadan kalkar
As you descend from the plateau to the plain. the burden disappears.
my father will recover.
babam da iyileşir.
I have no other words, Kurdoğlu.
Başka sözüm yok Kurdoğlu.
With the plateau. Do you know that you will meet Gündoğdu ?.
Yayladan düzlüğe inerken neyle
karşılaşacağını bilir misin Gündoğdu?
With the plateau. Do you know that you will meet Gündoğdu ?.
What do you mean, emmi?
Ne demeye çalışırsın emmi?
I don't mean that.
Demem o ki
This is not the way we go, son.
bu gittiğimiz yol, yol değildir evlat.
Toyun's decision, my father's order.
Toyun kararı, babamın da emri var.
I have no word of that, Kurdoğlu.
Bundan gayri sözüm yoktur, Kurdoğlu.
Do you think I have eyes on that power of attorney?
Sanır mısın ki o vekâlette gözüm var?
I've got your father set up in his shade?
Babanın gölgesinde otağına kurulasım var?
Don't you know me, Gundogdu?
Beni tanımaz mısın Gündoğdu?
You didn't tell me.
Sen demedin mi bana
Support my principality.
benim beyliğimi destekle
my father is now a husband. deadlock? Didn't I tell you too.
babam artık kocadı ondan beylik
çıkmaz diye? Ben de demedim mi sana
my father is now a husband. deadlock? Didn't I tell you too.
Just because I'm behind you, huh ?.
sonuna kadar arkandayım diye, ha?
What should he do?
Neyin davasını güdersin?
I'm an old man with his foot in the pit.
Ayağı çukurda bir ihtiyarım ben.
Your oba is brave like you.
Obanın senin gibi cesur
a gentleman who knows what he wants.
ne istediğini bilen bir beye
I've told you repeatedly that he needs it.
ihtiyacı olduğunu sana defalarca söyledim.
Get you out of this mess.
Seni bu müşkülden kurtarıp
new home.
yeni yurdunda
I want you to trust me until I do.
bey yapana kadar bana güvenmeni isterim.
Come to the point, emmi.
Sadede gel emmi.
Ertuğrul on our own. sinister
Ertuğrul'un başımıza
musallat ettiği uğursuz
Ertuğrul on our own. sinister
I also learned who the guests are.
misafirlerin kim olduğunu da öğrendim.
Numan and his son Seljuk. It is from the dynasty.
Numan'la oğlunun Selçuklu
Hanedanı'ndan olduğunu
Numan and his son Seljuk. It is from the dynasty.
I know they are princes now.
şehzade olduklarını biliyorum artık.
It's unclear who he is . Those people are what you call .
Kim olduğu belirsiz
o insanlar dediklerin var ya
It's unclear who he is . Those people are what you call .
The chick from the Seljuk dynasty.
Selçuklu Hanedanlığından hatun.
Or ,. That guy called your number, prince.
Ya,
Numan denilen o herif şehzade
Or ,. That guy called your number, prince.
That saint you despise the sultan.
o hakir gördüğün kız da sultan.
Oh, Ah.
If we deliver them.
Onları biz teslim edersek
Sultan revives obaya.
Sultan obayı ihya eder.
Seljuk territory. the most beautiful places.
Selçuklu topraklarındaki
en güzel yerlere kuruluruz.
Seljuk territory. the most beautiful places.
What do you want from me, Kurdoğlu ?.
Benden ne istiyorsun Kurdoğlu?
Give up Aleppo.
Halep'ten vazgeç.
Aleppo will be a disaster for all of us.
Halep, hepimizin felaketi olacak.
Let's get them tonight.
Bu gece onları alalım
and the Sultan Gundogdu.
ve Sultan'a verelim Gündoğdu.
My God.
Allah'ım
May he forgive you to us, to the Kayi.
seni bize, Kayılara bağışlasın.
Bey.
Beyim.
We're ready for the raid.
Baskın için hazırız.
And alikumselim, sir.
Ve aleykümselam beyim.
Alpargu, you go out.
Alpargu, siz çıkın.
I'd wait for you.
Ben de seni beklerdim.
But I wasn't expecting you, Gundogdu.
Ama ben seni beklemiyordum Gündoğdu.
Mr. Kurdoğlu.
Kurdoğlu Bey'im
raid the hand tent at night. and will miss the prince.
gece vakti el çadırına baskın
verip, şehzade kaçıracak
raid the hand tent at night. and will miss the prince.
I'm gonna miss this feast.
ben de bu şöleni kaçıracağım.
Is that okay?
Olur mu öyle şey?
Only yesterday.
Daha dün
crying and crying to let them go. You've been guards to people's tents.
gitsinler diye ağlayıp zırladığın
insanların çadırına muhafız mı oldun?
crying and crying to let them go. You've been guards to people's tents.
Pick up allegiance to your head.
Senin kafana göre biat toplayıp
You're a gentleman.
bey olduğun obada
Let us become the guard, emmi.
e bırak biz de muhafız oluverelim, emmi.
Besides, this oban must have a guard.
Hem bu obanın bir muhafızı olmalı.
It must be that dog.
Olmalı ki it köpek
shake your tail. obada
kuyruğunu sallaya sallaya
obada dolaşmasın.
shake your tail. obada
Tell me where you are. You learned this prince matter ?.
Hele söyle bakalım, sen nereden
öğrendin bu şehzade meselesini?
Tell me where you are. You learned this prince matter ?.
When I went to Kara Toygar as a messenger.
Kara Toygar'a ulak olarak gittiğimde
I pushed his mouth.
o itin ağzını yoklamıştım.
I understood his situation.
Onun hallerinden anladım.
Why did you keep it until this time?
Bu vakte kadar neden sakladın?
Suleiman Shah's own son. even if he kept it.
Süleyman Şah'ım öz evladından
bile neden sakladıysa
Suleiman Shah's own son. even if he kept it.
That's why I kept it.
ben de o yüzden sakladım.
You lie.
Yalan konuşursun.
You asked.
Sen sordun
I told him.
ben de söyledim.
Who sowed the seed of doubt into it.
İçine şüphe tohumlarını kim ektiyse
go ask him account.
git ondan hesap sor.
It's unclear who he is. Those people are what you call.
Kim olduğu belirsiz
o insanlar dediklerin var ya
It's unclear who he is. Those people are what you call.
From the Seljuk dynasty, chick.
Selçuklu Hanedanlığından, hatun.
That guy called your prince, your number. That saint you despise the sultan.
Numan denilen o herif şehzade,
o hakir gördüğün kız da sultan.
That guy called your prince, your number. That saint you despise the sultan.
Brother, I need to talk to you about something. Not now.
-Ağabey seninle bir şey konuşmam lazım.
-Şimdi değil.
Brother, I need to talk to you about something. Not now.
Brother. Not now, Dündar.
-Ağabey--
-Şimdi değil Dündar.
Brother. Not now, Dündar.
Gundogdu.
Something bad?
Kötü bir şey mi var?
That Numan and his son are princes. Did you tell Kurdoğlu, babe?
Numan'la oğlunun şehzade olduğunu
Kurdoğlu'na sen mi söyledin hatun?
That Numan and his son are princes. Did you tell Kurdoğlu, babe?
It is no?. Forget the evil.
-Hayırdır?
-Hayrını şerrini boş ver.
It is no?. Forget the evil.
Did you or didn't you?
Söyledin mi söylemedin mi?
What prince Gündoğdu ?.
Ne şehzadesi Gündoğdu?
What are you talking about?
Neden bahsedersin sen?
What makes you so angry?
Seni böyle öfkelendiren nedir?
Kurdoğlu their prince. chick.
Kurdoğlu onların şehzade
olduğunu öğrenmiş hatun.
Kurdoğlu their prince. chick.
What did he do?
Öğrenmiş de ne yapmış?
I don't know what he meant. but he wanted to keep it.
Niyeti neydi bilmiyorum
ama işte alıkoymak istemiş.
I don't know what he meant. but he wanted to keep it.
Where are the princes?
Şehzadeler nerededir?
They went with Ertuğrul.
Ertuğrul'la beraber gittiler.
You're in possession of El Aziz. I want you to take Ertuğrul.
El Aziz'e beratı senin
götürmeni istiyorum Ertuğrul.
You're in possession of El Aziz. I want you to take Ertuğrul.
But my brother gave you this job.
İyi de ağabey, bu görevi babam sana verdi.
Good, my friend. I'm giving it to you.
İyi ya gardaşım,
ben de sana veriyorum işte.
Good, my friend. I'm giving it to you.
Let's both do what we know. Ertuğrul Hem would not always say.
İkimiz de bildiğimiz işi yapalım
Ertuğrul. Hem sen hep demez miydin
Let's both do what we know. Ertuğrul Hem would not always say.
toy yours, so that the prey is mine.
toy senin, av benim olsun diye.
And you let him? What is your intention to do ?.
Sen de izin mi verdin?
Ne yapmaktır niyetin?
And you let him? What is your intention to do ?.
Do what you do. Did you or didn't you?
Ne yapmaksa yapmak.
Sen söyledin mi söylemedin mi?
Do what you do. Did you or didn't you?
I did not say Gündoğdu.
Ben söylemedim Gündoğdu.
What would I do with Kurdoğlu?
Benim ne işim olur Kurdoğlu'yla?
Kurdoğlu said that he heard from me?
Kurdoğlu mu söyledi benden duyduğunu?
He said he heard it from someone else.
Başka birinden duyduğunu söyledi.
But if you told me.
Ama eğer sen söylediysen
Babe, God be my witness.
hatun, Allah şahidim olsun--
You were not like this.
Sen böyle değildin
Something happened to you.
bir hâller oldu sana.
Carrying his son in his belly. Don't you trust woman?
Karnında evladını taşıyan
kadına güvenmez misin?
Carrying his son in his belly. Don't you trust woman?
She's gonna give you a son for her?
Sana bir oğul verecek hatununa?
Beyim, Ertugrul and their alps are gone.
Beyim, Ertuğrul ve alpleri gitmişler.
Gather the men you trust. let them pursue.
Güvendiğin adamları toparla,
peşlerine düşsünler.
Gather the men you trust. let them pursue.
Tell them.
Söyle onlara
they should not hesitate to shed blood if necessary.
gerekirse kan akıtmaktan da çekinmesinler.