Ana Hayme, this sinister girl. what do you get for? Ha?.
Hayme Ana, bu uğursuz kızı
ne diye alırsın yanına? Ha?
Ana Hayme, this sinister girl. what do you get for? Ha?.
Whatever happened to us. Isn't that because of you?
Ne geldiyse başımıza
bunlar yüzünden gelmedi mi?
Whatever happened to us. Isn't that because of you?
What a face he stops in our furnace ?.
Ne yüzle durur bizim ocağımızda?
Not in our grass. What are they doing in our obama?
Değil otağımızda,
obamızda ne işi var bunların?
Not in our grass. What are they doing in our obama?
How dare you ask me? Ha?.
Sen bana ne cüretle hesap sorarsın? Ha?
I said get out now.
Çık dışarı hemen! Hemen dedim!
Gentlemen, come on. Let's talk inside, come on.
Beylerim hadi,
hadi içeride konuşalım, hadi.
Gentlemen, come on. Let's talk inside, come on.
Everybody in the toy knows.
Toydaki herkesin haberi var.
What is happening? Your brain. What's going on in that way ?.
Ne oluyor? Beyinizin otağına
böyle girmekte neyin nesi?
What is happening? Your brain. What's going on in that way ?.
They wanted to meet their gentlemen. Hayme Ana.
Beyleriyle görüşmek istemişler
Hayme Ana.
They wanted to meet their gentlemen. Hayme Ana.
I didn't break your request.
Ben de ricalarını kırmadım.
Or deal with the state.
Ya devlet başa
or raven oak.
ya kuzgun leşe!
Walk.
Yürü!
Come on, I said.
Yürü dedim. Hadi!
Don't open yourself regardless.
Ne olursa olsun kendinizi açık etmeyin.
Yes, sir. Yes, sir.
-Emredersiniz efendim.
Walk.
Yürü!
Send princes Ertuğrul.
Şehzadeleri gönder Ertuğrul!
You send my father.
Sen de babamı gönder!
Let's.
Hadi.
Kill them all.
Hepsini öldürün!
All of it.
Hepsini!
Kill.
Öldürün!
What if our Solomon Shah does not return? What do we do, sir?
Ya Süleyman Şah'ımız geri dönmezse,
ne yapacağız beyim?
What if our Solomon Shah does not return? What do we do, sir?
My lord does not take this Black Lark ambition. What will we do if it comes at us?
Beyim bu Kara Toygar hırsını almaz da
üstümüze gelirse ne edeceğiz?
My lord does not take this Black Lark ambition. What will we do if it comes at us?
Endless, endless. he had troubles.
Ne bitmek, tükenmek bilmeyen
dertleri varmış obanın.
Endless, endless. he had troubles.
We've know.
Bilmezmişiz.
Old men in their power.
İşinde gücünde olan ihtiyarlar
toy they're looking forward to it.
toy meclisini şenlendirmeye
can atarlarmış meğer.
toy they're looking forward to it.
Beh, beh, beh, beh.
Beh, beh, beh, beh!
To know your lioness.
Aslanlığınızı bilmek için
your brain itself. you expect him to sacrifice.
beyinizin kendisini
feda etmesini beklermişsiniz.
your brain itself. you expect him to sacrifice.
We've know.
Bilmezmişiz.
Until now.
Şimdiye kadar
countless colors, blood sweat. Returning Suleyman Shah.
sayısız cenkten, kan ter içinde
dönen Süleyman Şah'ımız
countless colors, blood sweat. Returning Suleyman Shah.
I'm sure he would boast if he saw you.
bu hâlinizi görse eminim iftihar ederdi.
Kill them all.
Hepsini öldürün!
Why don't you attack?
Neden saldırmıyorsunuz?
Why is that?.
Neden?
Take these.
Al bunları!
I said kill them all. Kill them all.
Hepsini öldürün dedim size!
Hepsini öldürün!
I said kill them all. Kill them all.
Betrayal.
İhanet!
Lows.
Alçaklar!
I'm gonna ask for all of them.
Hepsinin hesabını soracağım sizden!
Attack.
Saldırın!
Ah.
AA.
Ah, ah.
I still have your brother Ertuğrul.
Ağabeyin hâlâ elimde Ertuğrul.
If anything happens to me.
Eğer bana bir şey olursa...
Don't bellow Black Lark.
Boşuna böğürme Kara Toygar!
Nobody's coming to help you.
Kimse sana yardıma gelmeyecek.
I want to talk alone, Mr. Ertugrul.
Yalnız konuşmak istiyorum Ertuğrul Bey.
The Alps are clear.
Alpler müsaade.
Long years. I commanded the Seljuk army.
Uzun yıllar
Selçuklu ordusuna kumandanlık yaptım.
Long years. I commanded the Seljuk army.
For Ali Selcuk both inside and. I shook swords outside, shed blood.
Âl-i Selçuk için hem içeride hem
dışarıda kılıç salladım, kan döktüm.
For Ali Selcuk both inside and. I shook swords outside, shed blood.
Then fate me. tossed next to my prince.
Sonra da kader beni
şehzademin yanına savurdu.
Then fate me. tossed next to my prince.
All I want is my only duty.
Bundan sonraki tek isteğim, tek görevim
protect the prince and his family.
şehzademi ve ailesini korumak.
The one I knew next to Kara Lark. that is why I contacted the soldiers.
Kara Toygar'ın yanındaki tanıdığım
askerlerle temas kurmam da bundandır.
The one I knew next to Kara Lark. that is why I contacted the soldiers.
This is Ertuğrul Bey.
Durum bu Ertuğrul Bey.
This is what I want, Mr. Afşin.
Benim de istediğim budur Afşin Bey.
Both my obam, my family and Halime.
Hem obamı, hem ailemi, hem Halime'yi
and Halime's. protect family.
hem de Halime'nin
ailesini korumak.
and Halime's. protect family.
Since our ambition is our desire.
Madem ki emelimiz, arzumuz bir
then let's stand like mountain ranges. across from that Black Toygar push.
o zaman sıradağlar gibi duralım
şu Kara Toygar'ın denen itin karşısında.
then let's stand like mountain ranges. across from that Black Toygar push.
You are a brave man, Mr. Ertugrul.
Siz yiğit bir adamsınız Ertuğrul Bey.
It is an honor to be friendly with you. It is an honor for me.
Sizin yanınızda candaş olmak şereftir,
onurdur benim için.
It is an honor to be friendly with you. It is an honor for me.
Tell me, Afşin.
Anlat o hâlde Afşin Bey.
Those soldiers you're in contact with.
Şu temasta olduğun askerler
How much influence ?.
ne kadar etkililer?
Let me tell you, Mr. Ertuğrul.
Şöyle anlatayım Ertuğrul Bey
Kara Lark. Oh, when you wish, one next to you.
Kara Toygar
aman dilediğinde, yanına bir tane
Kara Lark. Oh, when you wish, one next to you.
even the soldiers are too influential to come.
asker bile gelemeyecek kadar etkililer.
Then it's our job to make him wish.
O zaman bize düşen ona aman diletmek.
Then today at Eagle Hill. can us sword in the market.
O hâlde bugün Kartal Tepesi'ndeki
can pazarında bize kılıç
Then today at Eagle Hill. can us sword in the market.
I fell on you to be a shield.
sana kalkan olmak düştü Afşin Bey.
We will attack.
Biz saldıracağız
and you are the Seljuks next to Kara Toygar. you will keep your troops on the required level.
sen de Kara Toygar'ın yanındaki Selçuklu
askerlerini gereken safta tutacaksın.
and you are the Seljuks next to Kara Toygar. you will keep your troops on the required level.
Thank you, Ertuğrul Bey. we will surely be there.
Eyvallah Ertuğrul Bey,
mutlaka orada olacağız.
Thank you, Ertuğrul Bey. we will surely be there.
Today with the oppressed. We will keep pure against the oppressor.
Bugün mazlumların yanında,
zalimin karşısında saf tutacağız.
Today with the oppressed. We will keep pure against the oppressor.
The owner of the oppressed is witness to this.
Buna mazlumların sahibi şahittir.
God help us and get half.
Allah yar ve yardımcımız olsun.
Saru.
Saru!
I'll ask you for this.
Bunun hesabını soracağım sana!
Fucking dog.
Alçak köpek!
Burn in hell, Black Lark.
Cehennemde yanasın Kara Toygar!
With princes. you too will die.
Şehzadelerle birlikte
siz de gebereceksiniz!
With princes. you too will die.
I'll dry your lineage.
Soyunuzu kurutacağım!
Ah.
Those days are gone, Mother.
Geçti artık o günler Hayme Ana.
How will we get through the next yard? time to think about it.
Önümüzdeki yardan nasıl geçeceğiz
onu düşünmenin vakti.
How will we get through the next yard? time to think about it.
The Alpargu.
Know your limits.
Haddini bil!
For the salvation of our oba. we have to talk.
Elbette obamızın selameti için
konuşacaklarımız var.
For the salvation of our oba. we have to talk.
But it's also here. Suleiman is the privacy of our Shah.
Ama burası aynı zamanda
Süleyman Şah'ımızın mahremidir.
But it's also here. Suleiman is the privacy of our Shah.
To disturb our Mother Hayme. does not fit.
Hayme Ana'mıza rahatsızlık vermek
uygun düşmez.
To disturb our Mother Hayme. does not fit.
He's already got enough pain.
Zaten yeterince acısı var.
We could not think.
Düşünemedik.
Let's continue in my tent.
Benim çadırımda devam edelim.
Signs of the Beylik. Move to my tent.
Beylik alametlerini
benim çadırıma taşıyın.
Signs of the Beylik. Move to my tent.
My condolences, brother.
Başımız sağ olsun ağabey.
What happened in the caravan.
Kervanda olanlar
Death of the Alps. none of it was your fault.
Alplerin ölmesi,
hiçbiri senin suçun değildi.
Death of the Alps. none of it was your fault.
Did you already know?
Daha evvelden bilir miydin?
The Numa.
Numan'ın
is prince. Did you know before?
şehzade olduğunu
daha evvelden bilir miydin?
is prince. Did you know before?
No, I just learned.
Hayır, yeni öğrendim.
But obviously to hide. They had good reasons.
Ama belli ki saklamak için
iyi bir nedenleri varmış.
But obviously to hide. They had good reasons.
Like he tricked us. He tricked you.
Bizi oyuna getirdiği gibi
seni de oyuna getirdi.
Like he tricked us. He tricked you.
But you're still defending them.
Lakin sen hâlâ onları savunmaktasın.
Let me go, shepherds.
Bırakın beni keçi çobanları!
Who are you, huh? Dens are.
Siz kimsiniz ha? Densizler!
Leave.
Bırak!
The bandit is an informal Black Lark.
Eşkıyalığın gayrı sökmez Kara Toygar.
The persecution has expired.
Zulmünün miadı doldu.
Bandit.
Eşkıyalık ha!
A Seljuk commander. tribal
Bir Selçuklu kumandanını
derdest eden Türkmen aşireti.
A Seljuk commander. tribal
You think when Sultan Alaeddin hears them.
Sence Sultan Alâeddin bunları duyunca
who really. Thinks you are bandits ?.
kimin gerçekten
eşkıya olduğunu düşünecek?
who really. Thinks you are bandits ?.
Don't waste your breath, Black Lark.
Nefesini boşuna tüketme Kara Toygar.
Judiciary will be established first.
Önce yargı kurulacak.
. The decision will be made according to the custom.
Karar töreye göre verilecek.
When the ceremony spoke, the gentleman shut up and the sultan.
Töre konuştu mu, bey de susar, sultan da.
Let go, motherfucker.
Bırakın ulan!
Let go, let go.
Bırak, bırak!
Father.
Baba!
You all right, sir?
İyi misin beyim?
Want some rest, huh?
Biraz dinlen istersen ha?
I'm fine, Crazy Iron, I'm fine.
İyiyim Deli Demir, iyiyim.
Are we going back to oboe, Dad?
Obaya mı dönüyoruz baba?
No.
Hayır.
First that the infamous usurped from our caravan. we will go to get our goods.
Önce şu rezilin kervanımızdan gasp ettiği
mallarımızı almaya gideceğiz.
First that the infamous usurped from our caravan. we will go to get our goods.
Mr. Afşin.
Afşin Bey'im.
You know, sacrifice you.
Bilirsin sana canım feda.
But the end of this judiciary is not bad?
Lakin bu yargının sonu kötüye varmasın?
Don't worry, Saru.
Merak etme Saru.
Trust me.
Bana güven.
Obviously Kurdoğlu waited for the opportunity.
Belli ki fırsat beklermiş Kurdoğlu.
Or would you have established so much thesis?
Yoksa bu kadar tez kurulur muydu makama?
Shameless man.
Utanmaz adam!
He also gathered the signs of the principality and left.
Bir de beylik alametlerini toplayıp gitti.
We are sitting with our hands tied.
Biz de elimiz kolumuz bağlı oturuyoruz.
Enough Aykız.
Yeter Aykız!
Enough State affairs. you know and know yourself.
Yeter! Devlet işlerini
bilip bilmeden kendi kendine hâllenirsin.
Enough State affairs. you know and know yourself.
Are you allowed to, Hayme Ana ?.
Müsaade var mıdır Hayme Ana?
Come, girl, come.
Gel kızım gel.
It is no?.
Hayırdır?
You all wait with pain.
Hepiniz acınızla bekler durursunuz.
You wouldn't mind feeding yourself.
Karnınızı doyurmak aklınıza gelmez.
I wanted two bites to go down your throat.
İki lokma boğazınızdan geçsin istedim.
Thanks, girl.
Sağ ol kızım.
Put your hand on the table. Sit down late.
Koy elindekini sofraya,
geç otur şöyle sen de.
Put your hand on the table. Sit down late.
We all. we wait our hearts in our mouths.
Hepimiz
yüreğimiz ağzımızda bekler dururuz.
We all. we wait our hearts in our mouths.
As long as Suleiman Shah is in charge. they come with the best.
Süleyman Şah başlarında olduğu sürece
hayırlısıyla gider gelirler.
As long as Suleiman Shah is in charge. they come with the best.
But my sister Gündoğdu. He's very worried about my brotherinlaw.
Ama ablam Gündoğdu
eniştem için çok endişeleniyor.
But my sister Gündoğdu. He's very worried about my brotherinlaw.
You wait for your fathers.
Sizler babalarınızı beklersiniz.
I am for Mr. Ertugrul. I pray.
Ben de Ertuğrul Bey'im için
dua eder dururum.
I am for Mr. Ertugrul. I pray.
That's right.
Doğru dersin.
Your sister has a problem, I know.
Ablanın da derdi vardır, bilirim.
But don't worry.
Ama merak etmesin
soon we will go obadan.
yakında obadan gideceğiz.
I hope they all return safely.
İnşallah hepsi sağ salim dönecekler.
It's up to us to pray.
Bize de dua etmek düşer.
Dogs.
Soysuz köpekler!
Lows.
Alçaklar!
I'll kill you all. I'll kill you all.
Geberteceğim hepinizi!
Hepinizi geberteceğim!
I'll kill you all. I'll kill you all.
I'm gonna ask for all of them.
Hepsinin hesabını soracağım sizden!
I'll destroy you all.
Hepinizi yok edeceğim!
Not oboe.
Değil obanız
Apricots remember the name. There will not be one person in this world.
Kayılar ismini hatırlayan
tek bir kişi kalmayacak bu dünyada!
Apricots remember the name. There will not be one person in this world.
I'll kill you all.
Hepinizi geberteceğim!
Now you're on your way.
Şimdi tez yola çıkıyorsun.
Before he gets there.
Obasına varmadan
o You catch the dog called Gündoğdu.
o Gündoğdu denen iti yakalıyorsun.
And then. You're bringing him to Eagle Hill.
Sonra da
Kartal Tepesi'ne getiriyorsun onu.
And then. You're bringing him to Eagle Hill.
Eagle Hill?
Kartal Tepesi?
Eagle Hill.
Kartal Tepesi ya!
Turns out he was setting us up.
Meğer bizi tuzağa düşürecekmiş
o Kayi's goat herders.
o Kayı'nın keçi çobanları
Did you hear that, Saru?
duydun mu Saru?
They're gonna finish Kara Lark.
Kara Toygar'ı bitireceklermiş.
Bey.
Beyim
if you wish in advance. Let's take our precaution.
dilerseniz önceden
varıp tedbirimizi alalım.
if you wish in advance. Let's take our precaution.
Yes, Saru.
Evet Saru.
The archers you trust most.
En güvendiğin okçuları
Place it on the rocks of Eagle Hill.
Kartal Tepesi'nin kayalıklarına yerleştir.
As for my mark.
İşaretim gelince de
The ratio.
orasını
Hell for apricots. I want you to convert.
Kayılar için bir cehenneme
dönüştürmeni istiyorum.
Hell for apricots. I want you to convert.
Aye.
Başüstüne.
Saru.
Saru!
. We looked at the room where the goods were placed.
Malların konulduğu odaya baktık.
It's all done, sir.
Hepsi tamamdır beyim.
You okay, Dad?
İyi misin baba?
Ah.
I'm fine I'm fine.
İyiyim, iyiyim.
Bey.
Beyim
you are tired today.
bugün yoruldunuz.
Stay here for the rest of the night. I made you room.
Gece burada kalır istirahat edersiniz
diye size oda hazırlattım.
Stay here for the rest of the night. I made you room.
Let's move on.
Dilerseniz buyurun geçelim.
Thanks, Commander.
Sağ ol kumandan.
Ertugrul.
You stay here.
sen burada kal.
I go with Gündoğdu.
Ben Gündoğdu'yla giderim.
Mr. Ertugrul.
We need to talk to you. there are some issues.
Seninle konuşmamız gereken
bazı meseleler var.
We need to talk to you. there are some issues.
It's not like the jobs he's opened up to us.
Başımıza açtığı işler yetmezmiş gibi
and go without shame. Hayme takes refuge in Mother.
bir de utanmadan gidip
Hayme Ana'ya sığınır.
and go without shame. Hayme takes refuge in Mother.
Lamb wolf.
Kuzu kılıklı kurt!
But I'm Selcan.
Ama ben de Selcan'sam
what they do. I'll make you pay one by one.
bu yaptıklarını
sana bir bir ödeteceğim Halime.
what they do. I'll make you pay one by one.
Sister?.
Abla?
Gökçe where are you?
Gökçe neredesin sen?
Where did you hide again?
Yine hangi kuytuya saklandın?
Sister.
Abla!
Stubborn girl of the hand. he went to take refuge in Mother Hayme.
Elin soysuz kızı
gidip Hayme Ana'ya sığınır.
Stubborn girl of the hand. he went to take refuge in Mother Hayme.
My brother. per head in the nook.
Benim kardeşim
kuytuda köşede bir başına...
My brother. per head in the nook.
Sister, you're wrong.
Abla! Yanılırsın.
I'm not hiding anywhere.
Hiçbir yere saklandığım yok benim.
I come from the bitch, from their side.
Otağdan, yanlarından gelirim.
Look at my brother.
Bak hele benim kardeşime.
On the pretext of taking food. I got stuck next to them.
Yemek götürme bahanesiyle
yanlarına sokuldum.
On the pretext of taking food. I got stuck next to them.
I said I would, and I heard I would.
Diyeceğimi dedim, duyacağımı da duydum.
What did you hear?.
Ne duydun?
Kurdoğlu, has received the principality signs.
Kurdoğlu, beylik alametlerini almış
Tent.
çadırına götürmüş.
Obviously Solomon's. hope of his return cut.
Belli ki Süleyman'ın
dönüşünden umut kesilmiş.
Obviously Solomon's. hope of his return cut.
Did he take the signs of the Beylik to his tent?
Beylik alametlerini çadırına mı götürmüş?
Yeah.
Evet.
The Kurdoğlu.
What is your intention to do ?.
ne yapmaktır niyetin?
You wait here.
Sen burada bekle!
Sister.
Abla!
Ah.
Stop Gundogdu.
Dur Gündoğdu.
I saw the way you looked at Ertugrul today.
Bugün senin Ertuğrul'a bakışını gördüm.
You're his big brother.
Sen onun ağabeyisin.
Big brother doesn't look at your wife with a grudge.
Ağabey, karındaşına kinle bakmaz.
Besides, he saved you. He risked his life for it.
Hem o seni kurtarmak
için canını tehlikeye attı.
Besides, he saved you. He risked his life for it.
Father.
Baba
What do you say ?.
sen ne söylersin?
He risked his life?
Canını tehlikeye attı öyle mi?
He risked his life for us?
Canını bizim için mi tehlikeye attı
otherwise it is very precious. I don't know that for their guests.
yoksa o çok kıymetli
misafirleri için mi orasını bilmem?
otherwise it is very precious. I don't know that for their guests.
But there's one thing I know.
Ama bildiğim bir şey var.
If we fell into the life market. Ertuğrul is responsible for this.
Biz can pazarına düştüysek,
bunun sorumlusu da Ertuğrul'dur!
If we fell into the life market. Ertuğrul is responsible for this.
From your raid on your caravan. then his eyes covered with hatred.
Senin kervandaki baskından
sonra gözlerini kin bürümüş.
From your raid on your caravan. then his eyes covered with hatred.
You call the victim to blame.
Kabahat yüklemek için kurban ararsın.
Is Kurdoğlu comfortable?
Rahatın yerinde midir Kurdoğlu?
Instead of saving Gundogdu.
Gündoğdu'yu kurtarmak yerine
Suleyman Shah. Are you pleased to sit on the throne ?.
Süleyman Şah'ın
tahtına oturmak memnun etti mi seni?
Suleyman Shah. Are you pleased to sit on the throne ?.
You're in trouble with the man.
Erinin can derdine düştün.
I don't mean you're upset.
Canın sıkkın diye ses etmem.
But know where it is, Selcan Hatun.
Ama yerini bil Selcan Hatun!
I know where I am. I don't ask for an account.
Ben yerimi bilirim.
Ondandır hesap sormam!
I know where I am. I don't ask for an account.
To save Gündoğdu. Why don't you do something ?.
Gündoğdu'yu kurtarmak için
neden bir şey yapmazsın?
To save Gündoğdu. Why don't you do something ?.
Do you see what's happening in this oba?
Sen bu obada olanları görür müsün?
You hear that?
Duyar mısın?
If things happened to us I would. if I did not confiscate the events, oba would be divided.
Başımıza türlü işler geldi. Eğer ben
olaylara el koymasam, oba bölünecekti.
If things happened to us I would. if I did not confiscate the events, oba would be divided.
All kinds of work. Who came because?
Başımıza türlü işler
kimin yüzünden geldi ha?
All kinds of work. Who came because?
You didn't mess around?
Ortalığı sen karıştırmadın mı?
Suleyman Shah. I carried you what you're hiding from everyone.
Süleyman Şah'ın
herkesten gizlediğini sana taşıdım.
Suleyman Shah. I carried you what you're hiding from everyone.
I committed a crime.
Suç işledim.
What the hell did you do? No.
Amma velakin sen ne yaptın? Hiç!
What did you think I was gonna do?
Ne yapacağımı sanıyordun?
You betrayed me?
Beni hain mi belledin ha?
The secret intent of my obam. You think I'm gonna fly the enemy?
Obamın gizli niyetini
düşmana mı uçuracağım sandın?
The secret intent of my obam. You think I'm gonna fly the enemy?
What about them?
Onlara ne olacak?
It's called Black Lark. If he breaks into Gundogdu ?.
O Kara Toygar denen it,
Gündoğdu'ma kıyarsa?
It's called Black Lark. If he breaks into Gundogdu ?.
Ah.
We will pray for their salvation.
Onların kurtulmaları için dua edeceğiz.
This is what we can do.
Elimizden gelen bu.
. Before it went back to fire again.
Ortalık yine yangın yerine dönmeden önce
Seljuk. We have to leave as soon as possible.
Selçuklu topraklarından
bir an önce çıkmalıyız.
Seljuk. We have to leave as soon as possible.
Not for me.
Kendim için değil.
News from everything.
Her şeyden bir haber
for my sleeping son.
uyuyan oğlum için.
I understand you, Prince.
Sizi anlıyorum Şehzadem.
For everyone's salvation. I think that's the right thing.
Herkesin selameti için
en doğru olan bu galiba.
For everyone's salvation. I think that's the right thing.
Throw us to go alone. And you may need to give a compass.
Yalnız gitmemiz için bize at
ve pusat vermen gerekebilir.
Throw us to go alone. And you may need to give a compass.
I can think of another idea.
Benim aklıma başka bir fikir gelmekte.
Permission from my father after the funerals. I want to set out for Aleppo.
Cenazelerden sonra babamdan müsaade
isteyip Halep'e yola koyulacağım.
Permission from my father after the funerals. I want to set out for Aleppo.
Until you get there all right. I can take my alps.
Sizi sağ salim oraya kadar
götürebilirim alplerimle.
Until you get there all right. I can take my alps.
After that. Thank you, Mr. Ertugrul.
-Ondan sonrası...
-Sağ olasın Ertuğrul Bey.
After that. Thank you, Mr. Ertugrul.
Thanks.
Sağ olasın.
You and your family. I will always be grateful.
Sana ve ailene
her zaman minnettar olacağım.
You and your family. I will always be grateful.
Talk to Solomon Shah tomorrow.
Yarın Süleyman Şah'la konuşup
we set off as soon as possible.
bir an önce yola koyuluruz.
Ertugrul ?.
You sleep.
Uyumamışsın.
You didn't sleep.
Sen de uyumamışsın.
But we've been through this.
Bu durumu da atlattık ama
There 's a wolf gnawing on me.
içimi kemiren bir kurt var Deli Demir.
Black Lark ,. How did he know we were here ?.
Kara Toygar,
burada olduğumuzu nasıl bildi?
Black Lark ,. How did he know we were here ?.
Mother of the wolf gnawing at you. also gnawing at me.
Senin içini kemiren kurdun anası
da benim içimi kemirmekte.
Mother of the wolf gnawing at you. also gnawing at me.
Look, mister.
Bak beyim
I'll tell you something.
sana bir şey söyleyeceğim ama...
Come on, Master Iron.
De hadi Demir Usta.
It's the bastards' tent. raided night.
O itlerin Halimelerin çadırına
baskın düzenlediği gece...
It's the bastards' tent. raided night.
The one who took me away from the tents.
Beni çadırların yanından uzaklaştıran
I Kurdoğlu'y.
Kurdoğlu'ydu.
Nobody deserves it. I do not want to eat, Kurdoğlu'nun.
Kimsenin hakkını
yemek istemem, Kurdoğlu'nun da.
Nobody deserves it. I do not want to eat, Kurdoğlu'nun.
. But this is a matter of oba.
Ama bu mesele obanın meselesi.
I wanted to know.
Bil istedim.
There's news from Titus, master.
Titus'dan haber var efendimiz.
What did he write?.
Ne yazmış?
Dummies.
Aptallar!
They couldn't do a job.
Bir işi beceremediler!
Shah.
Şah!
And Mat.
Ve Mat!
Remember, when the game is over.
Unutmayın, oyun bitince
Shah too.
Şah da
pawns too.
piyonlar da
end up in the same box.
aynı kutuya girerler sonunda.
Who is the winner.
Galibin kim olduğunu
them off the table. only knows who lifts.
onları masadan
kaldıran bilir sadece.
them off the table. only knows who lifts.
You, you.
Siz, siz olun
before entering the box.
kutuya girmeden önce
Don't pull my anger on you.
öfkemi üzerinize çekmeyin.
Get word to Titus now.
Titus'a haber uçur hemen.
Black Lark.
Kara Toygar'ı
Let no one feed.
kimseye yem etmesin.
Titus, Apricots to Aleppo. Can they still keep them from coming?
Titus, Kayıların Halep'e
gelmelerini engelleyebilir mi hâlâ?
Titus, Apricots to Aleppo. Can they still keep them from coming?
I don't know if he can make it.
Bunu başarabilir mi bilmiyorum.
Not seeing tomorrow.
Yarını görememek
punishes my soul.
azap veriyor ruhuma.
Tell them to make preparations now, Marcus.
Söyle hazırlıkları yapsınlar hemen Marcus.
You're coming to Aleppo with me.
Benimle birlikte Halep'e geliyorsun.
Nasser and me. we have work to do.
Nasır'la halletmemiz
gereken işlerimiz var.
Nasser and me. we have work to do.
Another order for Titus. Is there a master?
Titus'a başka bir emriniz
var mı efendimiz?
Another order for Titus. Is there a master?
Black Lark. Let the fire of wrath be upon the apricots.
Kara Toygar'ı
Kayıların başına gazap ateşi kılsın.
Black Lark. Let the fire of wrath be upon the apricots.
Let him handle this on his own. Whether Kurdoğlu'yla.
Bu işi ister kendi başına halletsin
ister Kurdoğlu'yla.
Let him handle this on his own. Whether Kurdoğlu'yla.
Because I'm going to ask him about his account.
Hesabını ondan soracağım için
his preference is also his.
tercih de onundur.
Where is Süleyman Şah?
Süleyman Şah nerededir?
They say he's busted our caravan.
Kervanımıza baskın olmuş derler.
Where are the funerals, sir?
Cenazeler nerededir beyim?
Yeah, where's Mr. Right? Where are the funerals?
Evet, haklı. Bey nerede? Cenazeler nerede?
What is going on Kurdoğlu ?.
Neler dönmekte Kurdoğlu?
Kayı Gentlemen.
Kayı Beyleri
Do not time ah ,. it is not time to revel.
zaman ah etme,
vah etme zamanı değildir.
Do not time ah ,. it is not time to revel.
The mast of our obama is Suleyman Shah and. coach has still not heard from our valiant.
Obamızın direği Süleyman Şah'ımız ve
koç yiğitlerimizden hâlâ haber gelmedi.
The mast of our obama is Suleyman Shah and. coach has still not heard from our valiant.
God kept.
Allah muhafaza
just in case of our all kinds. we need to be prepared.
bizim her türlü ihtimale
hazırlıklı olmamız gerek.
just in case of our all kinds. we need to be prepared.
The union of our oba. and its strength is in danger.
Obamızın birliği
ve dirliği tehlike altındadır.
The union of our oba. and its strength is in danger.
And in the middle of all this trouble. Aleppo business.
Bir de tüm bu belaların ortasında
Halep işi.
And in the middle of all this trouble. Aleppo business.
In the time of our lord. reached this decision.
Beyimizin dirlik zamanında
vardığı bu kararı
In the time of our lord. reached this decision.
difficulty in time. we need to reconsider.
zorluk zamanında
tekrar gözden geçirmemiz gerekir.
difficulty in time. we need to reconsider.
What about Kurdoğlu ?. What's on your mind?
Ya ne edeceğiz Kurdoğlu?
Kafandan geçen nedir?
What about Kurdoğlu ?. What's on your mind?
Before I say what's in my head.
Kafamdakini demeden önce
I want to remind you that.
şunu hatırlatmak isterim ki
Before our Suleyman Shah set off. first he left me the power of attorney.
Süleyman Şah'ımız yola koyulmadan
önce vekaleti bana bırakmıştır.
Before our Suleyman Shah set off. first he left me the power of attorney.
My word.
Benim sözüm
is the word of our lord.
beyimizin sözüdür.
Thank you.
Eyvallah.
The fate of Aleppo to the unknown roads. I am not willing to be revan.
Halep'in akıbeti meçhul yollarına
revan olmaya gönlüm razı değildir.
The fate of Aleppo to the unknown roads. I am not willing to be revan.
Another place for immigration.
Göç için başka bir yer...
Suleyman Shah returned.
Süleyman Şah döndü!
.
Wait.
Durun!
Stop, stop.
Durun! Durun!
Don't do things that don't suit Kayi.
Kayı'ya yakışmayan işler yapmayın.
Toy will be judged.
Toy'da yargı konuşulacak.
He'll give the order to honor.
Hükmü töre verecek.
Take this man, tie him to the log.
Alın bu adamı, kütüğe bağlayın.
Ih Ih Leave me.
Ih! Ih! Bırak beni!
Hoot.
Yuh!
. Let me dry your lineage.
Bırakın. Soyunuzu kurutacağım.
Let's kill him.
Öldürelim onu! Öldürün!
Kill this.
Öldürün bunu!
Thank God you're back safe and sound.
Çok şükür! Sağ salim döndünüz.
God has accepted my prayers.
Allah dualarımı kabul etti.
Suleyman.
Süleyman! Süleyman!
Suleiman.
Süleyman!