Wake up, kid .
Alhamdulillahi of the world of rabbil.
Elhamdülillahi rabbil âlemin!
Oh, my God . Thank you .
Allah'ım
sana şükürler olsun!
Oh, my God . Thank you .
What did you do, get it done?
Ne yaptın, halledebildin mi?
Don't stop.
Dur yapma!
Why did you kill him? What's happening in here?.
-Neden öldürdün?
- Ne oluyor burada?
Why did you kill him? What's happening in here?.
We have learned a lot from you, Your Holiness.
Sizden çok şey öğrendik, Emir Hazretleri.
Not only our compasses in your city.
Şehrinizde sadece pusatlarımızı değil
at the same time. We need to protect.
aynı zamanda canımızı da
korumamız gerekiyormuş.
at the same time. We need to protect.
Who is this man, Nasir ?.
Kim bu adam, Nasır?
The Templars.
Tapınakçı.
What did you talk about at dinner?
Yemekte ne konuştunuz?
What did he want from El Aziz?
Ne istiyormuş El Aziz'den?
Apricots for wintering. They wanted a place from Emir.
Kayılar, kışlamak için
yer istediler Emir'den.
Apricots for wintering. They wanted a place from Emir.
The apricots should get what they want.
Kayılar istediğini almalı.
How so? I do not understand.
Nasıl yani? Anlamadım.
Receiving dormitory.
Alacakları yurt
On the borders of the Crusader County. Not only Ertuğrul.
Haçlı Kontluğu'nun sınırlarında
olsun. Sadece Ertuğrul değil
On the borders of the Crusader County. Not only Ertuğrul.
to dry your seed. there is no better opportunity than that.
soyunu da kurutmak için
bundan daha iyi bir fırsat olamaz.
to dry your seed. there is no better opportunity than that.
Kayi on.
Kayılar
On the outskirts of Amanos. no one has passed.
Amanos eteklerinde
kimsenin gelip geçmediği
On the outskirts of Amanos. no one has passed.
Barracks on the borders of Antakya.
Antakya Kontluğu sınırlarında kışlası.
This will be the last winters of their lives.
Hayatlarının son kışları olacak bu.
Titus, you know what you're saying?
Titus, ne dediğinin farkındasın değil mi?
This is a dangerous game.
Tehlikeli bir oyun bu.
Do what I say, Nasser.
Ne diyorsam onu yap, Nasır.
You won't let them go.
Peşlerini bırakmayacaksın.
Every step she takes, every step she takes. You will let me know every breath.
Attığı her adımı, aldığı
her nefesi bana bildireceksin.
Every step she takes, every step she takes. You will let me know every breath.
Take these pigeons.
Al bu güvercinleri.
He's the hero of oba. suddenly you look.
Obanın da kahramanı
oldun birden bakıyorum.
He's the hero of oba. suddenly you look.
You didn't look at us.
Yüzümüze de bakmaz oldun.
Suleyman Shah, oba's property. he won't give it to us to sell.
Süleyman Şah, obanın mallarını
satmamız için bize vermeyecekmiş.
Suleyman Shah, oba's property. he won't give it to us to sell.
We came to Obaya for nothing.
Obaya boşu boşuna geldik.
Come on, help me prepare a caravan.
Gel bakalım, kervan hazırlamama yardım et.
I'm not coming.
Gelmiyorum ulan.
Your heroism won't hurt me, Afşin.
Kahramanlığın bana sökmez Afşin.
Starve. I took you with me smelling.
Açlıktan nefesin
kokuyorken seni yanıma aldım.
Starve. I took you with me smelling.
I made you eat, I made you man.
Yedirdim, içirdim. Adam ettim seni.
You can't go back now, you owe me.
Şimdi dönemezsin, bana borçlusun.
Get well soon.
Geçmiş olsun.
Thank you, sir.
Sağ olasın beyim.
The fact that man is both a good trader.
İnsanın hem iyi bir tüccar olması
and the use of such good weapons. not much we have seen.
hem de böyle iyi silah kullanması
pek görüldük bir şey değil.
and the use of such good weapons. not much we have seen.
You were wounded last night. You fought well.
Dün gece bu yaralı hâlinle
iyi mücadele etmişsin.
You were wounded last night. You fought well.
The merchant's jazz. there's nothing left of you.
Tacirin cazgırının da
senden kalır yanı yok.
The merchant's jazz. there's nothing left of you.
If our merchandising was good, that's five. I wouldn't stay with kids without money.
Tüccarlığımız iyi olsaydı, böyle beş
parasız çocuklarla kalakalmazdım.
If our merchandising was good, that's five. I wouldn't stay with kids without money.
As for the sword.
Kılıca gelince
what we understand from the sword. having fun with the kids, that's all.
bizim kılıçtan anladığımız
çocuklarla eğleşmek, hepsi bu.
what we understand from the sword. having fun with the kids, that's all.
I hope you will soon. Our torment will be over, sir.
İnşallah yakında size
verdiğimiz eziyet bitecek beyim.
I hope you will soon. Our torment will be over, sir.
This is our only consolation, Numan Efendi.
Tek tesellimiz bu, Numan Efendi.
It's our only consolation.
Tek tesellimiz bu.
I owe you, huh?
Sana borçluyum ha?
Look at me, asshole.
Bana bak ulan, pislik herif.
I worked for you like a dog for years.
Senin için yıllarca köpek gibi çalıştım.
I owe all your favors.
Bütün iyiliklerinin borcunu da ödedim.
Get off my back now.
Düş yakamdan şimdi.
I'il rip your head off.
Kafanı kopartırım. Kaybol.
One trader.
Biri tüccar
caravan
biri kervan ayakçısı.
But they're warriors about guns.
Ama silah konusunda cengâverler.
You found each other well.
Birbirinizi iyi bulmuşsunuz.
Black Obsession. For some reason who your man is.
Kara Toygar'ın obadaki
adamının kim olduğunu nedense
Black Obsession. For some reason who your man is.
I do not wonder.
merak etmiyorum.
What are you doing?.
Ne yapıyorsun sen?
Selcen. Stop, stop.
-Selcan.
-Dur. Dur!
Selcen. Stop, stop.
You are sinning.
Günaha giriyorsun.
Allah's will is not prevented.
Allah'ın takdirinin önüne geçilmez.
If we had a baby. everything else would be different.
Eğer bir bebeğimiz olsaydı
her şey başka olurdu.
If we had a baby. everything else would be different.
Oh, chick.
Ah, hatun.
Someday, baby.
Bir gün olacak bebeğimiz.
No hope of Allah, Ha ?.
Allah'tan ümit kesilmez. Ha?
Anne.
Annen...
He will almost crown Halime.
...Halime'yi neredeyse baş tacı edecek.
Selcen.
Selcan
stop it.
uzatma artık.
What's going on. You don't realize it's over.
Neler olup
bittiğinin farkında değilsin.
What's going on. You don't realize it's over.
At the rug. You don't know the respect he shows.
Kilimhanede ona
gösterdiği saygıyı bilmiyorsun.
At the rug. You don't know the respect he shows.
He's showing him the respect he's given me.
Benden esirgediği saygıyı ona gösteriyor.
Like I'm not your son's wife. He treats me like I'm his maid.
Sanki ben oğlunun karısı değilim de
hizmetçisiymişim gibi davranıyor bana.
Like I'm not your son's wife. He treats me like I'm his maid.
Why is that?.
Neden?
Because I don't have a baby. She hates me.
Bir bebeğim olmuyor da ondan.
Benden nefret ediyor.
Because I don't have a baby. She hates me.
Selcen.
Selcan
You take my mother 's sin. He doesn't stoop to things like that.
annemin günahını alıyorsun bak.
Böyle şeylere tenezzül etmez o.
You take my mother 's sin. He doesn't stoop to things like that.
I know exactly what he thinks.
Ben onun ne düşündüğünü çok iyi biliyorum.
And the woman.
Ya kadın
Look exactly before the caravan. I can't listen to your nicks.
bak tam kervan öncesi
senin lakırdılarını dinleyemem.
Look exactly before the caravan. I can't listen to your nicks.
Okay? For the love of god.
Tamam mı? Allah aşkına.
You're not understanding, are you?.
Anlamıyorsun değil mi?
Halims, this obaya will pile. But you don't care.
Halimeler, bu obaya kazık çakacak
diyorum ama senin umurunda bile değil.
Halims, this obaya will pile. But you don't care.
Patience or patience.
Ya sabır, ya sabır.
Gundogdu, thank goodness has collected himself.
Gündoğdu, kendini iyi topladı çok şükür.
He deserved the caravan leadership.
Kervanın liderliğini hak ediyordu.
As he deserves to carry wood.
Odun taşımayı hak ettiği gibi.
Hopefully he will defeat his arrogance.
İnşallah kibrini de yenmeyi başarır.
Hopefully, Hayme.
İnşallah Hayme.
God willing.
İnşallah.
He collected the caravan very quickly, alone. It's not easy.
Kervanı çok çabuk topladı yalnız.
Hiç kolay bir şey değil.
He collected the caravan very quickly, alone. It's not easy.
She works day and night with her teeth and nails.
Dişiyle, tırnağıyla gece gündüz çalışıyor.
God bless.
Allah muvaffak etsin.
Sometimes.
Bazen
Sometimes what ?.
Bazen ne?
Nothing.
Yok bir şey.
Hayme, what's on your mind?
Hayme, aklından ne geçiyor?
I don't know, sir. There are all kinds of vesveses.
Ne bileyim beyim.
Türlü türlü vesveseler işte.
I don't know, sir. There are all kinds of vesveses.
Do not worry.
Merak etme.
Both will come and go safely.
İkisi de sağ salim gidip gelecek.
Hopefully, hopefully.
İnşallah, inşallah.
Halime, let's eat something.
Halime, hadi gel bir şeyler yiyelim.
Aykız, let me finish this, I'il be right back. Okay, well, I'm waiting.
-Aykız şunu bitireyim, hemen geliyorum.
-Tamam, peki. Bekliyorum.
Aykız, let me finish this, I'il be right back. Okay, well, I'm waiting.
Sister, what did you do? Don't worry about the account.
-Abla ne yaptın sen?
-Hesap soracağına işine bak sen.
Sister, what did you do? Don't worry about the account.
What did you throw into the accident? I'm trying to save you from that girl.
-Ne attın kazanın içine?
-Seni o kızdan kurtarmaya çalışıyorum.
What did you throw into the accident? I'm trying to save you from that girl.
Sister, that's not true.
Abla, bu yaptığın doğru değil.
It's also a matter. Not me, caravan.
Ayrıca mevzu zaten
Halime de değil, kervan.
It's also a matter. Not me, caravan.
Gökçe, why is your head so empty?
Gökçe, senin kafan niye böyle boş ha?
Do not you still understand? This is oba. The biggest disaster that ever happened to her.
Hâlâ anlamadın mı? Bu obanın
başına gelen en büyük felaket o kız.
Do not you still understand? This is oba. The biggest disaster that ever happened to her.
When will you understand that?
Ne zaman anlayacaksın bunu?
When Ertuğrul took him to his bosom?
Ertuğrul onu koynuna aldığı zaman mı?
Excuse me, sir?
Müsaade var mı beyim?
Sir, we've put you in a difficult position.
Beyim, seni müşkül duruma soktuk.
We want you to forgive us.
Bizi bağışlamanı istiyoruz.
If you make such a mistake again.
Bir daha böyle bir hata yaparsanız
will come across and ask for forgiveness. you do not have the opportunity.
karşıma geçip af dileyecek
fırsatı bulmazsınız.
will come across and ask for forgiveness. you do not have the opportunity.
His Holiness wants to see you.
Emir Hazretleri sizi görmek istiyor.
Come steppe, you son of a bitch, come.
Gel bozkırın yağız çocuğu, gel.
For what happened last night. I owe you an apology.
Dün gece olanlar için
sana bir özür borcum var.
For what happened last night. I owe you an apology.
Whoever's behind this, though.
Gerçi bu olayın arkasında her kim varsa
my uncle will find them and punish them.
dayım onları bulup gereken cezayı verecek.
My Dear uncle.
Dayıcığım.
To give you the dormitory you want. We decided, son.
Size istediğiniz yurdu vermeye
karar verdik bey oğlu.
To give you the dormitory you want. We decided, son.
In fact, Nasser convinced us.
Doğrusu bizi buna Nasır ikna etti.
Do you know here?. West of the Rebel River.
Burayı biliyor musun?
Asi Nehri'nin batısı.
Do you know here?. West of the Rebel River.
I heard your land is fertile.
Topraklarının bereketli olduğunu duydum.
His enemies are also fertile.
Düşmanları da bereketlidir.
The limit of those who came to kill you last night.
Dün gece seni öldürmeye gelenlerin sınırı.
Put it right with the devil. sheep
Tam da şeytanla koyun
koyuna yatılacak yermiş.
Put it right with the devil. sheep
That's all for your herd. Is it worth the danger?
Sürünüz için bu kadar
tehlikeye girmeye değer mi?
That's all for your herd. Is it worth the danger?
The enemy is always us. vigorous amount, keeps alive.
Düşman bizi her daim
dinç tutar, diri tutar.
The enemy is always us. vigorous amount, keeps alive.
Awesome, awesome, awesome.
Müthiş, müthiş, müthiş!
This steppe to the swarthy children. I love my uncle.
Bu bozkırın yağız çocuklarına
bayılıyorum dayıcığım.
This steppe to the swarthy children. I love my uncle.
Say.
Demek
scorpion You want your destiny.
akrebin kıskacında yoğurmak
istiyorsun kaderini. Öyle mi Ertuğrul?
scorpion You want your destiny.
Since the devil and the sheep. You are so curious to sleep.
Madem ki şeytanla koyun koyuna
uyumaya bu kadar meraklısınız
Since the devil and the sheep. You are so curious to sleep.
then it falls to us to say good luck.
o zaman bize de hayırlı olsun demek düşer.
I admire your courage once again.
Cesaretinize bir kez daha hayran kaldım.
With friends like you behind us.
Arkamızda sizin gibi dostlarımız varken
our breasts to the enemy. we do not hesitate to shield.
düşmana göğsümüzü
siper etmekten çekinmeyiz.
our breasts to the enemy. we do not hesitate to shield.
Still the words of Gokce. you think, Halime ?.
Hâlâ şu Gökçe'nin laflarını mı
düşünürsün, Halime?
Still the words of Gokce. you think, Halime ?.
No.
Yok.
What they told me.
Bana ne ki söylediklerinden.
Between Ertuğrul and Gökçe.
Ertuğrul'la Gökçe'nin arasında.
What is it to you?
Sana ne, öyle mi?
You've been eating up for two days. You don't think I see it, Halime?
İki gündür kendini yiyip bitiriyorsun.
Görmüyor muyum sanıyorsun, Halime?
You've been eating up for two days. You don't think I see it, Halime?
Aykız, let's take care of our business.
Aykız, biz işimizle ilgilenelim ne olur.
Okay, but look at this.
Tamam, ama bak sen de şu
Don't take Gökçe crazy.
Gökçe delisini ciddiye alma.
The bride becomes a bridegroom.
Kendi kendine gelin güvey oluyor.
Who knows, maybe.
Hayme Ana ile Gökçe kim bilir, belki de
Aykız.
To get this color. pheasant grass must enter into.
Bu rengi alması için
içine sülün otu girmesi lazım.
To get this color. pheasant grass must enter into.
Halime, who does that?
Halime, kim yapar bunu?
Anyways.
Neyse.
Everything has a cure.
Her şeyin bir çaresi bulunur.
The caravan will go, how do we raise it?
Kervan gidecek, nasıl yetiştireceğiz?
We'il raise Aykız. There's no other way.
Yetiştireceğiz Aykız.
Başka yolu yok. Yetiştireceğiz.
We'il raise Aykız. There's no other way.
We are going.
Gidiyoruz.
Let's go see our new place.
Gidip obamızın yeni yerini görelim.
Mr. Ertugrul. Or El Aziz ?.
-Ertuğrul Bey'im!
-Yoksa El Aziz?
Mr. Ertugrul. Or El Aziz ?.
Let's not wait too long for our new home.
E yeni yurdumuzu fazla bekletmeyelim.
.
Both Gündoğdu and my fatherinlaw.
Gündoğdu'nun da kayınbabamın da
Here's Mother Hayme. I don't want him to know I'm coming.
Hayme Ana'nın da buraya
geldiğimi bilmesini istemiyorum.
Here's Mother Hayme. I don't want him to know I'm coming.
No one will know.
Merak etme. Hiç kimse bilmeyecek.
Not that guy.
Hele o adam
Suleyman Shah will never know.
Süleyman Şah, asla bilmeyecek.
Like you said, Gündoğdu. I brought a pinch of hair.
Dediğin gibi, Gündoğdu'nun
saçından bir tutam getirdim.
Like you said, Gündoğdu. I brought a pinch of hair.
You're a big brain girl, Selcan. You don't deserve what you've been through.
Sen büyük bir beyin kızısın Selcan.
Yaşadıklarını hak etmiyorsun.
You're a big brain girl, Selcan. You don't deserve what you've been through.
She will be motherinlaw's arrogance.
O kaynanan olacak kadının küstahlıklarını
your husband looking at you like a dried branch. Enough.
-kocanın sana kurumuş dal gibi bakmasını--
-Yeter!
your husband looking at you like a dried branch. Enough.
Don't be ashamed of your suffering, Selcan. You'il get everything you deserve.
Yaşadığın acılardan utanma Selcan.
Hak ettiğin her şeyi alacaksın.
Don't be ashamed of your suffering, Selcan. You'il get everything you deserve.
The army of souls, your belly. to fill the man's offspring.
Ruhlar ordusu, karnını
erkeğinin dölüyle dolduracak.
The army of souls, your belly. to fill the man's offspring.
You'il have a son.
Bir erkek evladın olacak.
The fate of the Archbishop will also change.
Kayı Boyu'nun da kaderi değişecek.
Hamza.
We'il leave early tomorrow.
Yarın erkenden yola çıkacağız.
The ammunition of the Alps. Check it out.
Alplerin mühimmatlarını
kontrol et, eksik kalmasın.
The ammunition of the Alps. Check it out.
Head to head, sir.
Baş üstüne, beyim.
Good luck with. Thank you, Emmi.
-Kolay gelsin.
-Eyvallah Emmi.
Good luck with. Thank you, Emmi.
I thought you should go with your caravan.
Düşündüm de senin kervanla gitmen
not much like a good idea. did not come to me Gündoğdu.
pek iyi bir fikir gibi
gelmedi bana Gündoğdu.
not much like a good idea. did not come to me Gündoğdu.
Why is that?
O niye ki?
Push Black Lark. it is not clear what to do.
Kara Toygar itinin
ne yapacağı belli olmaz.
Push Black Lark. it is not clear what to do.
Next to the best in the Alps. It's too dangerous.
Yanına en iyi Alpleri de
alsan, bu çok tehlikeli.
Next to the best in the Alps. It's too dangerous.
You're a gentleman, no Ertuğrul. And your father's sick.
Sen bey oğlusun, Ertuğrul da yok.
E baban da hasta.
You're a gentleman, no Ertuğrul. And your father's sick.
You better find a way and stay in obada.
Bir yolunu bulup obada kalmanda fayda var.
Emmi.
The gentleman has no obada for his son. Do you look good?
Bey oğluna hiç obada
pineklemek yakışır mı?
The gentleman has no obada for his son. Do you look good?
Look around you.
Etrafına bir bak.
So much human property. He entrusted his labor to me.
Bu kadar insan malını,
emeğini bana emanet etti.
So much human property. He entrusted his labor to me.
E drive is of course to me.
E götürmek de elbette bana düşer.
Oh, like you said. Black Lark makes a shove.
Ha, dediğin gibi
Kara Toygar bir itlik yaparsa
Oh, like you said. Black Lark makes a shove.
we will do our best evelallah.
biz de elimizden geleni yaparız evelallah.
Don't bother.
Sıkma canını.
We've got everything ready, Mother. Gökçe finished the rugs.
Her şeyi hazır ettik Hayme Ana'm.
Gökçe bitirdi kilimleri.
We've got everything ready, Mother. Gökçe finished the rugs.
Don't worry about your hands.
Elleriniz dert görmesin.
I hope they find their value in the market.
İnşallah pazarda değerlerini bulurlar.
I touched it for you, Mother.
Bunu da sizin için dokudum Hayme Ana'm.
White girl, pure girl.
Ak kızım, pak kızım.
No one like you, girl.
Senin gibisi, kimselerde yok kızım.
He's in a hurry. When did you do that ?.
Bu kadar telaş içinde
ne zaman yaptın bunu?
He's in a hurry. When did you do that ?.
How many nights she hasn't slept, Mother.
Kaç gecedir uyumuyor, Hayme Ana'm.
Hullo.
Maşallah.
Halime, what are we gonna do?
Halime, ne yapacağız?
Why did this happen to me?
Neden böyle oldu Halime?
I guess we haven't used enough dung. Hayme Ana We will try again.
Yeterince tezek kullanmadık herhâlde
Hayme Ana. Yeniden deneyeceğiz.
I guess we haven't used enough dung. Hayme Ana We will try again.
You did your best. He won't catch up in the morning.
Sen elinden geleni yaptın.
Artık sabaha yetişmez.
You did your best. He won't catch up in the morning.
No.
Hayır.
If necessary, before sleep. Hayme Ana.
Gerekirse uyumadan, sabaha kadar
çalışıp yetiştiririz Hayme Ana.
If necessary, before sleep. Hayme Ana.
Do not worry about it.
Sen merak etme.
One last hope, huh? Well.
Son bir umut, ha? Peki.
Good luck with.
Kolay gelsin.
Welcome, gentlemen.
Hoş geldin, bey oğlu.
Ibn'Alababi before you hit the road. I wanted to get a blessing.
Yola düşmeden önce İbnü'l-Arabî'nin
bir hayır duasını almak istemiştim.
Ibn'Alababi before you hit the road. I wanted to get a blessing.
Shaykh Effendi is on his way.
Şeyh Efendi yola çıktı. Haberiniz yok mu?
Where?.
Nereye?
God knows.
Allah bilir.
I'm never gonna see her again? God knows.
-Bir daha onu göremeyecek miyim?
-Allah bilir.
I'm never gonna see her again? God knows.
But.
Ama
I have to find her.
benim onu bulmam lazım.
Did you lose it?
Kaybettin mi ki bulasın?
Did you find that you'd lose?
Buldun mu ki kaybedesin?
The largest possible. You made a fool, Titus.
Olabilecek en büyük
aptallığı yaptın Titus.
The largest possible. You made a fool, Titus.
That you failed to avenge your brother. Apricots have also plagued us.
Kardeşinin intikamını almayı beceremediğin
gibi Kayıları da başımıza musallat ettin.
That you failed to avenge your brother. Apricots have also plagued us.
Sorry.
Efendim
I did the right thing.
ben doğru olanı yaptım.
You did the right thing, huh?
Doğru olanı yaptın ha?
Such stupidity from you. I never expected.
Senden böyle bir aptallığı
hiç beklemezdim.
Such stupidity from you. I never expected.
Sir, from. I don't understand we're scared.
Efendim, kimden
korktuğumuzu anlayamıyorum.
Sir, from. I don't understand we're scared.
Is he from Ertugrul, or is he with you? Is it from the Ibn alNababi?
Ertuğrul'dan mı, yoksa o yanında
gördüğüm İbnü'l-Arabî'den mi?
Is he from Ertugrul, or is he with you? Is it from the Ibn alNababi?
How dare you tell me I'm scared?
Ne cüretle bana korktuğumu söylersin?
Listen to me, Titus.
Beni iyi dinle Titus.
To the Turks coming to our borders. you will never let.
Türklerin sınırlarımıza gelmesine
asla izin vermeyeceksin.
To the Turks coming to our borders. you will never let.
Never.
Asla!
You feel your revenge.
Eğer intikam duygun
If it passes one more time in front of their duties.
görevlerinin önüne bir kez daha geçerse
to your brothers. I bury it with my own hands.
seni kardeşlerinin yanına
kendi ellerimle gömerim.
to your brothers. I bury it with my own hands.
Hey, great God. What are you capable of.
Hey büyük Allah'ım,
sen nelere kadirsin be.
Hey, great God. What are you capable of.
This must be heaven.
Cennet burası olsa gerek.
But hell is under our noses.
Ama cehennem de burnumuzun dibinde.
Yes, from there onwards. Antioch Crusaders.
Evet. Oradan sonrası,
Antakya Haçlı Kontluğu.
Yes, from there onwards. Antioch Crusaders.
The secret castle of the Templars. It must be somewhere around here.
Tapınakçıların gizli kalesi,
buralarda bir yerde olmalı.
The secret castle of the Templars. It must be somewhere around here.
Satan is everywhere, Turgut. We're in Aleppo.
Şeytan her yerde Turgut.
Obamızda, Halep'te
Satan is everywhere, Turgut. We're in Aleppo.
everywhere.
her yerde.
We're gonna have fun, too.
Çok eğleneceğiz, çok.
Deh.
Deh!
Hey, masha. If you lift the stone, water will spill under it.
Hey maşallah beyim.
Taşı kaldırsan altından su fışkıracak.
Hey, masha. If you lift the stone, water will spill under it.
It's so fertile in my life. soils could not see.
Ömrümde böyle bereketli
topraklar göremedim.
It's so fertile in my life. soils could not see.
She grows babies.
Bebeleri büyütür
versions give obaya life.
sürümleri semirtir, obaya hayat verir.
Such a haven.
Böyle bir cenneti
How did they leave unattended, sir?
nasıl sahipsiz bırakmışlar beyim?
Right next door. That's why hell, Turgut.
Hemen yanı başı
cehennem de o yüzden, Turgut.
Right next door. That's why hell, Turgut.
Really, sir.
Sahi beyim
Why these Templars. They wanted to kill you.
bu Tapınakçılar niye
seni öldürmek istediler ki?
Why these Templars. They wanted to kill you.
The blood of the knights we killed. apparently they don't intend to quit.
Öldürdüğümüz şövalyelerin kanını yerde
bırakma niyetinde değiller anlaşılan.
The blood of the knights we killed. apparently they don't intend to quit.
Sir.
Beyim desene
they won't leave us alone here either.
burada da rahat bırakmayacaklar bizi.
Let go of them.
Bırak şu kefereleri.
Think about your wedding with Aykız.
Sen Aykız'la olan düğününü düşün.
Let that oba settle down. First thing, let's have your wedding with Aykız.
Hele şu oba bir yerleşsin,
ilk iş Aykız'la düğününüzü yapalım.
Let that oba settle down. First thing, let's have your wedding with Aykız.
I hope, sir.
İnşallah beyim.
Fucking goat. Hayti.
-Ulan hisli teke!
-Hayt!
Fucking goat. Hayti.
Another girl, though. he couldn't stand it.
Başka kız olsa,
dayanamaz çoktan başkasına varırdı.
Another girl, though. he couldn't stand it.
Lord.
Beyim.
We'il have a double wedding.
Bakarsın çifte düğün yaparız.
Flag the sun, sky will act tent.
Güneşi bayrak, göğü çadır eyleyeceğiz.
Our mares are endless. expanse to the plains.
Kısraklarımızı uçsuz
bucaksız ovalara süreceğiz.
Our mares are endless. expanse to the plains.
Halfway to our compasses. We will make our armies lush.
Pusatlarımızı yâr eğleyip,
ordularımızı gür kılacağız.
Halfway to our compasses. We will make our armies lush.
We have justice in seven climates. she will fluctuate.
Tamgamız yedi iklimde, adaletin
sancağı diye dalgalanacak.
We have justice in seven climates. she will fluctuate.
The hymn of the mountains. we will move beyond the seas.
İlahi muştumuzu dağların,
denizlerin ötesine taşıyacağız.
The hymn of the mountains. we will move beyond the seas.
Ah.
You came with your own foot. You've had your breath on our neck since Aleppo.
Kendi ayağınla geldin eceline.
Halep'ten beri nefesin ensemizde.
You came with your own foot. You've had your breath on our neck since Aleppo.
Tell me, who's got your collar?
Söyle, söyle tasman kimin elinde?
Aaa.
This is already hell.
Bu çoktan cehennemi boylamış.
These are messenger pigeons, sir.
Bunlar haberci güvercin beyim.
Then we'il send them to the owner.
O zaman bunları sahibine gönderelim.
And Lord, thank God.
Ya Rabbi, şükürler olsun.
The expected came.
Beklenen geldi.
What the hell are you talking about again?
Sen yine neler saçmalıyorsun?
You're the nightmare that's crumbling on you. Didn't you come with me because of Petruccio?
Sen de üstüne çöken bu karabasan
yüzünden yanıma gelmedin mi Petruccio?
You're the nightmare that's crumbling on you. Didn't you come with me because of Petruccio?
That was infested by the infidel Arabi of Andalusia.
O Endülüslü kâfir Arabi'nin savurduğu
I don't believe a single prophecy.
kehanetlerin bir tekine bile inanmıyorum.
My dear brother Giovanni.
Sevgili kardeşim Giovanni.
Don't call me Giovanni.
Bana Giovanni deme.
My name is Omer.
Benim adım Ömer.
You know too well.
Sen de çok iyi biliyorsun ki
Shaykh Ibn alNababi. everything he said came out.
Şeyhim İbnü'l-Arabî'nin
söylediği her şey çıktı.
Shaykh Ibn alNababi. everything he said came out.
The storm is heralding the expected leader.
Yıldız yağmuru beklenen liderin müjdecisi.
It's the shepherd he put in front of the Mongols. herd will rule the world?
Moğolların önüne kattığı bu çoban
sürüsü mü cihana hükmedecek?
It's the shepherd he put in front of the Mongols. herd will rule the world?
They are the only Islamic world. they will make a fist.
Onlar İslam âlemini tek
bir yumruk hâline getirecekler.
They are the only Islamic world. they will make a fist.
And that punch, your cursed order.
Ve o yumruk, sizin lanetli düzeninizi
razor
yerle bir edecek.
Did you get enough water, Gundogdu?
Yeterince su aldınız mı, Gündoğdu?
You won't find water when you cross Mount Kenger.
Kenger Dağı'nı geçerken su bulamazsınız.
We got it, sir.
Aldık beyim.
In order not to burden animals. we did not want to take too much.
Hayvanlara yük olmasın diye
çok fazla da almak istemedik.
In order not to burden animals. we did not want to take too much.
Good, is there anything missing?
Güzel, eksik bir şey kaldı mı?
There is Aykız and Halime.
Var. Aykız'la Halime.
I'il go jogging and see.
Ben bir koşu gidip bakayım.
Hah They are coming too.
Hah. Onlar da geliyor.
Sorry, we're late.
Kusura bakmayın, geciktik.
Is it over?.
Bitti mi?
It's all over, Mother.
Hepsi bitti Hayme Ana.
How is it worth going to the market ?.
Nasıl oldu, pazara gitmeye değer mi?
Show me one, how it happened.
Göster bakayım bir tanesini, nasıl olmuş.
How beautiful, lady?
Nasıl hanım, güzel mi?
I've never seen such vibrant colors in my life.
Ömrümde bu kadar canlı renkler görmedim.
Well, load the remaining prints.
İyi, kalan basmaları da yükleyin.
Get the caravan on the road.
Kervan yola çıksın.
Come.
Gel.
The caravan's on its way, sir. Gundogdu, the son of Suleyman Shah, is in charge.
Kervan yola çıktı komutanım.
Süleyman Şah'ın oğlu Gündoğdu da başında.
The caravan's on its way, sir. Gundogdu, the son of Suleyman Shah, is in charge.
Deh.
Deh!
Come here.
Gel bakalım.
Come come.
Gel, gel.
The flood went, the sand remained.
Sel gitti, kum kaldı.
Thank goodness, our soldiers. Our neck was not bent.
Çok şükür, erlerimizin
karşısında boynumuz bükülmedi.
Thank goodness, our soldiers. Our neck was not bent.
You're tired.
Çok yoruldunuz.
After you've been tidy up. then you can go and relax.
Etrafa çeki düzen verdikten
sonra sizler de gidin dinlenin.
After you've been tidy up. then you can go and relax.
Here you go.
Hadi bakalım.
Selcan, you come with me.
Selcan, sen benimle gel.
How long have you been talking to you? There is something I want.
Ne zamandır seninle konuşmak
istediğim bir mesele var.
How long have you been talking to you? There is something I want.
Here, mother.
Buyur ana.
My daughter.
Kızım
After your parents died.
anan ve baban öldükten sonra
you and your brother Gökçe are ours. you have become our life, our lungs.
sen de kardeşin Gökçe de bizim
canımız, ciğerimiz oldunuz.
you and your brother Gökçe are ours. you have become our life, our lungs.
You my own sons. I tried not to put apart.
Sizi kendi öz evlatlarımdan
ayrı koymamaya gayret ettim.
You my own sons. I tried not to put apart.
Bless you, Mother.
Canımız sana feda olsun, Hayme Ana'm.
We committed a crime without knowing? We broke your heart?
Bilmeden bir suç mu işledik?
Gönlünü mü kırdık?
We committed a crime without knowing? We broke your heart?
No, no, it's not like that.
Yok, hayır. Öyle bir şey değil.
What I'm trying to say is something else.
Benim söylemek istediğim şey başka.
Gökçe grew up.
Gökçe büyüdü
It was beautiful.
güzelleşti.
The lady became a girl.
Hanım bir kız oldu.
You no longer need to look at the head.
Artık baş göz etmek gerekir.
You're right, mom, I'm nice. I've been thinking about this for a long time.
Haklısın anam, ben de nice
zamandır düşünürüm bunu.
You're right, mom, I'm nice. I've been thinking about this for a long time.
Well.
Peki
Who are we going to deal with ?.
kiminle baş göz edeceğiz?
If you consent.
Eğer senin de rızan olursa
Ertuğrul and Gökçe are your husband on a pillow.
Ertuğrul ve Gökçe bir yastıkta kocasın.
Hey, Hayme. Ana'm Do you talk to me?
Estağfurullah Hayme
Ana'm. Bana laf mı düşer?
Hey, Hayme. Ana'm Do you talk to me?
Is that okay?
Olur mu öyle şey?
You've raised him since he was little.
Onu küçüklüğünden beri sen büyüttün.
I wanted to tell you first.
Ben önce sana söylemek istedim.
You check your mouth.
Sen bir ağzını yoklayıver.
Hayme Ana'in Emrin will be.
Emrin olur Hayme Ana'm. Emrin olur.
The pigeon . wing is up to the wolf's claw .
Güvercinin
kanadı, kurdun pençesine kadardır.
The pigeon . wing is up to the wolf's claw .
Solomon . Shah's son, Ertugrul .
Süleyman
Şah oğlu, Ertuğrul.
Solomon . Shah's son, Ertugrul .
Attack.
Saldırın!
.
Aah.
With the drums. We would be welcomed with kosler ?.
E hani davullarla,
köslerle karşılanacaktık?
With the drums. We would be welcomed with kosler ?.
There's something weird. Obviously the job is over.
- Bir tuhaflık var.
-İş güç bitmiş belli ki.
There's something weird. Obviously the job is over.
I guess the caravan's on its way. Everybody's nape.
Kervan da yola çıktı herhâlde.
Herkes ense yapıyordur.
I guess the caravan's on its way. Everybody's nape.
You continue.
Siz devam edin.
I'm gonna stop by my dad.
Ben babama uğrayacağım.
Wait.
Durun!