Allah makes a valiant, his banner. unites the whole world under.
Allah bir yiğit çıkarır, onun sancağı
altında tüm âlemi birleştirir.
Allah makes a valiant, his banner. unites the whole world under.
Both his sons and Constantine. conquers, takes Jerusalem.
Onun evlatları da Konstantiniyye'yi de
fetheder, Kudüs'ü de alır
Both his sons and Constantine. conquers, takes Jerusalem.
It also serves Mecca and Medina.
Mekke ile Medine'ye de hizmet eder.
Hopefully we will be the banner of that brave. Thank you under the cenk.
İnşallah biz de o yiğidin sancağı
altında cenk ederiz.
Hopefully we will be the banner of that brave. Thank you under the cenk.
God willing.
İnşallah.
I hope you're right.
İnşallah haklısınızdır.
I hope, my Lord, that valiant as soon as possible. we will relax.
İnşallah Rabbim o yiğidi bir an evvel
gönderir de biz de rahatlarız.
I hope, my Lord, that valiant as soon as possible. we will relax.
He shared his bite to me.
Bana lokmasını paylaşan
this is more valuable than each other. I want to know your friends of Allah.
bu birbirinden değerli
Allah dostlarını tanımak isterim.
this is more valuable than each other. I want to know your friends of Allah.
I am Ibn alArabi from Andalusia.
Ben Endülüslü İbnü-l-Arabî.
Ertuğrul by the neck.
Kayı boyundan Ertuğrul.
I brought molasses, Dad.
Pekmez getirdim baba.
Hands of health girl. Enjoy your meal.
-Ellerine sağlık kızım.
-Afiyet olsun.
Hands of health girl. Enjoy your meal.
So, tell me, Gundogdu.
Ee, anlat bakalım Gündoğdu.
What do you want to do? You need Oguz?
Ne yapmak istersin de
Oğuz töresine ihtiyaç duyarsın?
What do you want to do? You need Oguz?
If I was a gentleman. and Obama.
Eğer ben bey olsaydım
ve obama saldırsalardı
If I was a gentleman. and Obama.
to the Alps, unable to keep watch. I would think what punishment I would give.
nöbet tutmayı beceremeyen Alplerime
ne ceza vereceğimi düşünürdüm.
to the Alps, unable to keep watch. I would think what punishment I would give.
What would you do Kurdoğlu ?.
Peki sen ne yapardın Kurdoğlu?
I swear, my lord, Suleiman Shah. I say the punishment is his son.
Vallahi beyim, Süleyman Şah'ımızın
verdiği ceza evladır derim.
I swear, my lord, Suleiman Shah. I say the punishment is his son.
Son.
Evlat
someday you will be a gentleman.
bir gün bey olursun
Then you will seek the answer to this question.
bu sualin cevabını o vakit ararsın.
Now don't make your head busy with unnecessary things.
Şimdi kafanı lüzumsuz işlerle meşgul etme.
Make the most of your duty. think about how.
Kendi vazifeni en iyi şekilde
nasıl yapacağını düşün.
Make the most of your duty. think about how.
What mission?
Ne vazifesi?
Tomorrow's no thesis, oba for the caravan. you will collect the materials to be sold.
Yarından tezi yok, kervan için obanın
satılacak malzemelerini toplayacaksın.
Tomorrow's no thesis, oba for the caravan. you will collect the materials to be sold.
In three days. You will set off the caravan.
Üç gün içinde de
kervanı yola çıkaracaksın.
In three days. You will set off the caravan.
Lord.
Beyim
Why doesn't the merchant take the goods?
malları niye tacir götürmüyor?
Black Lark's intention is bad ,. caravan.
Kara Toygar'ın niyeti kötü,
kervanı basabilir.
Black Lark's intention is bad ,. caravan.
Because of this. we cannot give the goods to the merchant.
İşte bu yüzden
malları tacirin eline veremeyiz.
Because of this. we cannot give the goods to the merchant.
Gündoğdu will do this job with the Alps.
Gündoğdu, Alpleriyle bu işi yapacak.
Your order, Dad.
Emrin olur baba.
You've set me up for dinner. You shared your bite.
Bana sofranızı açtınız,
lokmanızı paylaştınız
You've set me up for dinner. You shared your bite.
It's your kindness in no time. I will not forget.
bu iyiliğinizi hiçbir vakit
unutmayacağım.
It's your kindness in no time. I will not forget.
Enjoy your meal.
Afiyet olsun.
Excuse me. I have to leave tonight.
Bana müsaade.
Bu gece yola koyulmak zorundayım.
Excuse me. I have to leave tonight.
Night roads are dangerous. We leave together at sunrise.
Gece yollar tehlikeli olur.
Gün doğarken beraber çıkarız yola.
Night roads are dangerous. We leave together at sunrise.
But I haven't seen my family in months.
Sağ ol. Ama aylardır ailemi görmem
them too. I don't want to make you more curious.
onları da
daha fazla meraklandırmak istemem.
them too. I don't want to make you more curious.
Aleppo is in the market. I have a carpet loom.
Halep, çarşıda
bir halıcı tezgâhım vardır.
Aleppo is in the market. I have a carpet loom.
I would like to welcome you all.
Sizleri, hepinizi orada ağırlamak isterim.
If we have time, we'il stop by.
Vaktimiz olursa uğrarız.
Be very alert, son. Crusaders can attack at any moment.
Çok uyanık olun evlat.
Haçlılar her an saldırabilir.
Be very alert, son. Crusaders can attack at any moment.
Those cavities. dervish
O gâvurların
buralarda esamesi okunmaz derviş.
Those cavities. dervish
You be careful, though.
Sen gene de dikkatli ol.
They're in every disguise.
Onlar her kılığa girip çıkar.
Thank you.
Eyvallah.
How are you, Turgut? I'm fine, I'm fine I'm better.
-Nasıl oldun Turgut'um?
-İyiyim, iyiyim. Daha iyiyim.
How are you, Turgut? I'm fine, I'm fine I'm better.
I came to myself.
Kendime geldim.
Where are we ?.
Neredeyiz?
Why when we have the means. We didn't kill them here.
İmkânımız varken neden
onları burada gebertmedik?
Why when we have the means. We didn't kill them here.
Fifteen soldiers in front of us. have killed warriors.
Karşımızda on beş askerimizi
öldürmüş savaşçılar var.
Fifteen soldiers in front of us. have killed warriors.
God finally accepted my prayers. he brought out my enemy.
Tanrım sonunda dualarımı kabul etti,
düşmanımı karşıma çıkardı.
God finally accepted my prayers. he brought out my enemy.
In Aleppo. We will prepare a nice welcome ceremony.
Halep'te onlara
güzel bir karşılama töreni hazırlayacağız.
In Aleppo. We will prepare a nice welcome ceremony.
O people, do not say we have not heard.
Ey ahali, duyduk duymadık demeyin!
In two days, the caravan will depart.
İki güne, kervan yola çıkacaktır!
It is the order of Suleyman Shah.
Süleyman Şah'ın emridir!
O Akcakoca, this decoy caravan.
Ey Akçakoca, bu çığırtkan kervan deyince
You know what I had in mind? What?.
-aklıma ne geldi biliyor musun?
-Ne?
You know what I had in mind? What?.
If you had listened to what I said.
Eğer sen benim dediklerimi dinleseydin
one end of your caravan would be in China.
senin kervanın bir ucu ta Çin'de olurdu.
Don't start, Crazy Iron, don't start.
Başlama yine Deli Demir, başlama!
Or Akçakoca'm no need to get angry ,. Look, I wouldn't say.
Ya Akçakoca'm kızmanın gereği yok,
bak demem o ki
Or Akçakoca'm no need to get angry ,. Look, I wouldn't say.
it was a wound ointment.
bu yara merhemiydi, dert merhemiydi
The remedy was ointment ,. it was a poison ointment.
çare merhemiydi,
zehir merhemiydi diye uğraşacağına
The remedy was ointment ,. it was a poison ointment.
You were going to make an ointment for women.
kadınlar için bir merhem yapacaktın
You were going to put them. yellow, blue, green, variegated bottles.
onları koyacaktın
sarı, mavi, yeşil, alacalı şişelere
You were going to put them. yellow, blue, green, variegated bottles.
women were going to put face to face.
kadınlar yüzüne gözüne süreceklerdi
when they find themselves beautiful. you wouldn't call it akche akche.
kendilerini güzel bulunca da
sen akçeye akçe demeyecektin.
when they find themselves beautiful. you wouldn't call it akche akche.
Or go to work, fesuphanallah.
Ya de git işine, fesuphanallah.
No, girl. Obada cattle can't grow dung.
Hayrola kızım?
Obada sığırlar tezek yetiştiremiyor size.
No, girl. Obada cattle can't grow dung.
Dad, if you love God. we are already in our noses.
Babam, Allah'ını seversen ya,
zaten canımız burnumuzda.
Dad, if you love God. we are already in our noses.
All right, nobody says anything.
Anlaşıldı, kimseye de bir şey söylenmiyor.
Did you wash it?
Yıkadın mı?
Put some more, Aykız.
Koy biraz daha, Aykız.
Is that enough, Halime? Enough, enough.
-Bu kadar tezek yeter mi Halime?
-Yeter, yeter inşallah.
Is that enough, Halime? Enough, enough.
Everyone's nervous, Halime.
Herkes tedirgin Halime.
The fabric deposited on the thread. They say no.
Tezeğe yatırılan kumaştan
hayır mı gelir derler.
The fabric deposited on the thread. They say no.
Just because all the efforts will be wasted. They dertlenmek.
Tüm emekler boşa çıkacak diye
dertlenirler.
Just because all the efforts will be wasted. They dertlenmek.
Look, Aykız.
Bak Aykız
The pressure they put on Mother Hayme. Why do you think he's faint?
Hayme Ana'ya getirdikleri baskılar
sence niye soluk çıktı?
The pressure they put on Mother Hayme. Why do you think he's faint?
Because the fabrics were faded.
Kumaşlar soluktu da ondan.
First we're going to print. we should bleach the fabrics.
Evvela baskı yapacağımız
kumaşları beyazlatmalıyız.
First we're going to print. we should bleach the fabrics.
Those ducks, these ducks. will make our fabrics snow white.
Bu tezekler var ya, bu tezekler
kumaşlarımızı kar beyazı yapacak.
Those ducks, these ducks. will make our fabrics snow white.
Then process the pattern you want.
Sonra istediğin deseni işle.
Believe me, Aykız. it will be really beautiful.
İnan bana Aykız,
gerçekten çok güzel olacak.
Believe me, Aykız. it will be really beautiful.
Let's get in trouble.
Derdimize derman olsun da.
But if we can't. We're still ruined.
Lakin beceremezsek
hâlimiz harap Halime.
But if we can't. We're still ruined.
We fall into the language of the nation.
Milletin diline düşeriz.
Aykız, who took this consistency. Let them wait a little in the sun.
Bu kıvamını aldı Aykız,
biraz güneşte beklesinler.
Aykız, who took this consistency. Let them wait a little in the sun.
Easy chicks.
Kolay gele hatunlar.
No, what do you do?
Hayrola, ne işle uğraşırsınız?
We put the fabrics on the thread.
Kumaşları tezeğe yatırırız.
Do you deposit the fabrics on the jungle ?.
Kumaşları tezeğe mi yatırırsınız?
Health in my mouth goodness.
Ağzıma iyilik sağlık.
Where did this Aykız come from?
Nereden çıktı bu Aykız?
My sisterinlaw. Hayme received desturades from Mother.
Halime bacım,
Hayme Ana'dan destur aldı.
My sisterinlaw. Hayme received desturades from Mother.
What happened to us.
Vah başımıza gelenler.
The mess isn't. we had one fabric left.
Pisliğin bulaşmadığı
bir kumaşımız kalmıştı.
The mess isn't. we had one fabric left.
What the hell is this?
Bu ne hâl Gökçe?
She got into the kilim. Why didn't you say stop?
Hatun kilimhaneye de el atmış,
neden dur demedin?
She got into the kilim. Why didn't you say stop?
What was I gonna say, sister?
Ne diyecektim abla?
After Mother Hayme said okay. Does that sound to me?
Hayme Ana tamam dedikten sonra
bana laf mı düşer?
After Mother Hayme said okay. Does that sound to me?
And don't worry about it.
Hem sen tasalanma.
They already got this job. when they get into their faces.
Onlar zaten bu işi ellerine
yüzlerine bulaştırdıklarında
They already got this job. when they get into their faces.
they will pay the price themselves.
bedelini kendileri ödeyecekler.
Why should the hand of the man pay the price Gökçe huh?
Elin kevaşesi neden bedel ödesin Gökçe ha?
Unless those goods don't reach the caravan.
O mallar kervana yetişmezse
it is up to us to pay the price.
bedeli ödemek bize düşer.
Sister, you this girl. Why do you make it so big?
Abla, sen bu kızı
niye bu kadar büyütüyorsun?
Sister, you this girl. Why do you make it so big?
Look, the more you raise this girl, the better. and he's on his own.
Bak sen bu kızı bu kadar büyüttükçe,
o da kendi kendine palazlanıyor.
Look, the more you raise this girl, the better. and he's on his own.
You know why I'm raising Gokce ?.
Neden büyütüyorum biliyor musun Gökçe?
I have a pure brother. I grow it.
Saf mı saf bir kardeşim var da
ondan büyütüyorum.
I have a pure brother. I grow it.
The one my brother loves. this girl is trapped in her nets.
Benim bacımın sevdiği er,
bu kızın ağlarına dolanmış kalmış.
The one my brother loves. this girl is trapped in her nets.
But my sister won't, I will.
Ama bacım görmez, ben görürüm.
My sister won't hear, I will.
Bacım duymaz, ben duyarım.
Ertuğrul looks at this girl. not nice at all.
Ertuğrul'un bu kıza bakışları
hiç hoş değil.
Ertuğrul looks at this girl. not nice at all.
When you hit your hands on your knees. You remember my words.
Ellerini dizlerine vurduğun zaman
bu laflarımı hatırlarsın.
When you hit your hands on your knees. You remember my words.
There's a smile on three branches .
Üç dalda bir gülüm var
I have a dervish .
Dervişim keşkülüm var
Medet or Abdulkadir .
I have a client .
Benim bir müşkülüm var
Pirin.
Your grandfather's Geylani. The smell comes from you Halebi.
Deden pirimiz Geylani Hazretleri'nin
kokusu geliyor senden Halebi.
Your grandfather's Geylani. The smell comes from you Halebi.
Thank you Welcome pirim.
Eyvallah. Hoş geldiniz pirim.
We've come a long way with our guests.
Misafirlerimizle uzun yoldan geldik.
Ertugrul the son of Suleyman Shah of the Kayi tribe.
Kayı Boyu'ndan Süleyman Şah oğlu Ertuğrul.
They're going to the palace.
Bir maruzatları var, saraya gidecekler.
They had rice. Today is the court's supply day.
Pirim nasipleri varmış.
Bugün sarayın arz günü.
They had rice. Today is the court's supply day.
They did, if they didn't. they will have to wait a month.
Görüştüler görüştüler, görüşemezlerse
bir ay beklemek zorunda kalacaklar.
They did, if they didn't. they will have to wait a month.
My cruel boy, son.
Zülcelâl-i vel-İkrâm evlat.
Oh, my God, it's a day of fabric. I'll use it to whiten.
Hay Allah'ım, tezekleri bir gün kumaş
beyazlatmak için kullanacağım
Oh, my God, it's a day of fabric. I'll use it to whiten.
I never thought of Halime.
hiç aklıma gelmezdi Halime.
You whites. Let it appear.
Daha sen beyazlıkları
ortaya çıksın da gör.
You whites. Let it appear.
It's worth the ordeal we suffer, Aykız.
Çektiğimiz çileye değecek Aykız.
Then we will see those who are now.
O vakit bıdı bıdı edenleri göreceğiz.
Well, dowry fabrics. We put it on the moon.
Ee, çeyizlik kumaşlarını da
tezeğe yatırırız ha Aykız?
Well, dowry fabrics. We put it on the moon.
We'il put it down.
Yatırırız vallahi.
Let them come back safely.
Sağ salim bir dönsünler de.
Ready dowry? Not ready?
-Hazır mı çeyizin?
-Hazır olmaz mı?
Ready dowry? Not ready?
How long has he been waiting in the crates?
Kaç zamandır sandıklarda bekler durur.
Turgut Alp could not get off the horse.
Turgut Alp at sırtından bir inemedi ki.
Ah Turgut Alp ah, ah.
So, Aykız, Alpine chick is not easy to be.
Ee Aykız, Alp hatunu olmak kolay değil.
I have been waiting for Mr. Ertuğrul for years.
Ben de yıllardır Ertuğrul Bey'i beklerim.
Had the Deli of the merchant not been Deli Iron. my reputation would be destroyed yeksan.
Tacirin adamıyla Deli Demir olmasaydı,
itibarım yerle yeksan olacaktı.
Had the Deli of the merchant not been Deli Iron. my reputation would be destroyed yeksan.
This is Black Lark. Do you think he'il bring back the rape?
Bu Kara Toygar,
tecavüzlerinin arkasını getirir mi dersin?
This is Black Lark. Do you think he'il bring back the rape?
In the eye of your Numan, Kara Toygar. We now know its value.
Numan'ın, Kara Toygar'ın gözündeki
değerini artık biliyoruz.
In the eye of your Numan, Kara Toygar. We now know its value.
More valuable than we hoped.
Umduğumuzdan daha değerliymiş.
Kara Lark. he will afford everything for him.
Kara Toygar
onun için her şeyi göze alacaktır.
Kara Lark. he will afford everything for him.
What are you going to do?.
Ne yapacaksın?
Until Ertuğrul returned with good news. we will live in a war order.
Ertuğrul hayırlı bir haberle dönene kadar
savaş düzeninde yaşayacağız.
Until Ertuğrul returned with good news. we will live in a war order.
That guest's daughter, Halime. Eye ?.
-Şu misafirin kızı, Halime var ya...
-Ee?
That guest's daughter, Halime. Eye ?.
sight, fasten the color of the flushes. is trying to start with love.
...görme, basmaların rengini tutturmak
için canla başla çalışıyor.
sight, fasten the color of the flushes. is trying to start with love.
You think he'il make it? They earn the most in the market.
Başarır mı dersin?
Pazarda en çok onlar kazandırıyor.
You think he'il make it? They earn the most in the market.
Hopefully, sir, hopefully.
İnşallah beyim, inşallah.
Hopefully after I emigrate to Aleppo. Ertuğrul's marriage.
Halep'e göç ettikten sonra da inşallah
Ertuğrul'un evlilik işini...
Hopefully after I emigrate to Aleppo. Ertuğrul's marriage.
Anyways.
Neyse.
Let a forehead turn from Aleppo.
Bir alnının akıyla dönsün de Halep'ten
we'll see.
bakarız.
Who's on your mind? Gokce.
-Kim var aklında?
-Gökçe.
Who's on your mind? Gokce.
I'm surprised you think about her despite her sister.
Ablasına rağmen onu düşünmene şaşırdım.
Gökçe is a good girl.
Gökçe başka, o iyi bir kız.
Both.
Hem
maybe so that her sister's running out. it also prevents the ambition of the unknown.
belki böylelikle ablasının bitmek tükenmek
bilmeyen hırsına da mani olur.
maybe so that her sister's running out. it also prevents the ambition of the unknown.
If not Gökçe's heart. You wouldn't say that.
Gökçe'nin gönlü olmasa
böyle söylemezdin.
If not Gökçe's heart. You wouldn't say that.
What about Ertugrul ?. Do you have his heart?
Peki, ya Ertuğrul?
Onun gönlü var mı?
What about Ertugrul ?. Do you have his heart?
Well, we'il take a look.
Hayırlısıyla, bakacağız artık.
Sister, you embarrassed me.
Abla rezil ettin beni, rezil.
What do you say Gökçe?
Ne diyorsun Gökçe?
Because of you, Halime. looking into the eye.
Senin yüzünden Halime'nin
gözünün içine bakarak
Because of you, Halime. looking into the eye.
I told him I was expecting Ertuğrul.
Ertuğrul'u beklediğimi söyledim.
What more do you want? You're already late.
Daha ne istiyorsun? Geç bile kaldın.
Sister, you don't understand.
Abla anlamıyorsun galiba.
I heard everyone heard Aykız also heard.
Herkes duydu diyorum. Aykız da duydu.
Now everyone's gonna make fun of me.
Şimdi herkes alay edecek benimle.
The bride herself is a bridegroom. and your fault.
Kendi kendine gelin güvey olmuş
diyecekler ve senin suçun.
The bride herself is a bridegroom. and your fault.
Gokce.
Look at me.
Bana bak
You won't care if the world hears it.
dünya duysa umurunda olmayacak.
Like I got Gündoğdu. you will get Ertugrul.
Benim Gündoğdu'yu elde ettiğim gibi,
sen de Ertuğrul'u elde edeceksin.
Like I got Gündoğdu. you will get Ertugrul.
Scratching with your nail, plucking it with your tooth.
Tırnağınla kazıyarak, dişinle kopararak.
Your sweet tongue, your beauty. the son of the bastard.
Tatlı dilinle, güzelliğinle alacaksın
o soysuzun oğlunu.
Your sweet tongue, your beauty. the son of the bastard.
Whoever comes in front of you will crush it.
Önüne kim çıkarsa ezip geçeceksin.
As I was the wife of Gündoğdu. You will be Ertuğrul's wife.
Benim Gündoğdu'nun karısı olduğum gibi,
sen de Ertuğrul'un karısı olacaksın.
As I was the wife of Gündoğdu. You will be Ertuğrul's wife.
Suleyman Shah. our account is not over.
Süleyman Şah'la
görülecek hesabımız bitmedi.
Suleyman Shah. our account is not over.
Our father's killer. every day he sits on the grass.
Babamızın katilinin
otağda oturduğu her gün
Our father's killer. every day he sits on the grass.
our shame, our bleeding wound.
bizim utancımız, kanayan yaramız.
I don't have any more blood in the vein anymore. Do you understand?.
Artık damarda akacak kanım kalmadı,
anlıyor musun?
I don't have any more blood in the vein anymore. Do you understand?.
It's our right to sit in this grass. and we will take what we are entitled to.
Bu otağda oturmak bizim hakkımız
ve hakkımız olanı da alacağız.
It's our right to sit in this grass. and we will take what we are entitled to.
What do you want?.
Ne istersin?
You swallowed your tongue, man? Talk to me.
Dilini mi yuttun be adam? Konuşsana!
The word &quot;private&quot; is said to your face, sir.
Er sözü, er yüzüne söylenir beyim.
Well.
Peki.
You have my eyes and ears. Tell me.
Gözüm de kulağım da sende.
Söyle bakalım.
You have my eyes and ears. Tell me.
Suleyman Shah, the chief of the Kayı neck. I came as an ambassador.
Kayı Boyunun Beyi Süleyman Şah'ın
elçisi olarak geldim.
Suleyman Shah, the chief of the Kayı neck. I came as an ambassador.
My son, my name is Ertugrul.
Oğluyum. Adım da Ertuğrul.
Eye ?.
What do you want, gentleman? I came to buy you a dorm.
-Ne istersin bey oğlu?
-Sizden yurt almaya geldim.
What do you want, gentleman? I came to buy you a dorm.
You want a dorm.
Yurt istersin.
So what do you give in return?
Peki karşılığında ne vereceksin?
One of your goats that will harm our crops. And your scent will come to our city.
Ekinlerimize zarar verecek keçilerinizden
ve şehrimize sinecek kokunuzdan başka?
One of your goats that will harm our crops. And your scent will come to our city.
The city made you forget the truth, sir?
Şehir sana aslını mı unutturdu beyim?
How did you know that I was a Turkmen?
Nasıl anladın benim de Türkmen olduğumu?
The dhikr on your finger.
Parmağındaki zikir.
Obviously, you're not wearing it for trappings. he's giving himself away.
Ziynet eşyası olarak takmadığın belli,
kendini ele veriyor.
Obviously, you're not wearing it for trappings. he's giving himself away.
Tired of shooting arrows at the voyage.
Kefereye ok atmaktan yıpranmış.
If you give us a dorm.
Eğer bize yurt verirsen
in exchange for two thousand Alpine.
karşılığında iki bin tane Alp
Your head will be there every time a tare falls.
başın her dara düştüğünde yanında olacak.
Two thousand alpine huh?
İki bin Alp ha?
My palace. even more than that.
Benim sarayımın
muhafızlarının sayısı bile bundan fazla.
My palace. even more than that.
Keep it clear, gentlemen.
Yolun açık olsun bey oğlu.
Next.
Sıradaki.
Lord.
Beyim.
Next.
Sıradaki.
Lord.
Beyim.
Let's.
Hadi!
Your guards, count three missing.
Muhafızların, üç eksik say!
Congratulations.
Tebrik ederim.
It was the most beautiful contact I've ever seen.
Hayatımda gördüğüm en güzel temaşaydı.
Isn't that right, Nasir? Give it up for you.
Öyle değil mi Nasır? Sen de alkışla.
Your Holiness.
Emir Hazretleri.
This is a valiant of Turkmen. I would love to get to know you better.
Bu Türkmen yiğidi
yakından tanımak isterim.
This is a valiant of Turkmen. I would love to get to know you better.
The nomads at dinner tonight. Stories of hankering life.
Bu akşamki yemekte göçerlerin
çileli hayat hikayelerini
The nomads at dinner tonight. Stories of hankering life.
heroic epics, its. Let's listen to your mouth, my uncle.
kahramanlık destanlarını, onun
ağzından dinleyelim sevgili dayıcığım.
heroic epics, its. Let's listen to your mouth, my uncle.
I am honored, Your Holiness.
Şeref duyarım Emir Hazretleri.
. He sent the bodies of my men.
Adamlarımın cesetlerini yollamış.
. In his mind, he intimidates me.
Aklınca bana gözdağı veriyor.
You and your soldiers. Pray that you have not crushed.
Seni ve askerlerini
ezip geçmediğine dua et.
You and your soldiers. Pray that you have not crushed.
I do not understand. Is the brain defying the Seljuk State?
Anlamadım.
Beyin Selçuklu Devletine kafa mı tutuyor?
I do not understand. Is the brain defying the Seljuk State?
Stop reading shit, Kara Lark.
Maval okumayı bırak Kara Toygar.
Don't excuse the Seljuk State.
Selçuklu Devletini de bahane etme.
Sultan Alaeddin. he doesn't know what he's doing.
Sultan Alaeddin'in
bu yaptıklarından haberi yok.
Sultan Alaeddin. he doesn't know what he's doing.
I know it's my name.
Bunu adım gibi biliyorum.
I understand these prisoners. it will open other doors for you in the state.
Anladığım kadarıyla bu esirler
sana devlette başka kapılar açacak.
I understand these prisoners. it will open other doors for you in the state.
Reflect your intelligence to your own work. That would be nice.
Zekânı kendi yaptığın işlere yansıtsan
güzel olur ha.
Reflect your intelligence to your own work. That would be nice.
This is intelligence. Kurdoğlu says for your incompetence ?.
Bu zekân,
beceriksizliğin için ne diyor Kurdoğlu?
This is intelligence. Kurdoğlu says for your incompetence ?.
You first. see the incompetence of your own men.
Sen önce
kendi adamlarının beceriksizliğini gör.
You first. see the incompetence of your own men.
They're even incapable of ambushing.
Pusu atmaktan bile acizler.
Eee Extension Kurdoğlu.
Eee! Uzatma Kurdoğlu!
Unless you bring me Numan. You can't get the principality you want.
Numan'ı bana getirmezsen
istediğin beyliği alamazsın.
Unless you bring me Numan. You can't get the principality you want.
I'il wash down the sky dome.
Gök kubbeyi başınıza yıkarım.
You and Suleiman Shah will remain under you.
Sen de Süleyman Şah da altında kalır.
If you can be patient. we both get what we want.
Sabırlı olursan,
ikimiz de istediğimizi alırız.
If you can be patient. we both get what we want.
But if you chew me.
Ama beni çiğnersen
we both lose.
ikimiz de kaybederiz.
The whole world for your number. I confront me.
Numan için bütün dünyayı
karşıma alırım.
The whole world for your number. I confront me.
Don't forget my promise.
Sen de bu sözümü unutma.
Still tell me who those prisoners are. You won't tell me?
Hâlâ bana o esirlerin kim olduklarını
söylemeyecek misin?
Still tell me who those prisoners are. You won't tell me?
Think of who I am, not them.
Onların değil, benim kim olduğumu düşün.
This is more important to you, Kurdoğlu.
Bu senin için daha önemli Kurdoğlu.
What will we do now?.
Şimdi ne yapacağız?
I'il give you Numan. I will also give Suleiman Shah.
Sana Numan'ı da,
Süleyman Şah'ı da vereceğim.
I'il give you Numan. I will also give Suleiman Shah.
You're gonna pick it up like a palm on your branch.
Dalındaki bir hurma gibi gidip alacaksın.
Now listen to me.
Şimdi beni iyi dinle.
When the caravan is pressed . Suleyman Shah cannot sit in his tent .
Kervan basıldığında
Süleyman Şah otağında oturamaz
When the caravan is pressed . Suleyman Shah cannot sit in his tent .
He will come after you .
senin peşine düşecektir.
Fourteen rugs.
On dört tane kilim.
Two dozen wooden spoons.
İki düzine tahta kaşık.
Seventytwo pieces.
Yetmiş iki parça yemeni.
Mashallah, mashallah.
Hay maşallah, hay maşallah.
Your bride and girl worked well.
Senin gelinle kız iyi çalışmışlar.
Auntie, look if you tied them up.
Teyzeciğim, bak iyi bağlasaydınız onları.
Then they're on their way.
Sonra başımıza bela olmasınlar yolda.
I'm Sardık Gündoğdu. We wrapped them tightly with my network.
Sardık Gündoğdu Bey'im,
ağamla sıkı sıkı sardık hepsini.
I'm Sardık Gündoğdu. We wrapped them tightly with my network.
We don't have much. but let me be a sacrifice.
Bizim çok bir şeyimiz yok
ama kurban olayım kervana mukayyet olun.
We don't have much. but let me be a sacrifice.
My animals are starving.
Hayvanlarım açlıktan telef oldu.
What we have, what we don't have to trust you.
Neyimiz var, neyimiz yok size emanet ağam.
I don't know or suck, don't I? Do not worry.
Bilmez miyim emmi, bilmez miyim?
Sen hiç merak etme.
I don't know or suck, don't I? Do not worry.
The goods are first entrusted to God, then to us.
Malların önce Allah'a, sonra bize emanet.
. Look, I picked my best Alps for this.
Bak bu iş için en iyi Alplerimi seçtim ben
keep the eye behind. Keep your eyes on the people.
gözün arkada kalmasın.
Gözünüz arkada kalmasın ahali.
keep the eye behind. Keep your eyes on the people.
Okay, come on.
Tamam, hadi.
Okay, sir, okay, sir.
Oldu beyim, oldu beyim.
Gundogdu.
With these blades I made. I will marry my daughter, according to her.
yaptığım bu bıçakların akçesiyle
kızımı evlendireceğim, ona göre.
With these blades I made. I will marry my daughter, according to her.
You can't get rid of Aykız's tongue.
Aykız'ın dilinden kurtulamazsın.
And Turgut.
Turgut'un da.
Now in Aleppo. what strangers must be.
Şimdi Halep'te
ne sıkıntı çekiyordur gariplerim.
Now in Aleppo. what strangers must be.
I hope the God helps them.
Allah yardımcıları olsun.
You too.
Senin de.
Next.
Sıradaki.
Don't come at me. I'il crush you like a millstone.
Üstüme gelmeyin.
Değirmen taşı gibi ezerim sizi!
Don't come at me. I'il crush you like a millstone.
I say no.
Yapmayın diyorum.
Whenever my meat touches me. Something comes.
Ya ne zaman etime su değse başıma
bir şey geliyor.
Whenever my meat touches me. Something comes.
Look, she's with me. you burn too.
Bak benimle beraber
siz de yanarsınız ha.
Look, she's with me. you burn too.
Baby, there's a feast at the palace.
Yavrum, sarayda ziyafet var.
Are you gonna eat with us? Decide whether you'll eat in the barn.
Sen bizimle mi yiyeceksin,
ahırda mı yiyeceksin, ona karar ver.
Are you gonna eat with us? Decide whether you'll eat in the barn.
Look, I don't make it right. Do not say.
Yapmayın! Bak hakkımı helal etmem,
yapmayın diyorum.
Look, I don't make it right. Do not say.
Basically, you have no salvation, you will be washed. Surrender.
Bamsı, kurtuluşun yok, yıkanacaksın.
Teslim ol.
Basically, you have no salvation, you will be washed. Surrender.
I'm not a wife. I don't, I don't die.
Olmam karındaş ya,
olmam, ölürüm de olmam!
I'm not a wife. I don't, I don't die.
Fucking skunk. come
Ulan kokarca, amma naz yaptın be,
gel ulan!
Fucking skunk. come
Don't do this to me, God.
Bana bunu yapmayın! Allah!
Oh, God.
Ah! Allah!
. We'il be late for the palace.
Oyalanmayın. Saraya geç kalacağız.
You heard our master.
Beyimizi duydunuz
Hold your hand quickly.
elinizi çabuk tutun.
Lord.
Beyim
What do you still think ?.
hâlâ ne düşünürsün?
To be entertained in Emir's palace. not a little thing for us.
Emir'in sarayında ağırlanmak
az bir şey değil bizim için.
To be entertained in Emir's palace. not a little thing for us.
What dorm gave us. nor did they promise, Elijah.
Bize ne yurt verdiler
ne de sözünü verdiler İlyas.
What dorm gave us. nor did they promise, Elijah.
Come on, good. Amen, sir.
-Hadi hayırlısı bakalım.
-Amin beyim.
Come on, good. Amen, sir.
The night must end.
Gece bu iş bitmeli.
The men you send. Will they do this?
Göndereceğin adamlar
bu işi becerebilecekler mi?
The men you send. Will they do this?
You do your part, Nasser.
Sen üzerine düşeni yap Nasır.
Which one of you got my pusats?
Ulan hanginiz aldı pusatlarımı?
What are you talking about,. Aren't we in the hammam together?
Ne diyorsun sen,
beraber girmedik mi hamama?
What are you talking about,. Aren't we in the hammam together?
So don't you see, there's no. How does it not ?.
-Ee yok görmüyor musun, yok işte da.
-Nasıl yok?
So don't you see, there's no. How does it not ?.
Neither do mine.
Benimkiler de yok.
They stole my compasses too.
Benim pusatları da çalmışlar.
Oh, I told you, every time I wash. I said a bad luck comes.
Aa! Size söylemiştim, ne zaman yıkansam
bir uğursuzluk gelir demiştim.
Oh, I told you, every time I wash. I said a bad luck comes.
Here you go.
Alın işte gördünüz.
Camel, we'il get you in the water. We've been inconsiderate.
Deve, seni suya sokacağız diye
tedbirsizlik ettik.
Camel, we'il get you in the water. We've been inconsiderate.
Just stop yelling.
Bağırmayı kesin yeter!
How to account for this. We will now.
Bunun hesabını beyimize nasıl
vereceğiz şimdi?
How to account for this. We will now.
What account Turgut?
Neyin hesabını Turgut?
I said, Turgut.
Sana dedim Turgut.
Sir, they stole our prams.
Beyim, pusatlarımızı çalmışlar.
What?.
Ne?
Here, sit down.
Buyurun, oturun.
Here you go, Alps.
Siz de buyurun Alpler.
Have you lost any of the fighting? No, Your Holiness.
-Çatışmada bir kaybınız oldu mu?
-Hayır Emir Hazretleri.
Have you lost any of the fighting? No, Your Holiness.
Say.
Demek
in my land. You were attacked?
benim topraklarımda
saldırıya uğradınız öyle mi?
in my land. You were attacked?
To send soldiers there and nest. We won't let you, uncle ?.
Oraya asker yollayıp yuvalanmalarına
izin vermeyeceğiz değil mi dayı?
To send soldiers there and nest. We won't let you, uncle ?.
Of course, Your Holiness. Well, uncle, well.
-Elbette Emir Hazretleri.
-Peki dayı, peki.
Of course, Your Holiness. Well, uncle, well.
They got the punishment too much. They all died.
Gereken cezayı fazlasıyla aldılar,
hepsi öldü.
They got the punishment too much. They all died.
Drought. I know how you hit the nomads.
Kuraklığın
göçerleri nasıl vurduğunu biliyorum.
Drought. I know how you hit the nomads.
Sultan Alaeddin to you. show more than tolerate.
Sultan Alaeddin size
fazlasıyla tahammül gösteriyor.
Sultan Alaeddin to you. show more than tolerate.
The villages of your herds. how he destroyed the towns.
Sürülerinizin köyleri,
kasabaları nasıl yok ettiği ortada.
The villages of your herds. how he destroyed the towns.
E Oghuz tribes among themselves. conflicts are an issue in itself.
E Oğuz Boylarının kendi aralarındaki
çatışmaları da başlı başına bir mesele.
E Oghuz tribes among themselves. conflicts are an issue in itself.
Everybody's after the flock, after the flock.
Herkes sürüsünün peşinde, aş peşinde.
Drought hit badly.
Kuraklık obaları kötü vurdu.
But a few stray precedents do not.
Ama birkaç başıbozuk emsal teşkil etmez.
Play something more alive.
Daha canlı bir şeyler çalın.
. Mongols on the one hand, Crusaders on the other.
Bir yandan Moğollar, bir yandan Haçlılar
With Harezmshah. Not to mention the Seljuks.
Harezmşahlarla
Selçukluları saymıyorum bile.
With Harezmshah. Not to mention the Seljuks.
This fire is not fueled by hand.
Bu yangına elinde körükle değil
we need an ally to run with a bowl of water.
bir tas suyla koşacak müttefik lazım bize.
Among the Muslims. while the fire of sedition burns all over.
Müslümanların arasındaki
fitne ateşi her yeri yakıp yıkarken
Among the Muslims. while the fire of sedition burns all over.
That's what we need. Right, Your Holiness?
ihtiyacımız olan bu.
Öyle değil mi Emir Hazretleri?
That's what we need. Right, Your Holiness?
That's uncle.
Öyle dayı.
We need to put out the fire.
Yangını söndürmemiz lazım, öyle.
Our swords do not scold.
Kılıçlarımız kınına girmez
our horses do not stand back from the jungle.
atlarımız cenkten geri durmaz.
He's gonna put us out in the house. I need an ally that comes with a bowl of water.
Bize de evdeki yangını söndürecek
bir tas suyla gelen müttefik lazım.
He's gonna put us out in the house. I need an ally that comes with a bowl of water.
How will we deal with you Turkmen?
Sizle nasıl anlaşacağız Türkmen?
We want a fertile winter for our oba.
Obamız için bereketli bir kışlak isteriz.
Overwintering ?.
Kışlak?
First you want overwinter ,. Then it becomes highland.
Önce kışlak istersiniz,
sonra olur o yaylak
First you want overwinter ,. Then it becomes highland.
then you want a dorm.
sonra bir de yurt istersiniz siz.
True.
Doğru.
We want.
İsteriz.
What if I gave you Aleppo?
Ben size peki Halep'i versem?
Are you satisfied with Ertuğrul ?.
Gözünüz doyar mı Ertuğrul?
It opens up to us. rather than breaking an order.
Bize toprağını açan
bir emiri kırmaktansa
It opens up to us. rather than breaking an order.
we break all the herd we have.
sahip olduğumuz bütün sürüyü kırarız.
But I have concerns, Ertugrul.
Ama benim kaygılarım var Ertuğrul.
I'm here to address your concerns.
Kaygılarınızı gidermek için buradayım.
What the apostles brought. Thank you for the gifts.
Kayı elçilerinin getirdikleri
hediyeler için teşekkür ederiz.
What the apostles brought. Thank you for the gifts.
If you accept us, too. we have gifts for you.
Kabul ederseniz bizim de
size hediyelerimiz var.
If you accept us, too. we have gifts for you.
These are our prams.
Bunlar bizim pusatlar.
Now tell me Ertuğrul.
Şimdi söyle Ertuğrul.
Even in peace with your weapons. valiant
Silahlarına barışta bile
sahip çıkamayan yiğitlerin
Even in peace with your weapons. valiant
How reliable?
sözlerine ne kadar güvenilir?
Why are you there, Nasir?
Sen niye oradasın Nasır?
Look how beautiful we are here. Have fun, come to me.
Bak biz burada ne kadar güzel
eğleniyoruz, gelsene yanıma.
Look how beautiful we are here. Have fun, come to me.
You can go now.
Şimdi gidebilirsiniz.
Rest, you've come a long way.
Dinlenin, uzun yoldan geldiniz.
Consult my commanders tomorrow morning. I will tell you my decision.
Yarın sabah komutanlarımla istişare edip
kararımı bildiririm size.
Consult my commanders tomorrow morning. I will tell you my decision.
From now on. sword
Ant olsun ki bundan sonra
kılıcına sahip çıkamayan ele
From now on. sword
pusat no profit.
pusat yâr olmasın!
Our compasses went up and down the sky.
Pusatlarımız gök girip kızıl çıkaydı da
Our Ertuğrul Bey had not experienced this shame.
Ertuğrul Bey'imiz bu utancı yaşamayaydı.
Mr. Ertugrul. Now who knows what it is.
Ertuğrul Bey'imiz
şimdi kim bilir ne hâldedir
Mr. Ertugrul. Now who knows what it is.
mad.
öfkeden delirmiştir.
I Esselamunaleyk.
Esselamunaleyküm.
And alikumselam. and Mercy of Allah and Berekatühü.
Ve aleykümselam
ve Rahmetullahi ve Berekatühü!
And alikumselam. and Mercy of Allah and Berekatühü.
Salâmeti Hâzirûn, Salâmeti Gâiubûn.
Selâmet-i Hâzirûn, Selâmet-i Gâiubûn
vuslat
âşıklara vuslat
A secret from the Prophet Almighty. Abdulkadir El Geylani al Fatiha.
bir sır Cenab-ı Hazreti
Abdulkadir El Geylani el Fatiha!
A secret from the Prophet Almighty. Abdulkadir El Geylani al Fatiha.
God, salli.
Allahümme salli âlâ
Sayyidina Muhammad.
seyyidina Muhammed!
Oh, God.
Allah! Hay!
Oh, God .
And God .
Oh, God, God .
Allah! Allah! Ya Allah!
Gee.
Allah! Allah!
God ,. you do not load on your servant can not carry.
Allah'ım,
sen kuluna taşıyamayacağı yük yüklemezsin.
God ,. you do not load on your servant can not carry.
You put the load of the whole oba on my shoulder.
Bütün obanın yükünü omzuma koydun.
How to handle this burden. or my Lord.
Bana bu yükün altından kalkmayı
nasip eyle ya Rabb'im.
How to handle this burden. or my Lord.
.
You take Yusuf out of the well. You are the Sultan of Egypt.
Sen ki Yusuf'u kuyudan çıkartıp
Mısır'a sultan yapansın
You take Yusuf out of the well. You are the Sultan of Egypt.
This is to get out of the bottomless well I fell.
bu düştüğüm dipsiz kuyudan çıkmak için
Give me a chance, my Lord.
bana bir imkan ver ya Rabb'im.
.
Medet, medet, medet .
Medet, medet, medet
Mededim medet .
.
Medet, medet, medet .
Medet, medet, medet
Mededim medet .
.
Wake up, kid .