. Take care of the spoils.
Ganimetlerle ilgilenin. Hadi.
What a pity.
Yazık. Çok yazık.
None of this. You don't deserve.
Bunların hiçbirini
hak etmedin Gündoğdu.
None of this. You don't deserve.
I told your father, &quot;If you don't give the captives.
Babana demiştim "Esirleri vermezsen
gök kubbeyi başına yıkarım." diye.
I told your father, &quot;If you don't give the captives.
Let him think now.
Şimdi düşünsün bakalım.
Will he choose his custom or his son?
Törelerini mi yoksa evladını mı seçecek?
. The whole oba is starving .
Bütün oba açlıktan kırılıyor.
Scarcity everywhere . We didn't even make a rush. .
Kıtlık her yerde.
Bir akına bile çıkamadık. Neden?
Scarcity everywhere . We didn't even make a rush. .
. Because our brain is in trouble with boils .
Çünkü beyimizin çıbanla başı dertte.
All oba people. complain about your old age.
Bütün oba halkı
senin yaşlılığından şikayetçi.
All oba people. complain about your old age.
I said, &quot;I'il be back before I get your face down.&quot;
Sana "Yüzünü kara çıkartmadan
döneceğim." dedim.
I said, &quot;I'il be back before I get your face down.&quot;
I'm back, Dad.
Döndüm baba.
My prayers were accepted.
Dualarım kabul oldu.
Thank goodness it was acceptable.
Çok şükür kabul oldu.
Now we have a barracks. But our work is not easy.
Artık bir kışlağımız var.
Lakin işimiz hiç kolay değil.
Now we have a barracks. But our work is not easy.
Kay doesn't aspire to the easy one, son.
Kayı kolay olana talip olmaz evlat.
Well, we'il get over every adversary.
Evelallah her müşkülün üstesinden geliriz.
We'il come.
Evelallah geliriz.
Welcome back, lion boy.
Hoş gelmişsin aslan oğlum.
You came with this good news. May my Lord make you happy in two worlds.
Bu müjdeyle geldin,
Rabb'im seni iki cihanda mutlu kılsın.
You came with this good news. May my Lord make you happy in two worlds.
Get your neck, get your clothes off.
Boyun boylansın, soyun soylansın.
Home.
Anam
honey
can anam
dear sacrifice mother.
canım feda anam.
May Allah not let you down.
Allah sizi başımızdan eksik etmesin.
God bless you.
Allah da seni korusun.
. Now get back to rest.
Hadi şimdi istirahate çekil.
You're joining Toya.
Toya katılacaksın.
All the gentlemen there.
Orada tüm Kayı beylerine
The one you brought from Aleppo. You will give the mush.
Halep'ten getirdiğin
muştuyu sen vereceksin.
The one you brought from Aleppo. You will give the mush.
Then the matter. we talk all along.
O zaman meseleyi
enine boyuna konuşuruz hep beraber.
Then the matter. we talk all along.
If I may. I have a job before I go to rest.
Müsaade varsa
istirahate çekilmeden önce bir işim var.
If I may. I have a job before I go to rest.
I'd like to handle it.
Halletmek isterim.
Numan.
God bless you.
Allah'ım sana şükürler olsun.
Just when our hope ends. You brought us Ertuğrul.
Tam umudumuzun bittiği anda
Ertuğrul'u çıkardın karşımıza.
Just when our hope ends. You brought us Ertuğrul.
You made him strong against the oppressors.
Onu zalimler karşısında güçlü kıldın.
Now with the good news. to return unharmed.
Şimdi de iyi haberlerle
sağ salim dönmeyi nasip et.
Now with the good news. to return unharmed.
Ertugrul.
I learned from Aykız that you are here.
Aykız'dan öğrendim burada olduğunu.
I wasn't afraid.
Korkmadım da
I'm surprised you've come.
şaşırdım. Tez geldin.
Didn't I tell you?
Sana söylemedim mi?
Didn't I say, &quot;I'm going to ride my horse.&quot;
"Atımı hiç durmadan süreceğim,
tez gidip, tez geleceğim." demedim mi?
Didn't I say, &quot;I'm going to ride my horse.&quot;
You said.
Dedin.
I kept my word.
Sözümü tuttum.
Did you bring good news from Aleppo?
Halep'ten güzel haberler getirdin mi?
Is there a new home?
Yeni bir yurt var mı gidecek?
Yeah.
Evet.
Thank goodness.
Şükürler olsun.
The people of Oba will finally take a sigh of relief.
Oba halkı sonunda rahat bir nefes alacak.
Everyone watched your way.
Herkes yolunuzu gözledi.
Mostly Aykız.
En çok da Aykız.
Mostly Aykız ?.
En çok da Aykız mı?
So.
Yani
Mom, Dad.
anne, baban
babies chilling in the cold of the plateau.
yaylanın soğuğunda üşüyen bebeler
everyone.
herkes.
We all.
Hepimiz.
I never took it from me.
Hiç yanımdan ayırmadım.
. It gave me strength in every challenge I've encountered.
Karşılaştığım her zorlukta bana güç verdi.
Every time I fall into tare, you too. He reminded me that he is with me.
Ne zaman dara düşsem, senin de
benim yanımda olduğunu hatırlattı bana.
Every time I fall into tare, you too. He reminded me that he is with me.
I bought it for you from Aleppo.
Halep'ten senin için aldım bunu.
For me?.
Benim için mi?
This is very nice Ertuğrul Bey.
Bu çok güzel Ertuğrul Bey.
The beauty I've seen. I wanted you to see it.
Gördüğüm güzelliği
senin de görmeni istedim.
The beauty I've seen. I wanted you to see it.
Everything is like a dream.
Her şey bir rüya gibi.
. But like any dream, it has an end.
Ama her rüya gibi bunun da bir sonu var.
What happened, Halime? What's bothering you?
Ne oldu Halime? Canını sıkan ne?
Kara Lark.
Kara Toygar.
He hit the obo and tried to kidnap us.
Obayı basıp bizi kaçırmaya kalktı.
He's after us. will never leave Ertugrul.
O bizim peşimizi
asla bırakmayacak Ertuğrul.
He's after us. will never leave Ertugrul.
Keep your heart fresh.
Gönlünü ferah tut.
And an oath.
And olsun ki
I will never leave you.
ben de sizi asla bırakmayacağım.
.
It's my father's death anniversary.
Babamın bugün ölüm yıldönümü.
It's been eight years.
Tam sekiz yıl oldu.
I wish I could cry.
Keşke ağlayabileceğim
If I had a grave I could pray for.
dua edebileceğim bir mezarı olsaydı.
Not for your father's dead.
Babanın ölüsü için değil
You must pray for her to live.
yaşaması için dua etmelisin.
Your father's body. nobody has ever seen.
Babanın cesedini
bugüne kadar kimse görmedi.
Your father's body. nobody has ever seen.
Who knows, maybe he's alive.
Kim bilir, belki de hayattadır.
He'il meet his beloved daughter one day. his dream is keeping him alive.
Sevgili kızıyla bir gün karşılaşacağı
hayali, onu hayatta tutuyordur.
He'il meet his beloved daughter one day. his dream is keeping him alive.
When did he meet this ominous?
Ne vakit geldi de bu uğursuzla buluştu?
Easy, babes.
Kolay gelsin hatunlar.
As soon as our Ertuğrul Bey arrives. This girl has taken her breath.
Ertuğrul Bey'imiz gelir gelmez
bu kızın yanında almış soluğu ana.
As soon as our Ertuğrul Bey arrives. This girl has taken her breath.
Where do they come from? How do they walk side by side ?.
Böyle nereden gelirler?
Yan yana nasıl yürürler?
Where do they come from? How do they walk side by side ?.
Without knowing the truth of a business. stinging
Bir işin aslını bilip bilmeden
içine fesatlık sokma Selcan.
Without knowing the truth of a business. stinging
This situation is of no use to anyone.
Bu hallerinin kimseye faydası yok.
Ertuğrul, when he arrives. First he kissed our hand.
Ertuğrul, geldiğinde
ilk önce bizim elimizi öptü.
Ertuğrul, when he arrives. First he kissed our hand.
I swear, this is the subject of hospitality. We need to get this done quickly, Ana.
Vallahi bu misafirlik konusunu
bir an önce halletmemiz lazım ana.
I swear, this is the subject of hospitality. We need to get this done quickly, Ana.
My father does not know, does not see what happened.
Bey babam bu olanları bilmiyor, görmüyor.
This girl means our hearth.
Bu kızın ocağımıza kastı var.
Let your language work.
Diliniz işleyeceğine eliniz işlesin.
There's as much work as the world.
Dünya kadar iş var.
What did Solomon Shah say, sir?
Süleyman Şah ne dedi beyim?
Ertugrul, returned from Aleppo.
Ertuğrul, Halep'ten dönmüş.
He bought the dormitory from El Aziz.
El Aziz'den yurdu almış.
Ertuğrul came out of our chest.
Ertuğrul sandığımızdan yaman çıktı.
You are in Kurdoğlu Bey. Do you think the game will run out ?.
Sen Kurdoğlu Beyi'nde
oyun tükenir mi sanırsın?
You are in Kurdoğlu Bey. Do you think the game will run out ?.
Of course we have an account.
Elbet bizim de bir hesabımız var.
Crazy Iron.
Deli Demir
sword
keferenin kılıcı seninkinden hallice.
Well get my son. Where did you get this donkey bat?
De get oğlum.
Nereden buldun bu eşek sopasını?
Well get my son. Where did you get this donkey bat?
The Crusaders we killed.
Geberttiğimiz Haçlılardan.
What does Haa Gavur know about the compass? Look.
Haa. Gavur pusattan ne anlar? Bak.
That's what you call a pusat.
Pusat dediğin aha böyle
It will curve like elif.
elif gibi eğri olacak.
It will sit on Yigit's wrist. It will be steel.
Yiğit'in bileğine oturacak.
Çeliğe baş olacak.
It will sit on Yigit's wrist. It will be steel.
Black Lark's men. Halime's tent is ridden Deli Demir.
Kara Toygar'ın adamları
Halime'nin çadırı basmış Deli Demir.
Black Lark's men. Halime's tent is ridden Deli Demir.
Is it correct?.
Doğru mu?
Right, Ertugrul.
Doğru Ertuğrul.
Push, pushed.
İt, itliğini yaptı ama
He also took the measure of his height.
boyunun ölçüsünü de aldı.
I tell you that tent. I've entrusted it for the sake of honor.
Ben sana o çadırı
namus bilesin diye emanet ettim.
I tell you that tent. I've entrusted it for the sake of honor.
How come our nose? come to the bottom and press the tent ?.
Nasıl olur da burnumuzun
dibine kadar gelip çadır basarlar?
How come our nose? come to the bottom and press the tent ?.
You're right, Ertugrul.
Haklısın Ertuğrul.
My neck is thinner than hair.
Boynum kıldan ince.
It's a moment of blunder.
Bir anlık gaflet.
Take the dagger.
Al hançeri vur.
Repentance is not my blood.
Tövbe kanım akmaz.
Thank you, Master Iron.
Yine de sağ olasın Demir Usta.
Thanks to you. life saved.
Senin sayende
hayatı kurtulmuş biçarelerin.
Thanks to you. life saved.
No, no, not just me.
Yok, yok. Sadece ben değil.
And Afşin.
Bir de Afşin.
. He was the merchant's man who came to obaya.
Obaya gelen tüccarın adamıymış.
But you know, Ertugrul. There is a no in everything.
Ama biliyor musun Ertuğrul,
her şeyde bir hayır var.
But you know, Ertugrul. There is a no in everything.
If he pushes the rabbit, go to obaya.
Eğer o itler iyice kudurup, obaya gelip
Had they not attacked the Halimas.
Halimelere saldırmasalardı
Halimeler that night.
o gece Halimeler
few or something.
kaçacaklarmış.
Or outside the oba.
Ya obanın dışında
If they had worked well elsewhere. none of us would have known.
başka bir yerde iyice çullansalardı,
hiçbirimizin haberi olmazdı.
If they had worked well elsewhere. none of us would have known.
Hali studies.
Halimeler
So they were going to run away ?.
kaçacaklardı yani?
Did that asshole go down?
O kadar iti Afşin mi tepeledi?
Look at the caravan footer.
Kervanın ayakçısına bak.
Halime.
As soon as my Ertuğrul Bey came, he asked about you.
Ertuğrul Bey'im gelir gelmez seni sordu.
He had a way of going after you.
Öyle bir gidişi vardı ki arkandan!
We will meet with Turgut in a moment.
Biz de birazdan buluşacağız Turgut'umla.
When he's away, my heart is always pure.
O uzaklardayken yüreğim hep pır pır.
Thank goodness they returned. With good news.
Çok şükür döndüler ya sağ salim.
Hem de güzel haberlerle.
Thank goodness they returned. With good news.
End of patience is salute Aykız.
Sabrın sonu selamettir Aykız.
Our wedding is close.
Düğünümüz yakındır artık.
The excitement of the moon. my hand, my foot cut ice.
Ay heyecandan
elim ayağım buz kesti baksana.
The excitement of the moon. my hand, my foot cut ice.
My Ertuğrul Bey took this?
Ertuğrul Bey'im mi almış bunu?
That's pretty good.
Pek de güzelmiş.
So there. She kept thinking about you.
Demek oralarda da
seni düşünüp dururmuş Halime.
So there. She kept thinking about you.
What if he thought about Aykız ?.
Düşünse ne olur Aykız?
Why do you say that, beautiful Halime?
Neden böyle dersin, güzel Halime?
You're obviously out of it.
Keyfin yok belli ki.
Is something hurting you?
Canını yakan bir şey mi var?
So we don't get hurt.
Canımız yanmasın diye
I had to run away my whole life.
ömrüm boyunca kaçmak zorunda kaldım.
You have to go for the first time. it hurts to be.
İlk defa gitmek zorunda
olduğum için canım acıyor.
You have to go for the first time. it hurts to be.
Who you're running from.
Kimden kaçtığınızı
I don't know why you're running away.
neden kaçtığınızı bilmiyorum.
Actually.
Doğrusu
No wonder at all.
hiç de merak etmiyorum.
But I know this, Halime.
Ama şunu biliyorum Halime
You are not alone anymore.
artık yalnız değilsiniz.
My Ertugrul will let you go.
Ertuğrul Bey'im ne gitmene izin verir
nor do you happen to have a job.
ne de başınıza bir iş gelmesine.
Elenore.
You're grieving.
Kederlisin.
Your grief has made even my pigeons uneasy.
Kederin güvercinlerimi bile huzursuz etti.
I'm in the land where my father died.
Babamın öldüğü topraklardayım.
I want to pray in your grave.
Mezarında dua etmek istiyorum.
Knight Giovanni.
Şövalye Giovanni
the wisest I've ever met.
tanıdığım en bilge
He was the bravest knight.
en cesur şövalyeydi.
Before the Turks killed my father.
Türkler babamı öldürmeden önce
You were the last one to see him, Mario.
onu en son gören sendin Mario.
They pulled miles in my eyes and left them to my fate.
Gözlerime mil çekip kaderime terk ettiler.
My eyes are as blind as a bottomless pit. The last thing he saw was your father.
Dipsiz bir kuyu kadar kör olan gözlerimin
gördüğü son şey baban oldu.
My eyes are as blind as a bottomless pit. The last thing he saw was your father.
What if my father didn't?
Babam ya ölmediyse?
With blood running through my eyes.
Gözlerimden kan akarken
I dig with my nails. I buried your father in the ground.
tırnaklarımla kazdığım
toprağa gömdüm babanı.
I dig with my nails. I buried your father in the ground.
When your eyes are blind. You say you buried my father.
Gözlerin körken
gömdüğünü söylüyorsun babamı.
When your eyes are blind. You say you buried my father.
The one you thought you buried. Not my father, but someone else?
Ya gömdüğünü zannettiğin kişi
babam değil de bir başkasıysa?
The one you thought you buried. Not my father, but someone else?
The master I served for years. How do I not know Elenora ?.
Senelerce hizmet ettiğim efendimi
nasıl tanımam Elenora?
The master I served for years. How do I not know Elenora ?.
I have to go.
Gitmem gerekiyor.
Excuse me, girl.
Müsaadenle kızım.
Farewell, Elenora.
Elveda Elenora.
I can't go back until I finish. I'm going on a mission.
Bitirmeden dönemeyeceğim
bir göreve gidiyorum.
I can't go back until I finish. I'm going on a mission.
I wanted to say goodbye to you.
Sana veda etmek istedim.
I'il pray for you to come back.
Dönmen için dua edeceğim.
Titus.
This letter to my sister Izadora. I want you to send.
Bu mektubu kız kardeşim Izadora'ya
göndermeni istiyorum.
This letter to my sister Izadora. I want you to send.
It's about his father's death. Sir, they have doubts.
Babasının ölümüyle ilgili
şüpheleri var Efendim.
It's about his father's death. Sir, they have doubts.
With questionable questions. trying to catch a gap.
Kuşku dolu sorularıyla
bir açığımı yakalamaya çalışıyor.
With questionable questions. trying to catch a gap.
Every step Elenora takes. I must know, Mario.
Elenora'nın attığı her adımdan
haberim olmalı Mario.
Every step Elenora takes. I must know, Mario.
Gokce.
Hayme Ana. &quot;Ertuğrul'da heart, ask,&quot; he said.
Hayme Ana
"Ertuğrul'da gönlü var mı, sor." dedi.
Hayme Ana. &quot;Ertuğrul'da heart, ask,&quot; he said.
And you, too.
Sen de akıllan artık.
Such corners to the shores. Stop eating yourself.
Böyle kıyılara köşelere gizlenip
kendini yemekten vazgeç.
Such corners to the shores. Stop eating yourself.
When I saw them so together.
Ben onları öyle birlikte görünce...
So he asked if I had a heart.
Demek gönlüm var mı diye sordu.
This is over now.
Bu iş bitti artık.
Will not escape.
Kaçmayacaksın.
Because it always is. You will be more visible to Ertugrul's eye.
Her zaman olduğundan
daha görünür olacaksın Ertuğrul'un gözüne.
Because it always is. You will be more visible to Ertugrul's eye.
Sister.
Abla
Ertuğrul's heart is in Halime.
Ertuğrul'un gönlü Halime'de.
You'il see it, you know.
Sen de görürsün, bilirsin.
His mother asked about me.
Anası beni sormuş ama
I know.
ben bilirim
his son doesn't want me.
oğlu istemez beni.
My beautiful sister, my pure sister.
Benim güzel bacım, saf bacım.
Who asked Ertuğrul?
Ertuğrul'a soran kim?
After Suleyman Shah said, &quot;I will marry you to Gokce.&quot;
Süleyman Şah "Seni Gökçe'yle
evlendireceğim." dedikten sonra
After Suleyman Shah said, &quot;I will marry you to Gokce.&quot;
Do you think Ertuğrul can object?
Ertuğrul itiraz edebilir mi sanıyorsun?
He can't, can he? Of course not.
-Edemez, değil mi?
- Edemez tabii.
He can't, can he? Of course not.
Suleyman Shah's word of marriage. Once he's out, you're done.
Süleyman Şah'ın ağzından evlilik lafı
bir kere çıktı mı, bu işi bitmiş bil.
Suleyman Shah's word of marriage. Once he's out, you're done.
And you're Ertugrul until today. Dad, have you ever seen him go away?
Hem sen Ertuğrul'un bugüne kadar
baba sözünden çıktığını gördün mü hiç?
And you're Ertugrul until today. Dad, have you ever seen him go away?
Gokce girl is near the wedding. Stop worrying like that.
Düğünün yakındır Gökçe kız.
Böyle dertlenmeyi bırak.
Gokce girl is near the wedding. Stop worrying like that.
May our Gundogdu return. Ertuğrul'la and you.
Gündoğdu Bey'imiz de dönsün hele,
Ertuğrul'la sizi sözleriz.
May our Gundogdu return. Ertuğrul'la and you.
Excuse me, Aunt?
Müsaade var mı yenge?
Yes, sir.
Buyur Beyim.
Welcome back. We found it nice.
-Hoş gelmişsin.
-Hoş bulduk.
Welcome back. We found it nice.
I just wanted to ask you for your memory. I hope you're okay.
Bir hâlinizi hatırınızı sorayım dedim.
İyisinizdir inşallah.
I just wanted to ask you for your memory. I hope you're okay.
We saw you. We are better, Mr. Ertugrul.
Seni gördük
daha iyi olduk Ertuğrul Bey'im.
We saw you. We are better, Mr. Ertugrul.
You bought a dorm in Aleppo.
Halep'ten yurdu almışsın.
Thank goodness we got it.
Aldık çok şükür.
Let my brother return with the caravan.
Abim dönsün kervanla, göç ederiz artık.
Let him return safely.
Sağ salim dönsün de.
I hope he will.
Dönecek inşallah.
.
Well, sir, all oba wants a new homeland.
İyi de beyim, bütün oba yeni yurt ister.
Door in the dark winter. Where should we immigrate to Aleppo?
Kara kış kapıda.
Halep'e göçmeyelim de nereye göçelim?
Door in the dark winter. Where should we immigrate to Aleppo?
Is there any way you know?
Var mı bildiğin çıkar bir yol?
The sword player in the Mongolian army.
Moğolların ordusu içinde kılıç çalan
There are few Turkmen obas. You know Alpargu ?.
kaç Türkmen obası vardır
bilir misin sen Alpargu?
There are few Turkmen obas. You know Alpargu ?.
No, I don't know.
Yok, bilmem.
I know.
Ben bilirim işte!
Follow Ertuğrul's mind. instead of the snake hole we're stuck.
Ertuğrul'un aklına uyup
tıkılacağımız yılan deliği yerine
Follow Ertuğrul's mind. instead of the snake hole we're stuck.
turn back. We can deal with Mongolian commanders.
geriye dönüp
Moğol kumandanlarıyla anlaşabiliriz.
turn back. We can deal with Mongolian commanders.
The swordsmen of the Templars. cover our lives.
Tapınakçıların kılıçlarına
canımızı siper edip
The swordsmen of the Templars. cover our lives.
Aleppo's caretaker push the aprons?
Halep'in bekçi iti mi olsun Kayılar?
Or like dozens of them. big greek land.
Ya da onlarcasının yaptığı gibi
koca Rum ülkesini
Or like dozens of them. big greek land.
plural fill our saddle bag?
baştan sona çapul niyetine
heybemize mi dolduralım?
plural fill our saddle bag?
But, Master. Didn't the Mongols enter our blood many times?
Fakat Beyim,
Moğollar defalarca girmediler mi kanımıza?
But, Master. Didn't the Mongols enter our blood many times?
This time it'il be different.
Bu sefer farklı olacak işte.
And for the safety of this oba.
Hem bu obanın selameti için
We should even afford to keep a job with the devil.
şeytanla bile iş tutmayı göze almalıyız.
Remember everything is for our oba.
Unutma. Her şey obamız için.
Now go get this Baybora thing. Talk to buttermilk fool.
Şimdi gidip şu Baybora denen
ayran budalasıyla konuş.
Now go get this Baybora thing. Talk to buttermilk fool.
And yesterday's baby. disallow
Dünkü bebenin aklını çelmesine de
müsaade etme.
And yesterday's baby. disallow
I'm gonna shut up today. You will talk.
Bugün ben susacağım,
siz konuşacaksınız toyda.
I'm gonna shut up today. You will talk.
View Ertuğrul's Full Profile Describing his victory.
Ertuğrul ballandıra ballandıra
zaferini anlatırken
View Ertuğrul's Full Profile Describing his victory.
shake her nicely.
onu şöyle güzelce bir silkeleyin.
And oba gentlemen. we'il check his pulse.
Hem oba beylerinin de
nabzını yoklamış oluruz.
And oba gentlemen. we'il check his pulse.
Let's see you. how many people will rise.
Bakalım sizinle birlikte
kaç kişinin sesi yükselecek.
Let's see you. how many people will rise.
.
Wait.
Durun!
Black Lark wants to live.
Kara Toygar canlı ister.
.
We will burden you, Elijah Fakı.
Sana da yük olacağız İlyas Fakı.
Until we emigrated to our new oba. You will manage now.
Yeni obamıza göç edene kadar
idare edeceksin artık.
Until we emigrated to our new oba. You will manage now.
Oh, you've made it. We're gonna curl up and lie down.
Amma uzattınız ha.
Şuncacık yere kıvrılıp yatıvereceğiz.
Oh, you've made it. We're gonna curl up and lie down.
You've got room on my head, garrades.
Başımın üstünde yeriniz var gardaşlarım.
Turgut, Mr. Ertugrul. What's he gonna see me?
Turgut, Ertuğrul Bey'im
benimle ne görüşecekmiş?
Turgut, Mr. Ertugrul. What's he gonna see me?
I see you've spread.
Bakıyorum yayılmışsınız.
Don't overwhelm Elijah Faki. Be tidy.
Sakın ola İlyas Fakı'ı bunaltmayın.
Derli toplu olun biraz.
Don't overwhelm Elijah Faki. Be tidy.
You heard what happened when we were gone.
Biz yokken olanları duymuşsundur.
Thank you Mr. Turgut told us everything.
Eyvallah Beyim. Turgut anlattı her şeyi.
Obviously Black Toygar's. He has a man inside.
Belli ki Kara Toygar'ın
içeride bir adamı var.
Obviously Black Toygar's. He has a man inside.
He'il hit the obo while we're gone. gave him courage.
Biz yokken obayı basacak
cesareti vermiş ona.
He'il hit the obo while we're gone. gave him courage.
We need someone who won't draw attention.
Bize dikkat çekmeyecek biri lazım.
What do we stop for, sir?
Biz ne güne dururuz beyim?
You're so blessed. You gonna do this with your murderous face?
Sen şu cüssenle,
cani suratınla mı yapacaksın bu işi?
You're so blessed. You gonna do this with your murderous face?
Is there someone suspected by my master?
Beyimin şüphelendiği biri mi var?
There is.
Var.
Afshar's.
The merchant's man.
Tüccarın adamı.
After I saved the halim. oba
Halimeleri kurtardıktan sonra
obada kalmış.
After I saved the halim. oba
I want to know who it is and what it is.
Kimdir, neyin nesidir bilmek isterim.
Thank you, sir.
Eyvallah Beyim.
Don't you ever wonder. My breath will be on the back of the neck.
Siz hiç merak buyurmayın.
Nefesim ensesinde olacak.
Don't you ever wonder. My breath will be on the back of the neck.
I'm here to ask your permission, sir.
İzninizi istemeye geldim Efendim.
Time for duty, huh?
Görev vakti ha?
I'm gonna finish what I left.
Yarım bıraktığım işi tamamlayacağım.
I'il do this quietly.
Bu işi sessizce halledeceğim.
Like a coy baby. augment
İçinde nazlı bir bebek gibi
büyüt intikamını.
Like a coy baby. augment
But never their duties. don't let it out.
Ama asla görevlerinin
önüne geçmesine izin verme.
But never their duties. don't let it out.
Turks. prevent it from coming to our borders.
Türklerin
sınırlarımıza gelmesine engel ol.
Turks. prevent it from coming to our borders.
Kill me.
Ol deyince olduran
faithful
gönüllerimizi imanla dolduran
With ninetynine names of Allah Almighty.
Yüce Allah'ın doksan dokuz adıyla
ya bismillah.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim. Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
You have Ertuğrul.
Söz sende Ertuğrul.
Our new land is in the epic of our ancestors. they look like legendary lands.
Yeni yurdumuz atalarımızın destanlarında
anlattıkları efsanevi topraklara benziyor.
Our new land is in the epic of our ancestors. they look like legendary lands.
Sheltered like that.
Orası gibi korunaklı.
Four sides surrounded by mountains.
Dört tarafı dağ ile çevrili.
Local people. He even called it a sailor.
Çevre halkı
Yelkesen diye isim dahi takmış mevkiye.
Local people. He even called it a sailor.
Then squeeze the stone and the water will flow.
Sonra taşı sıksan su akar.
It's such a fertile place.
Öylesine bereketli ve mümbit bir yer.
Our foals will run freely.
Taylarımızın özgürce koşacağı,
of animals broken from the frost in winter. a world paradise.
kışın ayazından kırılan hayvanlarımızın
semireceği bir dünya cenneti.
of animals broken from the frost in winter. a world paradise.
God bless you. God bless you.
-Allah senden razı olsun.
Thank you, thank you.
Var olasın, sağ olasın.
Just because we bought the dorm. Of course not everything roses.
Yurdu aldık diye
her şey güllük gülistanlık değil elbet.
Just because we bought the dorm. Of course not everything roses.
. Our new range is fertile.
Yeni menzilimiz toprağı bereketli
but the enemy of a place as much as the pain.
ama düşmanı da bir o kadar yaman bir yer.
The Crusader County is right under our noses.
Burnumuzun dibinde Haçlı Kontluğu var.
As our children and herds grow. the sedition fire around us will also grow.
Çocuklarımız ve sürülerimiz büyürken
etrafımızdaki fitne ateşi de büyüyecek.
As our children and herds grow. the sedition fire around us will also grow.
If so.
Madem öyle
why us ancestor ,. tell tales from grandfather.
neden bize atadan,
dededen kalma masallar anlatıp
why us ancestor ,. tell tales from grandfather.
You make our minds Ertuğrul Bey ?.
aklımızı bulandırırsın Ertuğrul Bey?
Yes, Alpargu is right.
Evet. Alpargu haklı.
Yeah, he's right. He says right.
- Evet, haklı.
- Doğru der.
Yeah, he's right. He says right.
We want dormitory not graves.
Biz yurt isteriz. Mezar değil.
Baybora is the tomb that makes the land dorm.
Toprağı yurt yapan mezardır Baybora.
Our land is our land, our grave. Let our country be the homeland.
Mezarımız olsun ki toprağımız yurt,
yurdumuz da vatan olsun.
Our land is our land, our grave. Let our country be the homeland.
Crazy Iron says right. Yeah, it's true.
-Deli Demir doğru der.
-Evet, doğru der.
Crazy Iron says right. Yeah, it's true.
You're wrong, Alpargu.
Yanlışsın Alpargu Bey.
You think our ancestors' epics are fairy tales?
Atalarımızın destanlarını masal mı sandın?
They're not to put the baby to sleep. The man is meant to wake.
Onlar bebe uyutmak için değil
adam uyandırmak içindir.
They're not to put the baby to sleep. The man is meant to wake.
We are one of them. We also learned fertile land.
Biz onlardan
bereketli toprakları da öğrendik
We are one of them. We also learned fertile land.
to melt the surrounding mountains of iron.
etrafını saran demir dağları eritmeyi de.
What do you say, Kurdoğlu ?.
Sen ne dersin Kurdoğlu?
Ertugrul is right, sir.
Ertuğrul haklıdır beyim.
The existence of our enemy is us being a veteran. Alhamdulillah opens the door of being a martyr.
Düşmanımızın varlığı bize gazi olmanın,
şehit olmanın kapısını açar elhamdülillah.
The existence of our enemy is us being a veteran. Alhamdulillah opens the door of being a martyr.
We add power to our oba, we collect booty.
Obamıza güç katar, ganimet toplarız.
Is there any objection?
Var mıdır itirazı olan?
If everyone agrees.
Madem herkes hemfikir
Then let the immigration preparations begin.
o zaman göç hazırlıkları başlasın.
Come on, Gundogdu.
Gel bakalım Gündoğdu.
Your anger is flowing through your eyes.
Öfken gözlerinden akıyor.
Rage at me or your father?
Bana mı yoksa babana mı hiddetin?
I don't like cranberry syrup, Black Lark.
Kızılcık şerbetini hiç sevmem Kara Toygar.
Actually, this is what happened. no need Gundogdu.
Aslında bu olanlara
hiç gerek yok Gündoğdu.
Actually, this is what happened. no need Gundogdu.
God forbid.
Allah göstermesin
Tomorrow is the next day. What if your old dad was a heck?
yarın öbür gün
ihtiyar babanın başına bir halt gelse
Tomorrow is the next day. What if your old dad was a heck?
substitute Wouldn't it be better for apricots?
yerine geçmen
Kayılar için daha hayırlı olmaz mı?
substitute Wouldn't it be better for apricots?
If I ever become a gentleman.
Eğer ben bir gün Bey olursam
Floating your skin. I'il feed the carcass to the dogs.
senin derini yüzer
leşini köpeklere yediririm.
Floating your skin. I'il feed the carcass to the dogs.
Wow.
Vay be!
When I came to obaya. snorting Ertuğrul I thought a heck.
Obaya geldiğimde
hırlayan Ertuğrul'u bir halt zannetmiştim.
When I came to obaya. snorting Ertuğrul I thought a heck.
The real one. toothless
Asıl cevval olan
dişini göstermeyen öteki enikmiş.
The real one. toothless
Bring him in.
Getirin onu!
Hamza.
I'm gonna give your father a last chance, Gundogdu.
Babana son bir fırsat vereceğim Gündoğdu.
I'm sending Alpin Hamza to your father.
Alpin Hamza'yı babana yollayacağım.
Tomorrow alone. I'll kindly ask her to bring it to me.
Yarın tek başına esirleri
bana getirmesini kibarca teklif edeceğim.
Tomorrow alone. I'll kindly ask her to bring it to me.
Unless he accepts my offer.
Teklifimi kabul etmezse
Before you,. Then I will sword all the Apricots.
önce seni,
sonra bütün Kayıları kılıçtan geçireceğim.
Before you,. Then I will sword all the Apricots.