Father.
Baba.
Are you okay? Do you have any pain, Dad?
İyi misin? Ağrın var mı baba?
Don't worry, I'm awake now.
Merak etme. Artık uyandım.
I'il pack up in the thesis.
Tez vakitte toparlanırım.
Thank god.
Çok şükür.
Get well soon.
Geçmiş olsun.
If you need one. Valiant tells us.
Bir ihtiyacınız olursa
Yiğit bize haber verir.
If you need one. Valiant tells us.
Ertugrul, Yigit told me everything.
Ertuğrul, Yiğit bana her şeyi anlattı.
You and you. the people who grow yaman.
Sen ve seni
yetiştirenler yaman insanlarmış.
You and you. the people who grow yaman.
You protected us.
Bizi kolladınız, korudunuz.
Whatever our custom requires. We did it, he doesn't owe.
Töremiz neyi gerektiriyorsa
onu yaptık, borcu olmaz.
Whatever our custom requires. We did it, he doesn't owe.
The people of this land. It's been a long time since you've forgotten the ceremony.
Bu toprakların insanları
töresini unutalı çok oldu.
The people of this land. It's been a long time since you've forgotten the ceremony.
For coming across someone like you.
Senin gibi birine denk geldiğimiz için
We were the beloved servants of Allah.
Allah’ın sevgili kuluymuşuz.
Do not mention it.
Estağfurullah.
I'll go and you rest.
Ben gideyim. Siz de istirahat edin.
Listen to me, Halime.
Beni iyi dinle Halime.
You'il find us a horse today.
Hemen bugün bize at bulacaksın.
You'il prepare with your brother.
Kardeşinle beraber hazırlanacaksın.
Don't show anything to anyone.
Kimseye bir şey belli etmeyin.
What's going on, Dad? What are we gonna do?.
Ne oluyor baba? Ne yapacağız?
We are going.
Gidiyoruz.
Halime, not otherwise.
Halime, başka türlü olmaz.
If we stay one more day.
Eğer bir gün daha fazla kalırsak
these people. We endanger their lives.
bu insanların
hayatlarını tehlikeye sokarız.
these people. We endanger their lives.
I'm going to the barn.
Ben ahıra gidiyorum.
Full toy front ,. where the barn came from Gundogdu ?.
Tam toy önü,
ahır da nereden çıktı Gündoğdu?
Full toy front ,. where the barn came from Gundogdu ?.
I'm gonna take care of their new horse.
Yeni getirdikleri ata bakacağım.
You too for Aleppo. Start preparations slowly.
Sen de Halep için
hazırlıklara başla yavaş yavaş.
You too for Aleppo. Start preparations slowly.
I'm gonna make everything ready.
Ben her şeyi hazır ederim de...
Is it certain you're going to Aleppo?
...Halep’e senin gideceğin kesin mi?
Destur.
I'm the one who brought the idea of Aleppo to the moon.
Halep fikrini toya götüren benim.
It is up to me to be an ambassador.
Elçi olmak da bana düşer elbette! He?
Well, say so. Either that or that.
-Öyle de--
-Ya öyle de böyle de
Well, say so. Either that or that.
Morning morning What is this restless situation Selcan ?.
sabah sabah ne bu huzursuz hâller Selcan?
You want me to go inside, so you can.
Gideceksin diye mi içim yansın,
If my father doesn't send you, you're offended. I didn't know if my mind would run off.
babam seni göndermezse kırılırsın
diye mi aklım kaçsın, bilemedim.
If my father doesn't send you, you're offended. I didn't know if my mind would run off.
Of course he will send me. Who else will he send?
Tabii ki beni gönderecek.
Başka kimi gönderecek?
Of course he will send me. Who else will he send?
Chick, look.
Hatun, bak,
If you're so sorry I'm leaving.
gidiyorum diye böyle üzülüyorsan
Until I go back and you. You welcome me two lives.
ben gidip gelene kadar sen de
beni iki canlı karşılarsın. He?
Until I go back and you. You welcome me two lives.
While you're taking care of horses in the barn.
Sen ahırda atlarla ilgilenirken,
While I'm here ready to run you.
ben de burada sana yolluk hazır ederken
he waits more than you say.
o dediğin daha çok bekler Gündoğdu.
I'il see the horses after the toy.
Toydan sonra bakarım atlara o vakit.
Sir, are you allowed?
Beyim, müsaade var mı?
Come Hamza, come.
Gel Hamza, gel.
What's up?.
Hayırdır?
Master, Solomon Shah wanted to see you.
Beyim, Süleyman Şah’ım sizi görmek istedi.
Come on, bismillah.
Haydi bismillah!
Hadi bismillah.
Come on, bismillah.
Bismillah.
Aleppo.
Halep’e
I decided to let Ertugrul go.
Ertuğrul’un gitmesine karar verdim.
Gundogdu.
I have something to talk to you about.
Seninle konuşacaklarım var.
Stay here.
Burada kal.
Ertuğrul, you go get ready.
Ertuğrul, sen de git hazırlan.
Tell Elijah Fakih.
İlyas Fakih’e de söyle,
he will come with you.
o da seninle gelecek.
Come on, hurry up.
Hadi. Hadi çabuk.
Come on, Turgut, come on.
Hadi hızlı Turgut'um, hadi hadi!
Let's.
Hadi.
I won, I won.
Ben kazandım. Ben kazandım.
Come on, I won. I crossed the line first.
Hadi oradan be! Ben kazandım.
Çizgiyi önce ben geçtim.
Come on, I won. I crossed the line first.
Come on, get these tricks. I crossed the line first.
Hadi geç bu hileleri.
Önce çizgiyi ben geçtim.
Come on, get these tricks. I crossed the line first.
Are you blind? Ask Aykız.
Kör müsün? Aykız'a sorun.
Aykız has no testimony. He's your baby.
Aykız'ın şahitliği olmaz.
Yavuklun o senin.
Aykız has no testimony. He's your baby.
Aa Let your mercy dry, Mr. Beyrek. When did I lie?
Aa! İnsafın kurusun Bamsı Beyrek.
Ne vakit yalan söyledim ha?
Aa Let your mercy dry, Mr. Beyrek. When did I lie?
I told you not to do that.
Sana bunu yapma dedim ulan!
What if I do?
Yaparsam ne olacak ha?
Look, walnuts. You have a brain, I won't be your reason.
Bak zaten ceviz kadar
beynin var, sebebin olmayayım ha.
Look, walnuts. You have a brain, I won't be your reason.
Walnut shell is intact. Don't be afraid, come, come, come.
Cevizin kabuğu sağlam.
Korkma, gel, gel, gel.
Walnut shell is intact. Don't be afraid, come, come, come.
Wait a second.
Bir durun hele. Bir durun.
What's wrong with Ertugrul?
Ertuğrul'un nesi var?
Suleyman Shah had called to his tent.
Süleyman Şah çadırına çağırmıştı.
I hope it's good.
Hayırdır inşallah.
I think the gazelle has gone hunting.
Bence ceylan avlamaya gitmiştir.
The gazelle also has a mashallah. Not like to hunt.
Ceylanın da maşallahı var ama.
Avlanacak gibi değil.
The gazelle also has a mashallah. Not like to hunt.
Prepare to go to Aleppo.
Hazırlanın. Halep'e gidiyoruz.
Heyt, Bamsy brother.
Heyt be! Bamsı kardeşim!
Shame, bro.
Bamsı, ha ha kardeşim!
Hey, man. I had a stomach for sitting.
Heyt be!
Oturmaktan göbeğim çıkmıştı be.
Hey, man. I had a stomach for sitting.
Tell Elijah Fakih. He's coming with us.
İlyas Fakih'e de söyleyin.
O da bizimle geliyor.
Tell Elijah Fakih. He's coming with us.
I brought the idea of Aleppo there.
Oraya Halep fikrini ben getirdim.
El Aziz's army. I told him he needs it.
El Aziz'in askere
ihtiyacı olduğunu da ben söyledim.
El Aziz's army. I told him he needs it.
Why isn't that me, Dad?
Niye ben değil de o baba?
That's why, son.
İşte bu yüzden evlat.
I know, I do, I told you.
Ben bilirim, ben yaparım, ben söyledim.
Your arrogance idol. When did you raise it?
İçindeki kibir putunu
ne zaman büyüttün sen?
Your arrogance idol. When did you raise it?
I'm arrogant?
Ben mi kibirliyim?
The whole oba is starving.
Bütün oba açlıktan kırılıyor.
Scarcity everywhere.
Kıtlık her yerde.
We couldn't even make a rush.
Bir akına bile çıkamadık. Neden?
Because our brain is in trouble with boils. Know your limits.
-Çünkü beyimizin çıbanla başı dertte.
-Haddini bil!
Because our brain is in trouble with boils. Know your limits.
For God's sake, Dad, all oba. people complain about your old age.
Bırak Allah aşkına baba. Bütün oba
halkı senin yaşlılığından şikâyetçi.
For God's sake, Dad, all oba. people complain about your old age.
Brother. Take your hand off me.
-Ağabey--
-Çek elini üzerimden.
Brother. Take your hand off me.
Your brother being an ambassador. You think he has a right?
Elçi olmanın ağabeyinin
hakkı olduğunu mu düşünürsün?
Your brother being an ambassador. You think he has a right?
Yeah.
Evet.
Why isn't he my brother?
Neden ağabeyim değil de ben?
He worshiped the spirit of power captured prisoners.
Taptığı iktidar ateşi ruhunu esir aldı.
So I put the fire out.
Ben de ateşi söndürdüm.
As for the fire within you.
Senin içindeki ateşe gelince,
Our guests you. They will stay in oba until they return.
misafirlerimiz sen
dönene kadar obada kalacaklar.
Our guests you. They will stay in oba until they return.
I'm saying that. don't weaken your duty.
Bunu söylüyorum ki
vazifeni zaafa düşürmeyesin.
I'm saying that. don't weaken your duty.
Do not turn emptyhanded from Aleppo.
Halep'ten eli boş dönmeyesin.
Kayi's future. I installed it on your shoulders.
Kayı'nın geleceğini
senin omuzlarına yükledim.
Kayi's future. I installed it on your shoulders.
. Failure is a disaster for all of us.
Başarısızlığın hepimizin felaketidir.
The dormitory of El Aziz. the price is given anyway.
El Aziz'in vereceği yurdun
karşılığında bedeli neyse verilir.
The dormitory of El Aziz. the price is given anyway.
But no Oguz sacrificial sheep.
Ama hiçbir Oğuz kurbanlık koyun değildir.
Do not forget this.
Şunu unutma.
Your home in Aleppo. as much as you need.
Senin Halep'te bir yurda
ihtiyacın olduğu kadar
Your home in Aleppo. as much as you need.
The Aleppo order of the Apricots. He needs his fighters.
Halep emirinin de Kayıların
savaşçılarına ihtiyacı var.
The Aleppo order of the Apricots. He needs his fighters.
. Keep your head up, who knows what you want.
Başını dik tut. Ne istediğini bilen,
true Show them you are a Oguz.
isteğinin hakkını veren gerçek
bir Oğuz olduğunu göster onlara.
true Show them you are a Oguz.
God help you.
Allah yardımcın olsun.
At the expense of my life. I will fulfill my duty, Father.
Hayatım pahasına
vazifemi yerine getireceğim baba.
At the expense of my life. I will fulfill my duty, Father.
I'il be back before I get your face black.
Yüzünü kara çıkartmadan geri döneceğim.
What happened?.
Ne oldu?
Gundogdu.
Gundogdu, stop Gundogdu, stop
Gündoğdu, dur. Gündoğdu, dur.
Back push woman.
Geri bas kadın.
Hamza Alp Alps.
Hamza Alp! Alpler!
Stop, stop.
Dur! Dur!
Get out, get out.
Çık dışarı! Çık dışarı!
You won't talk?
Konuşmayacak mısın?
The ambassador was Ertuğrul.
Elçi, elçi Ertuğrul oldu.
I told you. OK.
-Söylemiştim sana.
-Tamam!
I told you. OK.
Al Al come on, drink.
Al. Al hadi, iç.
Drink this.
İç şunu.
These are definitely the minds of Mother Hayme.
Bunlar kesin Hayme Ana'nın aklıdır.
Have him take the ball.
Topunu yel alsın.
Let them wind their ball. I know I will.
Topunu yel alsın onların.
Ben yapacağımı biliyorum.
Let them wind their ball. I know I will.
No, don't get angry.
Hayır. Öfkeye kapılma sakın.
Who starts up in anger sits down with a loss.
Öfkeyle kalkan zararla oturur.
For God's sake, woman, let go.
Bırak, Allah aşkına kadın, bırak.
Get your stuff together and get ready for the Alps.
İşlerini toparla. Alplerinle hazır ol.
You got that little brother's job. when he infects his face.
O densiz kardeşin işleri eline
yüzüne bulaştırdığı zaman
You got that little brother's job. when he infects his face.
you will get the right one.
sen hakkın olanı alacaksın.
And remember.
Hem unutma,
angels wait for the day in the grass.
ecel melekleri otağda gün bekler.
He's stuck here, Turgut.
Burama takılıp kaldı Turgut.
What can I swallow.
Ne yutabiliyorum
what can i throw.
ne atabiliyorum.
It was the first time we left. You speak like Aykız.
İlk defa ayrılırmışız
gibi konuşursun Aykız'ım.
It was the first time we left. You speak like Aykız.
When did we get Turgut?
Ne vakit kavuştuk ki Turgut?
Watching the road on his father bed. Husband is on his bed sooner a wait ?.
Baba döşeğinde yol gözlemekle
koca döşeğinde er beklemek bir mi?
Watching the road on his father bed. Husband is on his bed sooner a wait ?.
The pain of separation is not knotted in my throat.
Ayrılık acısı değil boğazımda düğümlenen.
Failure to Attain.
Kavuşamamak.
Every time we say we're getting married. always stops postponed for a reason.
Ne vakit artık evleniyoruz desek
hep bir sebepten ertelenir durur.
Every time we say we're getting married. always stops postponed for a reason.
No promises to postpone this time.
Söz. Bu defa ertelemek falan yok.
I don't know if it's Aleppo.
Halep işi olur, olmaz bilmiyorum ama
the first wedding of the new oba is ours. I promise you.
yeni obanın ilk düğünü bizimki
olacak. Sana söz veriyorum.
the first wedding of the new oba is ours. I promise you.
Drummers with Aykız. Turgut is finally getting married.
Davulcular Aykız'la
Turgut nihayet evleniyorlar
Drummers with Aykız. Turgut is finally getting married.
O people will shout.
ey ahali diye haykıracaklar.
Girls at the rug.
Kilimhanedeki kızlar
The most beautiful daughter of Oba is getting married.
obanın en güzel kızı evleniyor,
The turn will come to us. now they will show you.
sıra bize gelecek
artık diye seni gösterecekler.
The turn will come to us. now they will show you.
Even the sultan's daughters. you will leave with your beautiful beauty.
Sultan kızlarını bile
çatlatacak güzelliğinle ayrılacaksın
Even the sultan's daughters. you will leave with your beautiful beauty.
From Mad Demir's tent.
Deli Demir'in çadırından.
Very sad. I wanted to say that I am.
Çok üzgün
olduğumu söylemek istedim.
Very sad. I wanted to say that I am.
I don't know, which promise. this corresponds to pain.
Bilmiyorum, hangi söz
bu acıya karşılık gelir.
I don't know, which promise. this corresponds to pain.
You understand me best, Elenora.
Beni en iyi sen anlarsın Elenora.
And it was the Muslims who killed your father.
Babanı öldürenler de Müslümanlardı.
Get clear of the road Titus Be careful.
Yolun açık olsun Titus. Dikkatli ol.
I'il be back, Elenora.
Döneceğim Elenora. Görüşmek üzere.
Ha.
A good commander is real. transformed into a temple knight.
İyi bir komutanın gerçek
bir tapınak şövalyesine dönüştüğüne
A good commander is real. transformed into a temple knight.
You witnessed it, Elenora.
tanık oldun Elenora.
Revenge was what was missing at Titus.
İntikam, Titus'ta eksik olan buydu.
Revenge or straw. knight.
İntikam yoksa saman
askerden farkı kalmaz şövalyenin.
Revenge or straw. knight.
The death of Bisol was the miracle of Titus.
Bisol'ün ölümü Titus'un mucizesi oldu.
May God forgive the sins of Bisol.
Tanrı Bisol'ün günahlarını affetsin.
Judging by the gifts. Suleyman Shah understood his mistake.
Hediyelere bakılırsa
Süleyman Şah yaptığı hatayı anlamış.
Judging by the gifts. Suleyman Shah understood his mistake.
Our Bey loves and counts the Seljuks.
Beyimiz Selçuklu'yu sever, sayar.
But I can figure this out, Kara Lark.
Ama bu işi ben çözebilirim Kara Toygar.
The time I gave. Kurdoğlu ends in the morning.
Verdiğim süre
sabah olunca bitiyor Kurdoğlu.
The time I gave. Kurdoğlu ends in the morning.
Otherwise the Seljuks. all the Kayi Obasi burns out of his anger.
Aksi halde Selçuklu'nun
öfkesinden bütün Kayı Obası yanar.
Otherwise the Seljuks. all the Kayi Obasi burns out of his anger.
You with us. You'll burn Black Lark.
Bizimle birlikte sen de
yanarsın Kara Toygar.
You with us. You'll burn Black Lark.
How dare you.
Ne cüretle!
Don't tell me what happened. Don't tell me the Sultan has news.
Sakın bana bu olanlardan
Sultan'ın haberi olduğunu söyleme.
Don't tell me what happened. Don't tell me the Sultan has news.
To force them from Solomon Shah.
Onları Süleyman Şah'tan zorla almak için
the number of soldiers in your hand is not enough.
elindeki asker sayısı yeterli değil.
You need to pack a whole army.
Koca bir ordu toparlaman gerek.
Mighty to crush Kayi. I know you have armies.
Kayı'yı ezip geçecek kudretli
ordularınızın olduğunu biliyorum.
Mighty to crush Kayi. I know you have armies.
You do, but first of all. The Sultan needs to know.
Yaparsın ama önce bunlardan
Sultan'ın haberi olması gerek.
You do, but first of all. The Sultan needs to know.
That won't do you any good either.
Bu da senin işine gelmez.
Actually, it doesn't do us any good either.
Doğrusu bizim de işimize gelmez.
Long story short, both. For you and oba to win.
Uzun lafın kısası, hem
senin hem de obanın kazanması için
Long story short, both. For you and oba to win.
You have to listen to me.
sözümü dinlemen lazım.
Since your goal is to cooperate.
Mademki amacın iş birliği yapmak
Then tell me, who did it ?.
söyle o zaman, kim yaptı bunu?
Suleyman Shah?
Süleyman Şah mı?
The son of Süleyman Şah, Ertuğrul.
Süleyman Şah'ın oğlu, Ertuğrul.
Dogy, Dogan.
Bamsı, Doğan.
It's a journey.
Yolculuk varmış.
When?.
Ne vakit?
Morning with prayer. We will set off for Aleppo.
Sabah ezanıyla birlikte
Halep'e yola koyulacağız.
Morning with prayer. We will set off for Aleppo.
Are you ready?
Hazırlandınız mı peki?
We alps are ready for anything.
Biz alpler her an, her şeye hazırız.
Everything comes easy when you get used to it.
Doğru. Alışınca kolay gelir her şey.
Sometimes it's hard to get used to.
Bazen de zor gelir alışınca.
Have a nice trip.
Yolun açık olsun.
Don't let the sun burn.
Güneş tenini yakmasın.
Don't let the rain get cold.
Yağmur canını üşütmesin.
Don't touch the stone with your feet.
Ayağına taş değmesin. Su gibi git,
turn to water like obana.
su gibi dön obana.
It's like a bird flying.
Kuş misali uçarak götürür,
The thesis brings me back in time. obama then.
tez vakitte beni geri getirir
obama o zaman.
The thesis brings me back in time. obama then.
Your parents rejoice.
Annen baban sevinir.
What about you?.
Ya sen?
I?.
Ben?
I'il be gone by now.
Ben gitmiş olurum çoktan.
You can not leave.
Gidemezsin.
So before I return.
Yani ben dönmeden...
Your father can't pull himself together.
Baban toparlayamaz kendini.
Be clear, Ertuğrul Bey.
Yolun açık olsun Ertuğrul Bey.
Who knows, maybe.
Kim bilir belki...
I have something on my mind.
Aklıma takılan bir şey var.
Our forced guests.
Bizim zoraki misafirler
Are you relatives of Sultan Alaaddin or something?
Sultan Alaaddin'in akrabaları falan mı?
This is none of your business. True.
-Bu seni hiç ilgilendirmez.
-Doğru.
This is none of your business. True.
It's none of my business.
Beni hiç ilgilendirmez.
Come to the point What's going through your head?
Sadede gel. Kafandan ne geçiyor?
If you want to get what you want. I will have a small condition.
İstediğini almak istiyorsan
benim de küçük bir şartım olacak.
If you want to get what you want. I will have a small condition.
Ertugrul.
My chip, my Aykız whatever.
Can yongam, Aykız'ım neyse
Halime and her family are for me.
Halime ve ailesi de o benim için.
Do not worry.
Sen hiç merak etme.
God bless you, Crazy Iron.
Allah senden razı olsun Deli Demir.
God bless you.
Allah asıl senden razı olsun.
The valiant relic elevates the man.
Yiğidin emaneti adamı yüceltir.
You trusted me in this oba.
Sen bu obada bana güvendin.
You came to my threshold.
Benim eşiğime geldin.
You glorified me.
Beni yücelttin.
That's why.
İşte o yüzden
God bless you.
Allah asıl senden razı olsun.
. I trust both myself and his family.
Halime de ailesi de bana emanet.
You keep your heart fresh.
Sen gönlünü ferah tut.
Come on, salute.
Hadi selametle.
Sincere son.
Candan oğul.
My dear son.
Canım oğul.
Keep your path open and your luck.
Yolun da bahtın da açık olsun.
. Kayi's got a load on her shoulders.
Kayı'nın bütün yükü omuzlarında.
Don't tilt your head. Get under the load you can't carry.
Ne başını eğ ne de
taşıyamayacağın yükün altına gir.
Don't tilt your head. Get under the load you can't carry.
God let him open the way.
Allah yolunu açık etsin.
You have to go, no return .
Gitmek var, dönmek yok.
There is no turning, no seeing .
Dönmek var, görmek yok.
To see you . I'll ride my horse nonstop .
Seni görmek için
atımı hiç durmadan süreceğim.
To see you . I'll ride my horse nonstop .
Open the road, Ertugrul .
Yolun açık olsun Ertuğrul.
While you paid your father the rebellion.
Sen babana isyanının cezasını öderken...
embassy fell on our little brain.
...küçük beyimize elçilik düşmüş.
I knew you'd come.
Geleceğini biliyordum.
Welcome.
Hoş geldin.
I don't care about prisoners, Black Lark.
Esirler umurumda bile değil Kara Toygar.
They escaped on your land.
Sizin topraklarınızda kaçtılar.
We did our part.
Biz üzerimize düşeni yaptık.
Give me the name of my brother's killer.
Bana kardeşimin katilinin adını ver.
You can't wait to be a hangman.
Cellat olmak için sabırsızlanıyorsun.
Be careful. Executioner, Black Lark.
Dikkat et.
Celladın ipine dolanma Kara Toygar.
Be careful. Executioner, Black Lark.
Your own incompetence. Don't try to tear me down.
Kendi beceriksizliğini
sakın bana yıkmaya çalışma.
Your own incompetence. Don't try to tear me down.
A couple of knights you brag about. butt couldn't get a broken alpine.
Övündüğün şövalyelerin birkaç
kıçı kırık alpin hakkından gelemedi.
A couple of knights you brag about. butt couldn't get a broken alpine.
To name it. What do you want from me?.
Onun ismini vermek için
benden ne istiyorsun?
To name it. What do you want from me?.
You. I'll give you more than you want.
Sana
istediğinden daha fazlasını vereceğim.
You. I'll give you more than you want.
. I'il hand him over to him.
Onu ellerine teslim edeceğim.
It's not a matter of credit. Do you understand me?.
Bu bir alacak verecek meselesi değil.
Beni anlıyor musun?
It's not a matter of credit. Do you understand me?.
Just help a painful friend.
Sadece acılı bir dosta yardım.
Their help. We do not leave unrequited.
Bize yapılan yardımları
karşılıksız bırakmayız.
Their help. We do not leave unrequited.
Thank you.
Eyvallah.
Who?.
Kim?
Son of Solomon Shah.
Süleyman Şah'ın oğlu
Ertugrul.
Aykız.
Take a look at those pressures, girl.
Şu baskılara bir de sen bak kızım. Gel.
I'il be right over.
Hemen gelirim.
When are you leaving ?.
Ne vakit gidiyorsunuz?
Every time my dad says.
Babam ne vakit derse.
Don't stare in vain.
Hiç boşuna diklenme.
A person doesn't stop where he's not wanted.
İnsan istenmediği yerde durmaz.
If it's your turn. If you have some ar go to gather the thesis.
Eğer sizde
biraz ar varsa tez toplanıp gidin.
If it's your turn. If you have some ar go to gather the thesis.
It is customary, not to go to the guest. That's why everybody shut up.
Âdettendir, misafire git denmez.
Herkes bu yüzden susar.
It is customary, not to go to the guest. That's why everybody shut up.
Both.
Hem
Is that how you pay. Your debt to these people ?.
böyle mi ödeyeceksiniz
borcunuzu bu insanlara?
Is that how you pay. Your debt to these people ?.
. He gave you his bread, his tent.
Size ekmeğini veren, çadırını veren
to the people who have wounded you. you see this reva ?.
sizin yaranızı saran insanlara
bunu mu reva görüyorsunuz?
to the people who have wounded you. you see this reva ?.
I. Joyful.
-Ben--
-Sen...
I. Joyful.
You're in pursuit. blood will be shed while running obada, blood.
Sen oynaş peşinde
koşarken obada kan dökülecek, kan.
You're in pursuit. blood will be shed while running obada, blood.
Get on your way.
Varın gidin yolunuza.
Halime.
Halime. Selcen.
- Halime!
- Selcan!
Halime. Selcen.
What did you tell her?
Ne söyledin kıza?
What he needs to hear.
Duyması gerekeni.
He needs to hear. you say things?
Duyması gereken
şeyleri sen mi söylüyorsun?
He needs to hear. you say things?
I'm thinking about the obanity.
Ben obanın dirliğini düşünüyorum.
That girl. he should have heard it long ago.
O kızın bunları
çok evvel duyması gerekirdi.
That girl. he should have heard it long ago.
Woe woe woe woe. The gentleman was ungrateful.
Vah vah vah vah!
Bey kızı töre bilmez olmuş.
Woe woe woe woe. The gentleman was ungrateful.
Ata. speak
Atasının
sözünün üzerine söz söyler olmuş.
Ata. speak
Selcan.
Akılını başına devşir Selcan.
You thought you crushed it. Then you stay under those stones.
Ezdiğini sandığın
o taşların altında kalırsın sonra.
You thought you crushed it. Then you stay under those stones.
What happened?. Go to work.
-Ne oldu?
-İşine bak!
What happened?. Go to work.
Ertuğrul set out with four alpes.
Ertuğrul dört alpiyle yola çıkmış.
Shortly.
Kısasa kısas.
Poetic justice.
İlahi adalet.
Where's he going?
Nereye gidiyormuş?
Aleppo.
Halep'e.
I will avenge myself.
İntikamımı kendi ellerimle alacağım.
I can never allow that, Titus.
Buna asla izin veremem Titus.
Why is that?.
Neden?
I'm in charge of this land.
Bu topraklarda idare bende.
On my own. I only use force.
Kendi sınırlarımda
sadece ben güç kullanırım.
On my own. I only use force.
Ally with a crusader.
Bir haçlıyla ittifak yapıp
If I hear bloodshed, our plan is broken.
kan döktüğüm duyulursa planımız bozulur.
This guy killed my brother, Kara Lark.
Bu adam kardeşimi öldürdü Kara Toygar.
I want him alive. I'il take his life with my own hands.
Onu senden canlı istiyorum.
Kendi ellerimle alacağım onun canını.
I want him alive. I'il take his life with my own hands.
Do not worry.
Sen hiç merak etme.
Sacrifice her. like a ram.
Onu kurbanlık
bir koç gibi bıçağına sunacağım.
Sacrifice her. like a ram.
Kara Lark is convinced, sir.
Kara Toygar ikna oldu beyim.
Until they recover and end their stay.
İyileşip misafirlikleri bitene kadar
He asked us to look after them.
bizden onlara göz kulak olmamızı istedi.
Did you find out who they were?
Kim olduklarını öğrenebildin mi?
Ser gave it, he did not tell the son of the pig.
Ser verdi, sır vermedi domuzun oğlu.
Bigger Seljuk.
Koca Selçuklu'yu telaşlandırdığına göre
obviously have a tail pains.
belli ki bir kuyruk acıları var.
It is our duty to take advantage of this opportunity.
Bize düşen bu fırsattan faydalanmaktır.
You ordered me, sir.
Beni emretmişsiniz beyim.
Unless you have another. Go to rest.
Başka bir diyeceğin yoksa,
yol yorgunusun Kurdoğlu. Git dinlen.
Unless you have another. Go to rest.
Alp.
That malady. Save me from boils Akçakoca.
Şu illet
çıbandan kurtar beni Akçakoca.
That malady. Save me from boils Akçakoca.
I hope, sir.
İnşallah beyim.
. I guess that's what my death will be.
Ölümüm bundan olacak galiba.
Keep me informed. Your order, sir.
-Beni her şeyden haberdar et.
-Emrin olur beyim.
Keep me informed. Your order, sir.
Everything's ready, Dad.
Her şey hazır baba.
I got what I needed.
Gerekenleri koydum.
We'il go tonight.
Bu gece gideceğiz.
You don't think about your wound.
Sen yaranı düşünme.
Akçakoca'nın what and how. I learned that he did well.
Akçakoca'nın neyi nasıl
yaptığını da iyice öğrendim.
Akçakoca'nın what and how. I learned that he did well.
Auntie, calm down, girl.
Halime, sakin ol kızım.
Like we always do. we will escape from a place where we seek refuge.
Her vakit yaptığımız gibi,
sığındığımız bir yerden kaçacağız.
Like we always do. we will escape from a place where we seek refuge.
So.
O kadar.
Is that it, Dad?
O kadar mı baba?
Just that?
Sadece o kadar mı?
I don't know what's on your mind.
Aklından neler geçiyor bilmiyorum.
But what makes this place different for you?
Ama burayı senin için farklı kılan ne?
Is there something you didn't tell me?
Bir şey mi var bana söylemediğin?
I'm tired, Dad.
Çok yoruldum baba.
I'm so tired of running now.
Artık kaçmaktan çok yoruldum.
Let's start a new life.
Yeni bir hayat kuralım.
No one of us. Let's go to places he can't find.
Kimsenin bizi
bulamayacağı yerlere gidelim.
No one of us. Let's go to places he can't find.
Let us cross the deserts and seas. Let's go, Dad, as long as we go.
Çölleri, denizleri aşalım ama
gidelim baba, yeter ki gidelim.
Let us cross the deserts and seas. Let's go, Dad, as long as we go.
Father.
Baba.
What happened, son? What is it, Valiant?
Ne oldu oğlum? Ne oldu Yiğit'im?
We have guests Want to enter.
Misafirimiz var. Girmek ister.
Gelsin.
Selamun aleykum. I Aleykümselam.
-Selamünaleyküm.
-Aleykümselam.
Selamun aleykum. I Aleykümselam.
Here you are.
Buyurun.
Dad, look, Crazy Iron. He made a sword for you and my sister.
Baba, bak. Deli Demir,
sen ve ablam için kılıç yapmış.
Dad, look, Crazy Iron. He made a sword for you and my sister.
He's the best blacksmith around here. He makes the best swords.
Buraların en iyi demircisidir o.
En iyi kılıçları o yapar.
He's the best blacksmith around here. He makes the best swords.
No, son.
Yok be oğlum.
Ours is just an occupation.
Bizimkisi sadece meşgale.
These are yours.
Bunlar sizin.
Thanks.
Sağ olasın.
Promise, girl? Our Ertuğrul Bey is gone.
Sözü mü olur kızım?
Ertuğrul Bey'imiz gitti ya,
Promise, girl? Our Ertuğrul Bey is gone.
I wanted to stay in touch.
pusatsız kalmayın istedim.
Besides, it'il make her comfortable.
Hem onun içi rahat eder
and mine.
hem de benim.
Anyway, I'm in the shop, but my eye is in the tent.
Neyse, ben dükkândayım ama gözüm çadırda.
. If you have a request, feel free.
Bir isteğiniz olursa çekinmeyin.
What would happen to the big obada?
Koca obada ne olur ki?
Look, girl.
Bak kızım.
Ertuğrul is my son.
Ertuğrul benim evladım sayılır.
So he won't break his request.
O yüzden onun ricasını kırmak olmaz.
That was bad.
İşte bu kötü oldu.
We're going this way.
Bu taraftan gideceğiz.
. Tell Ertuğrul to let the horses rest.
Ertuğrul'a söyle, atlar biraz dinlensin.
Animals that will crack.
Çatlayacak hayvanlar.
His mind is Obadan in Halime. She wants to keep up with her.
Onun aklı Halime'de. Obadan
ayrılmadan ona yetişmek istiyor.
His mind is Obadan in Halime. She wants to keep up with her.
Tell me if you dare.
Cesaretin varsa sen söyle.
Lord.
Beyim.
We'il crack and the horses will crack.
Biz çatlasak olur da atlar çatlayacak.
Sir, what if we breathe by that creek?
Beyim, şu dere kenarında nefeslensek?
Let's get down there. We leave before sunrise.
Şu aşağıda dinlenelim.
Gün doğmadan yola çıkarız.
Let's get down there. We leave before sunrise.
Born, close to fire.
Doğan, ateş yakın.
My head is on my head, sir.
Başım gözüm üstüne beyim.
Follow me quietly.
Sessizce beni takip edin.
Hush.
Hişt!
Selamun aleykum.
Selamünaleyküm.
I Aleykümselam.
Aleykümselam.
What about the animal?
Ne olmuş hayvancağıza?
I found it like this.
Bu hâlde buldum.
Who knows which hunter. he fell into this state.
Kim bilir hangi avcının
elinden kaçarken bu hale düşmüş.
Who knows which hunter. he fell into this state.
I think that hunter is mine.
O avcı benim galiba.
That you missed this prey. You're not a good hunter, son.
Bu avını elinden kaçırdığına
göre pek iyi bir avcı değilsin evlat.
That you missed this prey. You're not a good hunter, son.
Thank you dervish.
Eyvallah derviş.
Moon beautiful face.
Ay güzel yüzlüm.
You're big. You got away from it, huh?
Bu koca yiğidin
elinden kaçıp kurtuldun ha?
You're big. You got away from it, huh?
You have a mashallah.
Maşallahın varmış.
Come on, bre bismillah. Get your health back in a short time.
Haydi bre bismillah.
Kısa zamanda sıhhatine kavuşasın.
Come on, bre bismillah. Get your health back in a short time.
Come on, let's go.
Hadi bakalım, hadi git hadi.
Where do you come and go?
Nereden gelip nereye gidersin?
We'il come and go to hell.
Haydan gelip huya gideriz.
What about you?.
Ya sen?
We'il go to Aleppo.
Halep'e gideriz.
Oh, so keep your eyes open.
Ha, öyleyse hep gözünüz açık olsun.
Do not feed the bird to the wolf. The weather is hazy.
Kurda kuşa yem olmayın.
Buraların havası pusludur.
Do not feed the bird to the wolf. The weather is hazy.
Don't get lost.
Pusta kaybolmayın.
Will you forgive me your name?
Bana ismini bağışlar mısın?
Ibn 's of Andalusia.
Endülüslü İbnü'l-Arabî.