All dead?
Hepsi öldü mü?
Unfortunately, it has to be.
Maalesef öyle olmak zorunda.
All but Gundogdu will die.
Gündoğdu dışında hepsi ölecek.
Maybe one of them is lucky.
Belki içlerinden şanslı biri
will bring the bad news to Solomon Shah.
kötü haberi, Süleyman Şah'a getirecek.
Wow.
Vay canına.
Suleyman Shah's reign will end.
Süleyman Şah'ın saltanatı bitecek.
Well, the whole world.
De gidi koca dünya.
Wow Wow wow.
Vay, vay, vay.
What if he insists on honor?
Ya töre diye ısrar ederse?
If he doesn't.
Esirleri vermezse?
What will he do?
Vermeyip de ne yapacak?
Amen to call your son's death?
Oğlunun ölümüne amin mi diyecek?
Gathering their Alps. What do we do if he attacks Kara Lark?
Alplerini toplayıp
Kara Toygar'a saldırırsa ne yapacağız?
Gathering their Alps. What do we do if he attacks Kara Lark?
I know Solomon Shah well.
Süleyman Şah'ı iyi tanırım.
He's your own life.
O kendi canını ortaya kor.
Black Lark will eliminate both.
Kara Toygar ikisini de ortadan kaldıracak.
Only Ertuğrul remains.
Geriye bir tek Ertuğrul kalıyor.
Him too.
Onu da...
You've gone too far, sir.
Çok ileri gittin beyim, çok.
This doesn't end well.
Bu işin sonu hiç iyi değil.
Fuck it.
If you were so scared. Why have you been with me?
Madem bu kadar korkuyordun,
niye benimle birlik oldun?
If you were so scared. Why have you been with me?
It's for the oba to go straight.
Obanın düze çıkması için beyim.
That this will get here. What's going on, huh?
-Bu işin buraya varacağını...
- Neye varacak ha?
That this will get here. What's going on, huh?
What will he get?
Neye varacak?
Three, five for the sake of this oba. If the alpine is to be sacrificed, it is welcome.
Bu obanın iyiliği için üç, beş
alp feda edilecekse, edilir.
Three, five for the sake of this oba. If the alpine is to be sacrificed, it is welcome.
No way, huh?
Edilmez mi ha?
Tell me, can't you?
Söyle bana, edilmez mi?
Welcome, sir.
Edilir beyim.
It is.
Edilir.
Ah.
May Allah have mercy on all of them.
Allah hepsine gani gani rahmet eylesin.
. We did what we needed.
Biz ne gerekiyorsa onu yaptık.
If you caravan Black Lark. If I had not persuaded the raid.
Eğer Kara Toygar'ı kervan
baskınına ikna etmeseydim
If you caravan Black Lark. If I had not persuaded the raid.
with his army.
ordusuyla üstümüzden geçerdi.
He refuted our family.
Sülalemizi çürütürdü.
Now all we have to do is. lean back.
Şimdi tek yapmamız gereken şey,
arkamıza yaslanıp
Now all we have to do is. lean back.
obaya black news. wait for it to fall.
obaya kara haberin
düşmesini beklemek.
obaya black news. wait for it to fall.
You go wash your hands. Come on, come on.
Sen de git elini yüzünü yıka.
Kendine gel hadi.
You go wash your hands. Come on, come on.
Watch this coward, Alpargu.
Bu korkağa dikkat et Alpargu.
If his fear hits his tongue. also avoid hesitation.
Eğer korkusu diline vuracak olursa,
kökünden koparmaktan da çekinme.
If his fear hits his tongue. also avoid hesitation.
Everything. She'll be fine, sister, you'll see.
Her şey
düzelecek abla, göreceksin.
Everything. She'll be fine, sister, you'll see.
Suleyman Shah does not sacrifice his son.
Süleyman Şah, oğlunu feda etmez.
No sacrifice, huh?
Feda etmez ha?
Of course not.
Etmez tabii.
But he won't crush his ritual either.
Ama töresini de ezip geçmez.
Sister.
Abla.
Things that won't happen for God's sake. don't think about yourself.
Allah aşkına olmayacak şeyler
düşünüp, kendini perişan etme.
Things that won't happen for God's sake. don't think about yourself.
Gündoğdu from Kara Toygar. If he does a madness to save ?.
Gündoğdu'yu Kara Toygar'ın elinden
kurtarmak için bir delilik yaparsa?
Gündoğdu from Kara Toygar. If he does a madness to save ?.
This is gnawing, Gökçe.
İçimi kemiren bu, Gökçe.
I'm gonna go talk to Suleyman Shah.
Gidip Süleyman Şah'la konuşacağım.
First he will release Gundogdu.
Önce Gündoğdu'yu serbest bırakacak.
Then where we want Black Lark. I will set out to bring.
Sonra Kara Toygar'ı istediğimiz yere
getirmek için yola çıkaracağım.
Then where we want Black Lark. I will set out to bring.
. And when we get to where we're going.
Varacağımız yere ulaşınca da
The rest is now your courage. And your skill will remain, son.
gerisi artık sizin cesaret
ve hünerinize kalacak evlat.
The rest is now your courage. And your skill will remain, son.
It's a big deal. is on a distinguished road.
Mühim bir mesele
konuşulmakta Selcan Hatun.
It's a big deal. is on a distinguished road.
Get away from me.
Çekil önümden.
Our master's orders.
Beyimizin emri.
I said get out of my way.
Sana çekil önümden dedim.
Black Lark Eagle. We'll set him up on Hill.
Kara Toygar'ı Kartal
Tepesi'nde tuzağa düşüreceğiz.
Black Lark Eagle. We'll set him up on Hill.
Let's talk outside.
Gel dışarda konuşalım.
Gündoğdu my brother is safe to you. I promise to bring it.
Gündoğdu abimi sana sağ salim
getireceğime dair söz veriyorum.
Gündoğdu my brother is safe to you. I promise to bring it.
If anything happens to my Gundogdu.
Eğer Gündoğdu'ma bir şey olursa,
If your brother is on the way. sacrifice what you find.
eğer ağabeyini yolda
bulduklarına feda edersen
If your brother is on the way. sacrifice what you find.
I have two hands on your collar.
iki elim yakanda olur Ertuğrul.
Bey.
Beyim.
As a father.
Bir baba olarak
I have one last request from you.
senden son bir isteğim olacak.
If you'll excuse my daughter. I want to entrust you.
Müsaade edersen kızımı
sana emanet etmek istiyorum.
If you'll excuse my daughter. I want to entrust you.
Black Lark ,. He's after me and my son.
Kara Toygar,
oğlumla benim peşimde.
Black Lark ,. He's after me and my son.
She has no problem with my daughter.
Kızımla dertleri yok.
My daughter is the daughter of the oba.
Kızım, obanın kızıdır artık.
He has no one, no place to go.
Ne kimsesi var, ne gidecek yeri.
Keep your heart fresh, Aunt.
Gönlünü ferah tut yenge.
Stop what do you want ?.
Dur! Ne istiyorsun?
I was going to ask about an otak head.
Bir otak başını soracaktım.
He used to be the head of my unit.
Eskiden birliğimin otak başıydı.
Who are you looking for?.
Kimi arıyorsun?
They say Saru Saru Börü.
Saru. Saru Börü de derler.
We know Saru Börü.
Saru Börü'yü tanırız elbet.
But now he is. Not the head, but the division.
Ama artık kendisi
otak başı değil, bölükbaşı oldu.
But now he is. Not the head, but the division.
Headquarters?
Karargahta mı?
He went on a mission with Kara Toygar.
Kara Toygar'la göreve gitti.
If you have something to say to us.
Bir diyeceğin varsa bize de.
I got it, I got it.
Var. Var yiğidim, var.
Welcome back, Titus.
Hoş gelsin Titus.
Come on, sit down.
Geç, otur.
Master dove. I read the letter he sent.
Üstadın güvercinle
gönderdiği mektubu okudum.
Master dove. I read the letter he sent.
Your apricots to Aleppo. he didn't want him to emigrate.
Kayıların, Halep'e
göç etmesini istemiyormuş.
Your apricots to Aleppo. he didn't want him to emigrate.
Yeah.
Evet.
No worries.
Hiç merak etmesin.
The apricots are not Aleppo.
Kayılar Halep'e değil
they will emigrate to where I want.
benim istediğim yere göç edecekler.
How?.
Nasıl?
Future gentlemen. He thinks the same thing.
Müstakbel beyleri,
benimle aynı şeyi düşünüyor.
Future gentlemen. He thinks the same thing.
Crusaders. rather than walking around.
Haçlıların
ayağına dolaşmaktansa
Crusaders. rather than walking around.
At the bottom of the Mongols directory. prefers to sit.
Moğolların dizinin dibinde
oturmayı tercih ediyor.
At the bottom of the Mongols directory. prefers to sit.
Who is this guy?.
Kim bu adam?
The Kurdoğlu.
Suleyman Shah's blood brother.
Süleyman Şah'ın kan kardeşi.
A passionate fool.
İhtiraslı bir budala.
He won't break our promises, what we want. someone we can use like.
Sözümüzden çıkmayacak, istediğimiz
gibi kullanabileceğimiz birisi.
He won't break our promises, what we want. someone we can use like.
What about Suleyman Shah?
Ya Süleyman Şah?
Suleyman Shah.
Süleyman Şah.
In the evening, come to my headquarters. will be delivered.
Akşam olunca karargahıma gelip,
teslim olacak.
In the evening, come to my headquarters. will be delivered.
And that his knights missed.
Üstelik şövalyelerinin elinden kaçırdığı
princes will bring with you.
şehzadeleri de yanında getirecek.
Mr. Afşin.
Afşin Bey'im.
I thought he was dead.
Öldüğünü zannediyordum.
It was supposed to be known, Börü.
Öyle bilinmesi gerekiyordu Börü.
Our state is under great threat.
Devletimiz büyük tehdit altında.
I need your help.
Yardımına ihtiyacım var.
Where is this ominous news ?.
Nerede kaldı bu uğursuz haber?
Sir, I am Suleyman Shah. waits for you
Beyim, Süleyman Şah'ım
sizi otağında bekler.
Sir, I am Suleyman Shah. waits for you
The princes, whatever. No black lark.
Her ne olursa olsun şehzadeleri,
Kara Toygar almamalı.
The princes, whatever. No black lark.
Or Sultan Alaeddin. If he manages to take princes?
Ya Sultan Alâeddin'e
şehzadeleri götürmeyi başarırsa?
Or Sultan Alaeddin. If he manages to take princes?
He becomes Alaeddin's favorite commander.
Alâeddin'in en gözde komutanı olur.
The Templars occupy Konya.
Tapınakçılar, Konya'yı mesken tutarlar.
They throw javelin in the state. It would be great to plague Saru.
Devletin içinde cirit atarlar,
bunun vebali büyük olur Saru.
They throw javelin in the state. It would be great to plague Saru.
We did not establish this state easily.
Biz bu devleti kolay kurmadık.
And princes, if necessary. We will not hesitate to kill.
Gerekirse şehzadeleri de
öldürmekten çekinmeyeceğiz.
And princes, if necessary. We will not hesitate to kill.
Whatever you want from me. I'm ready to do it, sir.
Benden ne istiyorsanız
yapmaya hazırım beyim.
Whatever you want from me. I'm ready to do it, sir.
Thank you, I know Saru, I know.
Eyvallah, biliyorum Saru biliyorum.
Wow, cruel Kara Toygar.
Vay zalim Kara Toygar vay.
How to chopped brave?
Nasıl kıymış yiğitlerimize?
And Gundogdu. captured, huh ?.
Üstüne üstlük Gündoğdu'yu da
esir etmiş, ha?
And Gundogdu. captured, huh ?.
Yeah.
Evet.
Now the guests. They expect me to deliver.
Şimdi de misafirleri
teslim etmemi bekliyorlar.
Now the guests. They expect me to deliver.
So push this rabies push. will be our best.
Öyleyse bu kuduz itin eceli
bizim elimizden olacak.
So push this rabies push. will be our best.
Let's go with our Alps. Let's get the world over.
Varalım alplerimizle gidelim,
dünyayı başlarına geçirelim.
Let's go with our Alps. Let's get the world over.
No.
Hayır.
I'm going alone.
Ben tek başıma gideceğim.
I won't put you alone.
Seni yalnız koymam.
When one of us went to death. Let the other look after.
Biz, birimiz ölüme giderken
öteki ardından baksın
When one of us went to death. Let the other look after.
To shed like tears.
avratlar gibi gözyaşı döksün diye mi
We became blood brother in time, sir.
kan kardeşi olduk zamanında beyim?
My path. The fate of the unknown Kurdoğlu.
Benim çıkacağım yolun
akıbeti meçhul Kurdoğlu.
My path. The fate of the unknown Kurdoğlu.
When something happens to me. The obama I left behind.
Başıma bir hâl geldiğinde
ardında bıraktığım obama
When something happens to me. The obama I left behind.
Blood stretched my brother's arm. If I didn't know, wouldn't I go?
kan kardeşimin kol kanat gerdiğini
bilmezsem, gözüm açık gitmez mi?
Blood stretched my brother's arm. If I didn't know, wouldn't I go?
You have power while I'm gone.
Ben yokken vekâlet sende.
Come on, put this on.
Gel, şunu da giy.
Cold on the roads.
Yollarda üşüme.
Sister.
Abla.
Oh, tell me, lion.
Hı, söyle aslanım.
What if I never see you again?
Ya bir daha seni göremezsem?
What does that mean, Valiant?
O ne demek öyle Yiğit'im?
We've been through what.
Biz beraber ne badireler atlattık.
What challenges we have come against.
Ne zorluklara karşı geldik.
Of course we will overcome this.
Bunun da üstesinden geleceğiz elbet.
But this time we're leaving. and we are without you.
Ama bu defa ayrılıyoruz
ve yanımızda sen yoksun.
But this time we're leaving. and we are without you.
And those guys will take us.
Ya o adamlar bizi alır...
. Don't you ever squeeze your heart like that.
Sen hiç yüreğini böyle dertlerle sıkma
lion brother?
olur mu aslan kardeşim?
Look, we're not alone this time. oba has gentlemen.
Bak, bu defa yalnız değiliz,
obanın beyleri var.
Look, we're not alone this time. oba has gentlemen.
They protect our lives. interests us.
Onlar bizim canımızı korurlar,
bize sahip çıkarlar.
They protect our lives. interests us.
You stay with my father. Just get out of his word, okay?
Sen babamın yanından ayrılma.
Onun sözünden çıkma yeter, olur mu?
You stay with my father. Just get out of his word, okay?
And don't think about me.
Hem sen beni de düşünme.
I'll sit here, wait for you.
Ben burada oturacağım, sizi bekleyeceğim.
No worries, okay?
Üzülmek yok, anlaştık mı?
Now go.
Hadi. Şimdi git
Goodbye to your friends.
arkadaşlarına allahaısmarladık de.
Ugh. Let's.
- Of
- Hadi.
Ugh. Let's.
Father.
Baba.
Don't be brave. But I'm telling you not to worry.
Yiğit korkmasın,
üzülmesin diye söylüyorum ama
Don't be brave. But I'm telling you not to worry.
My mind doesn't believe, Dad.
aklım inanmıyor baba.
What about this?
Ne olacak bu iş?
My daughter,.
Kızım,
It's been a long time.
çok uzun zaman oldu.
Running away, falling prisoner. We have suffered a lot.
Kaçarak, tutsak düşerek
çok çileler çektik.
Running away, falling prisoner. We have suffered a lot.
I hope this will end this time.
Bu iş, bu defa bitecek inşallah.
Ertugrul has an idea.
Ertuğrul'un bir fikri var.
It's in my mind.
Benim de aklıma yattı.
At the time of the dissertation, go safely. We will go back to Allah's leave.
Tez zamanda sağ salim gidip,
geri döneceğiz Allah'ın izniyle.
At the time of the dissertation, go safely. We will go back to Allah's leave.
This oba is just for us. that he paid heavy prices.
Bu oba bizim için o kadar
ağır bedeller ödedi ki
This oba is just for us. that he paid heavy prices.
Never do what we do rights. We can't pay, Dad.
ne yapsak asla haklarını
ödeyemeyiz baba.
Never do what we do rights. We can't pay, Dad.
But, Dad, let me. Let me come with you.
Ama baba izin ver,
izin ver ben de sizinle geleyim.
But, Dad, let me. Let me come with you.
Whatever it is, no or evil.
Ne olacaksa olsun, hayır ya da şer.
We'll end up together.
Sonumuz beraber olsun.
You just pray for us, girl.
Sen bizim için dua et yeter kızım.
Nice heart. my own beautiful, brave girl.
Gönlü güzel,
kendi güzel, cesur kızım benim.
Nice heart. my own beautiful, brave girl.
She's as devoted, devoted, beautiful as her mother.
Anası gibi fedakâr, cefakâr, güzel kızım.
Do not worry.
Merak etme.
Everything will be alright.
Her şey düzelecek.
No, what do you want ?.
Hayırdır, ne istiyorsunuz?
Fall in front of us.
Düş önümüze.
Ugh.
Of...
Like a knife stuck in my back. it hurts me.
Sırtıma saplanmış bıçak gibi
canımı yakar bu çıban musibeti.
Like a knife stuck in my back. it hurts me.
Oh, sir, ah. Ugh.
- Ah beyim, ah.
-Of
Oh, sir, ah. Ugh.
Pain, pain.
Acın, acımdır.
But I can't help it.
Lakin elimden bir şey gelmez.
My children and pray for you. I can't do anything else.
Evlatlarım ve senin için dua
etmekten başka bir şey yapamıyorum.
My children and pray for you. I can't do anything else.
We have suffered.
Biz ne acılar çektik.
No migrations, no wars.
Ne göçler, ne savaşlar gördük.
Husband also had a share.
Kocamak da nasip oldu.
Thank God for these days. We came all the way, Hayme.
Şükürler ola ki bugünlere
kadar gelebildik Hayme'm.
Thank God for these days. We came all the way, Hayme.
We saw it, sir.
Gördük ya beyim.
No weddings, no new babies, no springs.
Ne düğünler, ne yeni bebeler, ne baharlar.
We saw victories.
Zaferler de gördük.
Hopefully we will see from now on.
İnşallah bundan sonra da göreceğiz.
Get your halal.
Hakkını helal et.
Neither of these troubles persistent. what is this life, sir.
Ne bu dertler kalıcı,
ne bu ömür bâki beyim.
Neither of these troubles persistent. what is this life, sir.
You walked the right way.
Sen doğru yolda yürüdün.
You didn't bend over.
Eğilip bükülmedin.
Walking towards the road,. disappeared manager?
Doğru yolda yürüyenin,
kaybolduğu görülmüş müdür?
Walking towards the road,. disappeared manager?
If Allah grants you and. I will see my sons return.
Allah nasip ederse senin ve
evlatlarımın dönmesini göreceğim.
If Allah grants you and. I will see my sons return.
God help you.
Allah yardımcın olsun.
I have a right to you.
Hakkım sana helal olsun.
Thanks.
Sağ ol.
No, what do you want ?.
Hayırdır, ne istiyorsunuz?
Where it comes from. Where do you go, Afşin Bey ?.
Nereden gelir,
nereye gidersin Afşin Bey?
Where it comes from. Where do you go, Afşin Bey ?.
Are you getting off or gin? one wanted to hear from you.
İn misin, cin misin
bir senden duymak istedim.
Are you getting off or gin? one wanted to hear from you.
My God.
Allah'ım.
Protect them, my Lord.
Sen onları koru ya Rabb'im.
You called me, Mother.
Beni çağırtmışsın ana.
I called.
Çağırdım ya.
Come on, sit down.
Gel, otur şöyle.
Here, mother.
Buyur ana.
Mr. Ertugrul.
Excuse me?
Müsaade var mı?
Halime Sultan comes to our ottoman. Permission to talk?
Halime Sultan otağımıza gelir de
müsaadenin lafı mı olur?
Halime Sultan comes to our ottoman. Permission to talk?
Ertuğrul Bey ,.
I lied to you.
ben sana yalan söyledim.
Yeah, you did.
Evet, söyledin.
Now you understand why. that we have to go ?.
Şimdi anladın mı neden
gitmek zorunda olduğumuzu?
Now you understand why. that we have to go ?.
Why are your days in this obada for us?
Neden bu obada geçen günlerin bizim için
The thesis is a dream that will end in time ?.
tez vakitte sona erecek bir rüya olduğunu?
You're happy here.
Sen burada mutlusun.
Despite his life at the palace.
Sarayda geçen ömrüne rağmen
nomad You say I'm dreaming.
göçebe bir obada
rüyadayım diyorsun ya Halime
nomad You say I'm dreaming.
If the whole world came together.
bütün cihan bir araya gelse
still unhappy. I won't let you.
yine de mutsuz olmana
müsaade etmem.
still unhappy. I won't let you.
Do you understand me, girl?
Beni anladın mı kızım?
I get it, Ana.
Anladım ana.
Good.
İyi.
Come on now.
Hadi git şimdi.
Instead of rebelling and saying bad words. Remember the name of Allah, pray.
İsyan edip kötü söz söylemek yerine
Allah'ın adını an, duanı et,
Instead of rebelling and saying bad words. Remember the name of Allah, pray.
Fill your heart with goodness. Good share.
yüreğini iyilikle doldur ki
nasibimiz iyi olsun.
Fill your heart with goodness. Good share.
It's just a matter. not my happiness.
Mesele sadece
benim mutluluğum değil.
It's just a matter. not my happiness.
It's my father's. my brother's soul.
Mesele babamın,
kardeşimin canı.
It's my father's. my brother's soul.
Do not worry.
Merak etme.
Your father and your brother. I won't let anything happen.
Babana da kardeşine de
bir şey olmasına müsaade etmeyeceğim.
Your father and your brother. I won't let anything happen.
. I'll bring them back to you unharmed.
Onları sana sağ salim getireceğim.
Keep your heart fresh.
Gönlünü ferah tut.
Stolen from my life. whatever is left of the plucked.
Hayatımdan çalınanlardan,
koparıp alınanlardan geriye kalan ne varsa
Stolen from my life. whatever is left of the plucked.
Take them, you will go Ertuğrul.
onları alıp, gideceksin Ertuğrul.
My father, my brother.
Babamı, kardeşimi...
I beg you to come back with them.
Yalvarırım sen de onlarla dön.
Turn back to complete what's missing in me.
Dön ki içimde eksik olanı tamamla.
If I can't go back, you know.
Eğer geri dönemezsem bil ki
If anything is missing inside me, I found it in you.
içimde eksik olan ne varsa, sende buldum.
Their intention is another Gökçe.
Bunların niyeti başka Gökçe.
They'll send the range to death for the custom.
Töre için erimi ölüme yollayacaklar.
Sister, look, Suleyman Shah is a human being.
Abla, bak Süleyman Şah da bir insan.
Do you ever take your son?
İnsan hiç evladına kıyar mı?
What happens in your mind?
Ne olur çıkar şu vesveseleri aklından.
You haven't met Solomon Shah yet.
Sen Süleyman Şah'ı tanımamışsın daha.
He even burns his obas for his ceremony.
O, töresi için obasını bile yakar.
I have to find a way, Gökçe.
Mutlaka bir yol bulmalıyım Gökçe, mutlaka.
To sacrifice the range. I won't let you.
Erimi kurban etmelerine
izin vermeyeceğim.
To sacrifice the range. I won't let you.
Sister.
Abla.
Ertuğrul's Alps were omitted. lurking, waiting to go.
Ertuğrul'un Alpleri atlanmış,
pusaklanmış, gitmeyi bekler.
Ertuğrul's Alps were omitted. lurking, waiting to go.
I have something to say to you, Kurdoğlu.
Sana diyeceklerim var Kurdoğlu.
No, Selcan Hatun ?.
Hayırdır Selcan Hatun?
Gundogdu trusts you. you count.
Gündoğdu sana güvenir,
seni sayar bilirsin.
Gundogdu trusts you. you count.
What about you, Selcan Hatun?
Peki ya sen Selcan Hatun?
I've always trusted your bravery.
Yiğitliğine her zaman güvenmişimdir.
Thank you.
Eyvallah.
Head of Gundogdu. arrivals is not something that happens.
Gündoğdu'nun başına
gelenler olur şey değil.
Head of Gundogdu. arrivals is not something that happens.
But do not worry,. Solomon Shah will bring him.
Ama merak etme,
Süleyman Şah onu getirecektir.
But do not worry,. Solomon Shah will bring him.
No, he won't do that.
Hayır, bunu yapmayacak.
If you dare.
Eğer yiğitsen,
If Solomon Shah. If you don't want him to throw obas.
eğer Süleyman Şah'ın
obasını ateşe atmasını istemiyorsan
If Solomon Shah. If you don't want him to throw obas.
if you like Gündoğdu a little bit.
eğer Gündoğdu'yu biraz olsun seviyorsan...
If Suleiman Shah does such a thing.
Eğer Süleyman Şah böyle bir şey yaparsa
I throw him into the fire with my own hands.
onu ateşe ben kendi ellerimle atarım.
Now I'm listening to you, Selcan Hatun.
Şimdi seni dinliyorum Selcan Hatun.
Süleyman Şah with Ertuğrul.
Süleyman Şah, Ertuğrul'la birlikte
Black Lark. He's gonna trap it on Eagle Hill.
Kara Toygar'ı,
Kartal Tepesi'nde tuzağa düşürecek.
Black Lark. He's gonna trap it on Eagle Hill.
What are you saying, Selcan Hatun?
Ne diyorsun sen Selcan Hatun?
I heard it with my ears.
Kulaklarımla duydum.
Suleyman Shah rather than smashing the ceremony.
Süleyman Şah töresini ezip geçmektense
crush your son. I prefer you.
oğlunu ezip geçmeyi
tercih etti diyorum sana.
crush your son. I prefer you.
Don't tell anybody about it, Selcan Hatun.
Bundan kimseye bahsetme Selcan Hatun.
You never talked to me, we never met.
Benimle de hiç konuşmadın, hiç görüşmedik.
Okay, Selcan Hatun?
Tamam mı Selcan Hatun?
What about Gundogdu?
Gündoğdu'ya ne olacak?
We'll find a solution.
Bir hâl çaresi buluruz elbet.
Come on, go before anyone sees you.
Hadi, kimseler görmeden git şimdi.
Haha.
Are we gonna let them go, sir?
Gitmelerine izin mi vereceğiz beyim?
Black Lark's hunt is more fertile. Let Alpargu.
Kara Toygar'ın avı daha bereketli
olsun diye izin vereceğiz Alpargu.
Black Lark's hunt is more fertile. Let Alpargu.
Before I go to my sword. without blood on me.
Elim kılıcıma gitmeden,
üstüme kan bulaşmadan
Before I go to my sword. without blood on me.
I've cleaned up all the shit.
obayı bütün pisliklerden temizledim.
Come on, jump on your horse.
Hadi, atla atına.
To Black Lark. I have to say.
Kara Toygar'a
diyeceklerim var.
To Black Lark. I have to say.
Pale . to the horses running out of breath .
Soluk
soluğa koşan atlara ant olsun.
Pale . to the horses running out of breath .
. All those who come out of their horseshoes .
Nallarından kıvılcım çıkanlara ant olsun.
. For our height, for our lord,.
Boyumuz için, beyimiz için,
If I'm afraid to die for our custom .
töremiz için ölmekten korkar isem
black steel . Let me mow like heaven .
kara çelik öz kılıncımla
gök ekin gibi biçileyim.
black steel . Let me mow like heaven .
. Let the blue sky be split, and let the earth drill .
Mavi gök yarılsın, yağız yer delinsin.
. May my name be erased from similar stones .
İsmim bengü taşlardan silinsin.
My father,. happy birthday obam plaintiff in the hereafter .
Oğuz babam,
kutlu obam ahirette benden davacı olsun.
My father,. happy birthday obam plaintiff in the hereafter .
On my way to the gas .
Çıktığım gaza yolunda
May Allah help me, Khidr Ata, my companion .
Allah yardımcım, Hızır Ata yoldaşım olsun.
Come on, Titus.
Hadi Titus. Rahatla biraz.
The day is our day.
Gün, bizim günümüz.
We'll both get what we want.
İkimiz de istediğimizi alacağız.
Ertuğrul on his way to Aleppo. You were so comfortable.
Ertuğrul, Halep'e giderken de
böyle rahattın.
Ertuğrul on his way to Aleppo. You were so comfortable.
You were loose.
Böyle gevşektin.
After that.
Sonrası malum.
The incompetence of your men.
Adamlarının beceriksizliği.
Sir, Suleyman Shah.
Efendim, Süleyman Şah.
Let's not keep our guests waiting.
Misafirlerimizi bekletmeyelim.
Have them come now.
Gelsinler hemen.
They came alone, sir.
Yalnız geldiler efendim.
Quick, get him here.
Çabuk onu buraya getir.
Let's see if he hopes or finds. Black Lark.
Bakalım umduğunu mu yoksa bulduğunu mu
yiyeceksin Kara Toygar?
Let's see if he hopes or finds. Black Lark.
What do you do. You turn Suleyman Shah ?.
Sen ne işler
çeviriyorsun Süleyman Şah?
What do you do. You turn Suleyman Shah ?.
Where are they ?.
Nerede onlar?
When you leave my son, you get what you want.
Oğlumu bıraktığında istediğini alacaksın.
You thirsty, man?
Canına mı susadın be adam?
Is my life more precious than my son and me. Or the princes?
Oğlumla benim canım mı daha kıymetli,
yoksa şehzadelerin mi?
Is my life more precious than my son and me. Or the princes?
You will release Gündoğdu. Kara Lark.
Gündoğdu'yu serbest bırakacaksın
Kara Toygar!
You will release Gündoğdu. Kara Lark.
Are you threatening me?
Beni tehdit mi ediyorsun?
If you damage Gündoğdu's hair.
Gündoğdu'nun kılına zarar verirsen
Ertugrul, Seljuk them. land.
Ertuğrul, onları Selçuklu
topraklarından çıkaracak.
Ertugrul, Seljuk them. land.
Track them again. you will never find.
Bir daha onların izini
asla bulamayacaksın.
Track them again. you will never find.
What you.
Ne sen
nor are you at the service of the Templars.
ne de hizmetinde olduğun Tapınakçılar.
If you set my son free.
Oğlumu serbest bırakırsan
I'll take you to them.
seni onlara götürürüm.
Where are they ?.
Nerede onlar?
To keep them from running. I left them to Ertuğrul.
Kaçmamaları için
Ertuğrul'a bıraktım onları.
To keep them from running. I left them to Ertuğrul.
Or if something happens to us.
Ya da başımıza bir iş gelirse
Sultan Alaeddin will know everything.
Sultan Alâeddin her şeyi bilecek.
The prince wrote in a letter. He told Sultan Alaeddin everything.
Şehzade yazdığı bir mektupta
Sultan Alâeddin'e her şeyi anlattı.
The prince wrote in a letter. He told Sultan Alaeddin everything.
Temples for months. how he stayed.
Aylarca Tapınakçıların
elinde nasıl kaldığını.
Temples for months. how he stayed.
To make himself a sultan. how they were tortured.
Kendisini sultan yapmak için
nasıl işkenceler edildiğini.
To make himself a sultan. how they were tortured.
Despite these tortures. that he never sold his state.
Bu işkencelere rağmen
devletini asla satmadığını.
Despite these tortures. that he never sold his state.
. That you collaborated with the Templars.
Senin Tapınakçılarla iş birliği yaptığını.
So everything.
Yani her şeyi.
The decision is yours.
Karar senin.
.
Father.
Baba!
Son.
Oğlum!
What happened to the prisoners of Black Lark? No.
-Ne oldu verdin mi esirleri Kara Toygar'a?
-Hayır.
What happened to the prisoners of Black Lark? No.
Father.
Baba!
Kara Lark has released you.
Kara Toygar seni serbest bıraktı.
Go to oboe.
Obaya git.
Dad, that guy won't keep you alive.
Baba, o adam seni yaşatmaz burada!
Do what I tell you, Gundogdu.
Sana ne diyorsam onu yap Gündoğdu.
Go, come on.
Git hadi!
Father.
Baba!
Hurry up.
Çabuk ol!
Go.
Hadi git!
I said go.
Git dedim sana!
Let's go talk. what will happen?.
Gidelim bakalım konuşalım,
ne olacak?
Let's go talk. what will happen?.
No, it's Akcakoca ?.
Hayırdır Akçakoca?
Is there someone in there?
İçeride biri mi var yoksa?
What's happening in here?.
Ne oluyor burada?
What an inconvenience.
Bu ne densizlik!
Get out, Akcakoca, get out. Let's see who's inside.
Çekil Akçakoca, çekil de
içeride kim var görelim!
Get out, Akcakoca, get out. Let's see who's inside.
What's that to you?
Size ne bundan?
Get off Akçakoca.
Çekil Akçakoca!
What was said was true.
Söylenenler doğruymuş.
.
Enough enough.
Yeter! Yeter!
Enough.
Yeter!
What do you think you're doing, huh?
Ne yaptığınızı zannediyorsunuz siz ha?
Our sons are dead, Mother. because of them.
Evlatlarımız ölmüş Hayme Ana,
onlar yüzünden.
Our sons are dead, Mother. because of them.
They started the caravan. You won't tell us.
Kervanı başmışlar kervanı!
Bize demezsiniz!
They started the caravan. You won't tell us.
You'll break the ceremony and our lord, huh?
Töreyi ve beyimizi çiğnersiniz ha?
Shame on you.
Yazıklar olsun size!
Enough, Hayme Ana.
Yeter artık Hayme Ana!
How many lives will we die?
Töre diyorsun, daha kaç canımız ölecek?
Where are the bodies of our sons?
Evlatlarımızın cenazeleri nerede?
Where is Süleyman Şah?
Süleyman Şah nerede?
Not yours,. My son is dead, Mother.
Senin değil,
benim oğlum öldü Hayme Ana!
Not yours,. My son is dead, Mother.
Everyone in this oba.
Bu obadaki herkes
my child.
benim evladım.
My heart.
Benim yüreğim.
What you call Oba, unity and solidarity. when it remains.
Oba dediğin, birlik ve beraberliğin
olduğu zaman ayakta kalır.
What you call Oba, unity and solidarity. when it remains.
Unity is broken.
Birlik bozulmuşsa
Defeat the enemy,. you are destined to disappear.
düşmanın karşısında yenilmeye,
yok olmaya mahkumsunuzdur!
Defeat the enemy,. you are destined to disappear.
Suleyman Shah, our own life.
Süleyman Şah Bey'imiz, kendi canını
before your life. huh?
sizin canınızın önüne
koymuş mudur ha?
before your life. huh?
Beware of your children.
Evlatlarınızı sakınmış
oba the other way?
obanın iyiliğinden
öte yol seçmiş midir?
oba the other way?
No matter what he does,. oba is for goodness and salvation.
Ne yaparsa yapsın,
obanın iyiliği, selameti içindir.
No matter what he does,. oba is for goodness and salvation.
In his absence.
Onun yokluğunda
disrupt the unity of the oba. exuberance
obanın birliğini bozmak,
taşkınlık yapmak size yaraşır mı?
disrupt the unity of the oba. exuberance
If you try to crush it.
Töreyi ezmeye kalkarsanız
one day you will be crushed.
elbet bir gün ezilirsiniz.
After that, throwing stones at them. throws stones at me.
Bundan sonra onlara taş atan,
bana taş atmış olur.
After that, throwing stones at them. throws stones at me.
They're against them. he would have taken me against him.
Onları karşısına alan,
beni karşısına almış olur.
They're against them. he would have taken me against him.
This is known.
Bu böyle biline!
Come on, girl.
Gel kızım.
They're playing games with you.
Seninle oyun oynuyorlar.
The relationship between us. How did they learn Titus ?.
Aramızdaki ilişkiyi
nasıl öğrendiler Titus?
The relationship between us. How did they learn Titus ?.
Ertugrul.
It was only a matter of time before he understood that.
Bunu anlaması zaten an meselesiydi.
Damn it.
Lanet olsun!
I have to kill them all.
Hepsini öldürmek zorundayım!
The prince wrote to the Sultan. What about the letter ?.
Şehzadenin Sultan'a yazdığı
mektup ne olacak?
The prince wrote to the Sultan. What about the letter ?.
My palace friends.
Saraydaki dostlarım
It is the letters of the Sultan. prevents
o mektupların Sultan'ın
eline geçmesine engel olur.
It is the letters of the Sultan. prevents
I hope.
Umarım.
Who prey.
Kim av
who is the hunter.
kim avcı
They will see.
görecekler.
God keep something for you. I was so scared.
Allah muhafaza sana bir şey
olacak diye çok korktum.
God keep something for you. I was so scared.
If something happened to you. What would I tell Suleyman Shah?
Sana bir şey olsaydı
Süleyman Şah'a ne derdim ben?
If something happened to you. What would I tell Suleyman Shah?
Stay here until they get back.
Onlar dönene kadar burada kal.
Waiting for our loved ones to return.
Sevdiklerimizin dönmesini beklerken
we become comrades.
birbirimize yoldaş oluruz.
Prayer ,.
Duayla,
faithfully, patiently.
inançla, sabırla...
This is what Kay has survived.
Bu Kayı ne badireler atlattı.
It's all pain.
Hepsinin acısı
na here.
na buramda
is standing in my heart.
yüreğimde duruyor.
God knows.
Allah biliyor ya
I have never been so myself. I never felt helpless.
kendimi hiç bu kadar
çaresiz hissetmemiştim...
I have never been so myself. I never felt helpless.
That's my son.
...ki oğlum,
range.
erim
What's in my short life.
Şu kısacık ömrüme ne badireler sığdı.
Those who wanted to kill my father and my brother.
Babamla kardeşimi öldürmek isteyenler...
Because they're princes. states that wish to use them.
Şehzade oldukları için
onları kullanmak isteyen devletler.
Because they're princes. states that wish to use them.
The nights we rotted in the dungeons.
Zindanlarda çürüdüğümüz geceler.
God loves every day. I lived in fear of losing.
Allah'ın her günü sevdiklerimi
kaybetme korkusuyla yaşadım.
God loves every day. I lived in fear of losing.
My Ertuğrul Bey. aroused from this nightmare.
Ertuğrul Bey'im bizi
bu kâbustan uyandırdı.
My Ertuğrul Bey. aroused from this nightmare.
Put it in a beautiful dream.
Güzel bir rüyanın içine koydu.
Hayme Ana.
Hayme Ana,
I have never lived in my life. I found peace in your oba.
ben hayatım boyunca yaşamadığım
huzuru obanızda buldum.
I have never lived in my life. I found peace in your oba.
You wanted it.
İstediğin oldu.
Now it's my turn, Suleyman Shah.
Şimdi sıra bende, Süleyman Şah.