Thank God you're back safe and sound.
Çok şükür! Sağ salim döndünüz.
God has accepted my prayers.
Allah dualarımı kabul etti.
Suleyman.
Süleyman! Süleyman!
Suleiman.
Süleyman!
I'll make you pay.
Ödeteceğim bunu size.
I'm gonna wipe all your obes.
Bütün obanızı sileceğim.
You won't even have ashes on earth.
Yeryüzünde külünüz bile kalmayacak.
Look at your grandfather's ass, he's still barking.
Dedenin hergelesine bak, hâlâ havlıyor.
Stop what are you doing?
Dur! Ne yapıyorsun?
Didn't you hear the word of the brain? Is it good to break the word to Kayi?
Duymadın mı beyin sözünü?
Kayı'ya bey sözü çiğnemek yaraşır mı?
Didn't you hear the word of the brain? Is it good to break the word to Kayi?
Oh.
Solomon ,.
Süleyman,
Look you're not good.
bak iyi değilsin.
Let me call Akcakoca. Have a look at you, huh?
Akçakoca'ya sesleneyim de
bir bakıversin sana ha?
Let me call Akcakoca. Have a look at you, huh?
Don't worry, Hayme.
Endişelenme Hayme.
I'm just tired.
Sadece yorgunum.
Where are the signs of the Beylik?
Beylik alametleri nerede?
Kurdoğlu's work.
Kurdoğlu'nun işleri işte!
Come.
Gel.
Elderly.
Yaslan.
Anyway.
Neyse.
Your pout face, Hayme.
Asma suratını Hayme'm.
Let's breathe a little.
Biraz soluklanalım
The original lining then talk.
aslını astarını sonra konuşuruz.
Yah.
Yah Yah.
Swings his sword in the air and.
Kılıcını havada savurdu ve
stabbed in the throat of the enemy.
düşmanın gırtlağına sapladı.
I wish you'd told me. If I could see it too.
Keşke anlattıklarını
ben de görebilseydim.
I wish you'd told me. If I could see it too.
Do you know?.
Biliyor musun?
When I grow up, Ertuğrul is like my brother. I'll be as strong as her.
Ben de büyünce Ertuğrul ağabeyim gibi
olacağım. Onun kadar güçlü
When I grow up, Ertuğrul is like my brother. I'll be as strong as her.
And I'll be as brave as he is.
ve onun kadar cesur olacağım.
Did you see?.
Gördün mü?
This way. You will cross all the Alps.
Bu gidişle
bütün Alpleri geçeceksin Dündar.
This way. You will cross all the Alps.
Brother?.
Ağabey?
Valiant with the enemy. He was telling me how you woke up.
Yiğit de bana düşmanla
nasıl cenk ettiğini anlatıyordu.
Valiant with the enemy. He was telling me how you woke up.
He was very brave, too. Did he tell them?
O da çok cesurdu ama.
Onları da anlattı mı?
He was very brave, too. Did he tell them?
I'll go check on my dad.
Ben bir gidip babama bakayım.
Tell me. Did you do the same job I gave you?
Anlat bakalım.
Sana verdiğim görevi yaptın mı?
Tell me. Did you do the same job I gave you?
Something happened to the oba people when you left.
Sen gidince oba halkına bir şeyler oldu.
They stoned Halime's tent. They stoned the tent?
-Halime Abla'nın çadırını taşladılar.
-Çadırı mı taşladılar?
They stoned Halime's tent. They stoned the tent?
Yes, Halime sister was inside.
Evet. Halime Abla da içerideydi.
Inside? Thank God, my mother has come.
-İçeride mi?
-Allah'a şükür, anam geldi de
Inside? Thank God, my mother has come.
all gave their share of the mouth.
hepsinin ağzının payını verdi.
Then with Halime Abla. they went to our car.
Sonra Halime Abla'yla
gidip bizim otağa geçtiler.
Then with Halime Abla. they went to our car.
I know, you have a problem.
Bilirim, derdin vardır,
I know, you've had a hard time.
bilirim, zora düştün.
But these situations are temporary.
Ama bu haller geçici.
You're the hassle. You know how to handle it.
Sen bu güçlüklerin
üstesinden de gelmeyi bilirsin.
You're the hassle. You know how to handle it.
I just didn't fall for it.
Sadece zora düşmedim.
I'm hard on it.
Zora düşürdüm de.
Ah.
Slow chick.
Yavaş hatun.
The one with me. Am I in favor of my Alps?
Benimle yola çıkan
Alplerimin öldüğüne mi yanayım?
The one with me. Am I in favor of my Alps?
It's the Black Lark dog. That I fell captive?
O Kara Toygar köpeğinin
eline esir düştüğüme mi?
It's the Black Lark dog. That I fell captive?
Our brain ,.
Beyimizin,
my own father.
kendi öz babamın
surrender to save me. Let me get to the bottom of the ground?
beni kurtarmak için teslim
olması mı beni yerin dibine soksun?
surrender to save me. Let me get to the bottom of the ground?
Or come Ertuğrul. heroism?
Yoksa Ertuğrul'un gelip
kahramanlık yapması mı?
Or come Ertuğrul. heroism?
They planted the seed, Black Lark mowed you.
Tohumu onlar ekti, Kara Toygar seni biçti.
Just because you were milled on a millstone. Now you're gonna blame yourself?
Değirmen taşında öğütüldün diye
şimdi de kendini mi suçlayacaksın?
Just because you were milled on a millstone. Now you're gonna blame yourself?
The real criminals are enjoying it.
Asıl suçlular keyif çatmakta.
Brother,.
Ağabey,
Welcome, Mr. Ertugrul.
Hoş geldiniz Ertuğrul Bey.
I was going to see you.
Ben de sizi görmeye gelecektim.
Brother, my mother has done. I'll take a look.
Ağabey, anam aş yapmıştır,
ben bir gidip bakayım.
Brother, my mother has done. I'll take a look.
My heart was right again.
Yüreğim yine haklı çıktı.
You one more time. You kept your promise.
Sen bir defa daha
verdiğin sözü tuttun.
You one more time. You kept your promise.
You brought my father and brother to me safely.
Babamla kardeşimi sağ salim bana getirdin.
May Allah be pleased with you, Mr. Ertugrul.
Allah senden razı olsun Ertuğrul Bey.
Thank goodness, unharmed. I was destined to go and return.
Çok şükür, sağ salim
gidip dönmek nasip oldu.
Thank goodness, unharmed. I was destined to go and return.
Those who have the opportunity to go. I heard what they did, Halime Sultan.
Gitmemizi fırsat bilenlerin
yaptıklarını duydum, Halime Sultan.
Those who have the opportunity to go. I heard what they did, Halime Sultan.
I heard that.
Duydum ki
they do not know themselves have done infamous work.
kendini bilmezler rezil işler yapmışlar.
Your gentlemen, their custom. betrayed, stoned the tent.
Beylerine, törelerine
ihanet edip, çadır taşlamışlar.
Your gentlemen, their custom. betrayed, stoned the tent.
Of course you didn't.
Sizler yoktunuz elbette ama
Bey's chick, all the brave. mother, Hayme was like a mountain mother.
Bey'in hatunu, tüm yiğitlerin
anası, Hayme Ana dağ gibi yerindeydi.
Bey's chick, all the brave. mother, Hayme was like a mountain mother.
He stretched me out.
Bana da kol kanat gerdi.
They'll stay under what you've done.
Yaptıklarının altında kalacaklar.
You just went back and that's enough for me.
Siz gidip döndünüz ya bu bana yeter.
Thanksgiving what slice. What anger left in my heart.
Şükretmekten ne dilimde,
ne yüreğimde öfkeye yer kalmadı.
Thanksgiving what slice. What anger left in my heart.
Don't go over them. Ertuğrul of those who are ineffective.
Üstlerine gitme
densizlik edenlerin Ertuğrul.
Don't go over them. Ertuğrul of those who are ineffective.
They were painful.
Acılıydılar
they lost their relatives because of us.
yakınlarını bizim yüzümüzden kaybettiler.
You're so cleanhearted.
Öyle temiz kalplisin ki
made to you. even evil cannot defile him.
sana yapılan
kötülükler bile onu kirletemiyor.
made to you. even evil cannot defile him.
In the lifetime of us. there are as good as the wicked.
Bize biçilen ömürde
kötüler kadar iyiler de vardır.
In the lifetime of us. there are as good as the wicked.
Thank God it was his problem. Allah gives you his cure.
Şükürler olsun ki derdini veren
Allah, dermanını da veriyor.
Thank God it was his problem. Allah gives you his cure.
My father told me.
Babam söyledi.
We come out of the Seljuk lands. Until you're going to be with us.
Biz Selçuklu topraklarından çıkana
kadar bizim yanımızda olacakmışsınız.
We come out of the Seljuk lands. Until you're going to be with us.
God willing.
İnşallah.
I'll be waiting by the tree. If you'll excuse me.
Ağacın orada bekliyor olacağım.
Müsaaden olursa
I'll be waiting by the tree. If you'll excuse me.
I will introduce you to a very beautiful girl.
seni çok güzel bir kızla tanıştıracağım.
Mr. Gündoğdu.
Gündoğdu Bey'im
If anyone is ashamed, it 's not you.
utanacak biri varsa o sen değilsin.
Ertuğrul is the plague of these troubles.
Başımıza bu belaları saran Ertuğrul'dur.
Look at these things I've been through, babe.
Düştüğüm şu hallere bir bak hatun.
In the eyes of the people. Look at these things.
Ahalinin gözünde düştüğüm
şu hallere bir bak.
In the eyes of the people. Look at these things.
My honor has been trampled.
Onurum ayaklar altına alındı.
Don't worry, you know the truth.
Tasalanma sen, ahali de bilir gerçeği.
Yel doesn't move the rock.
Yel, kayayı oynatmaz.
It takes dust.
Tozunu alır!
It's not good for you to give up.
Vazgeçmek sana yakışmaz.
Now come to the table.
Şimdi sofraya gel.
Your father waits for everyone at the table.
Baban sofrada bekler herkesi.
What now, sir?
Ne olacak şimdi beyim?
What if Kara Lark talks?
Kara Toygar ya konuşursa?
He'll do whatever it takes.
Ne gerekiyorsa o yapılacak.
The arrow went off the bow once.
Ok bir kere çıktı yaydan
whoever is in it will be stabbed. Bey.
-kimin nasibiyse ona saplanacak.
-Beyim
whoever is in it will be stabbed. Bey.
Even if we got Black Lark.
Kara Toygar'ı halletsek bile
When Solomon Shah was gone. We've fired up.
Süleyman Şah yokken
ortalığı biz ateşlendirdik.
When Solomon Shah was gone. We've fired up.
Doesn't he say who's behind this?
Demez mi bu işin ardında kim var diye?
Did he question this job?
Bu işi bir sorguladı mı
first goes to my head.
ilk benim kellem gider.
Baybora.
Now is the time for the storm.
şimdi fırtına zamanıdır.
Like dry leaves. If you keep vibrating, you will be thrown away.
Kuru yaprak gibi
titreşip durursan savrulursun.
Like dry leaves. If you keep vibrating, you will be thrown away.
Stand a little upright.
Azıcık dik dur.
What shall I do, sir?
Ne yapayım peki beyim?
Just disappear for a while.
Ortadan kaybol bir süre.
I'll let you know when we're clear.
Etraf durulunca sana haber ederim.
Okay, sir. What are we gonna do, sir?
-Tamam beyim.
-Biz ne yapacağız peki beyim?
Okay, sir. What are we gonna do, sir?
&quot;What do we do?&quot; lion?
"Ne yapacağız"ı
var mı aslanım?
&quot;What do we do?&quot; lion?
In the absence of Solomon Shah. we have relinquishes.
Süleyman Şah'ımızın yokluğunda
sahip çıktığımız emanetlerini
In the absence of Solomon Shah. we have relinquishes.
We will return him to Suleiman Shah.
Süleyman Şah'ımıza iade edeceğiz.
Where's your brother? She's talking to Halime.
-Ağabeyin nerede?
-Halime Abla'yla konuşuyor.
Where's your brother? She's talking to Halime.
I'm sorry, I made you wait.
Kusura bakmayın, beklettim.
Gökçe, come on, girl, sit down.
Gökçe, hadi kızım sen de otur.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
But we postponed when these things intervened.
Bu olaylar araya girince erteledik ama
The certificate you gave. I have to take him to Aleppo, Dad.
verdiğin beratı
Halep'e götürmem lazım baba.
The certificate you gave. I have to take him to Aleppo, Dad.
Guests like to go. I don't know where they're going.
-Misafirler de gitmek ister.
-Varacakları yeri bilmiyorum.
Guests like to go. I don't know where they're going.
But at least until Aleppo.
Ama en azından Halep'e kadar
Let's get together, we talked. If you'll excuse me.
beraber yol alalım diye konuştuk.
Tabii müsaaden olursa.
Let's get together, we talked. If you'll excuse me.
I want you to have a meeting.
Hele toy bir toplansın.
We'll see if the funerals come.
Cenazeler bir gelsin, bakarız.
Baybora.
There you go, Alpargu.
İşte oldu Alpargu.
The signs of our lord. where we belong.
Beyimizin alametlerini
ait olduğu yere getirdik.
The signs of our lord. where we belong.
What's happening, Rahman?
Ne oluyor Rahman?
The Kurdoğlu. He brought the portents of the principality.
Kurdoğlu
beylik alametlerini getirmiş.
The Kurdoğlu. He brought the portents of the principality.
To meet you. waits for acceptance, sir.
Sizinle görüşmek için
huzura kabul bekler beyim.
To meet you. waits for acceptance, sir.
Tell him.
Söyle ona
You wait.
beklesin.
Tell me.
Söyle bakalım.
Who says.
Kim söyledi
Hamza's hiding tent?
Hamza'nın saklandığı çadırı?
What?.
Let's.
Hadi.
I'm listening, tell me.
Dinliyorum, söyle.
Who's behind this curse?
Kim bu lanetin arkasındaki?
I can't say, sir.
Diyemem beyim!
If I say, they'll kill me right.
Dersem beni sağ komazlar.
Right comas.
Sağ komazlar demek!
Dimezsen is our you alive. Who said we were going to quit?
Dimezsen bizim seni sağ
bırakacağımızı kim söyledi ha?
Dimezsen is our you alive. Who said we were going to quit?
Say it, dog.
Söyle ulan köpek!
You threw me in my sister's tent. Were the stones too big, huh?
Halime bacının çadırına attığın
taşlar da bu kadar büyük müydü ha?
You threw me in my sister's tent. Were the stones too big, huh?
Said.
Söyle!
Tell me to have a salvation.
Söyle de bir kurtuluşun olsun.
Who fired you and released you?
Kim ateşleyip, saldı ortalığa sizi?
Who? Talk.
Kim? Konuş!
Doğanca.
Doğanca!
these wrestlershaped valiants,. such small stones do not match.
bu pehlivan endamlı yiğitlere,
böyle ufak tefek taşlar yaraşmaz.
these wrestlershaped valiants,. such small stones do not match.
It's like a mountain cub. cuts the ones.
Öyle dağ yavrusu gibi
olanları anca keser.
It's like a mountain cub. cuts the ones.
Baybora built it. Baybora built it all.
Baybora yaptırdı.
Hepsini Baybora yaptırdı.
Baybora built it. Baybora built it all.
Oh, wow.
Vay anasını!
My brother's madness.
Kardeşimin deliliği,
my father's stubbornness,.
babamın inadı,
as if the brutality of the enemy was not enough.
düşmanın gaddarlığı yetmezmiş gibi
and a traitor in us.
bir de içimizde bir hain türedi.
A traitor who sold his own man to the enemy.
Kendi insanını düşmana satan bir hain.
Who is this traitor?
Kimmiş bu hain?
I know.
Bilsem.
Oh, if only I knew. I will punish myself with my own hand.
Ah, bir bilsem.
Kendi elimle vereceğim cezasını.
Oh, if only I knew. I will punish myself with my own hand.
But it's very close.
Ama çok yakınımızda belli ki.
So he'll tell the enemy. close up of a traitor.
Demek düşmana haber verecek
kadar yakın bir hain var.
So he'll tell the enemy. close up of a traitor.
But you still retreat to your tent. trouble
Ama sen hâlâ çadırına çekilip,
derdine yanacak kadar
But you still retreat to your tent. trouble
quiet, deserted.
sessiz, ıssız kalırsın öyle mi?
Do not you understand?.
Anlamıyor musun?
You are the hope of this oba, Gundogdu.
Bu obanın umudu sensin Gündoğdu.
Don't leave the square empty.
Meydanı boş bırakma!
Because of those people who are unclear.
Kim olduğu belirsiz o insanlar yüzünden
oban disallow
obanın dirliğinin
bozulmasına müsaade etme.
oban disallow
It's unclear who he is. Those people have what they call you ?.
Kim olduğu belirsiz
o insanlar dediklerin var ya?
It's unclear who he is. Those people have what they call you ?.
Who?.
Kim?
The chick from the Seljuk Dynasty.
Selçuklu Hanedanlığı'ndan hatun.
That guy called your number.
Numan denilen o herif
prince,.
şehzade,
That saint you despise the sultan.
o hakir gördüğün kız da sultan.
Ugh.
Ahh.
Ahh!
That's what happened to us. now it is clear why.
Başımıza bunların
neden geldiği şimdi belli oldu.
That's what happened to us. now it is clear why.
Ertuğrul's obaya infested. the problem, exceeded his own neck.
Ertuğrul'un obaya musallat
ettiği dert, kendi boyunu da aştı.
Ertuğrul's obaya infested. the problem, exceeded his own neck.
You sit here. What are you going to watch.
Sen burada oturup
olanları mı seyredeceksin
You sit here. What are you going to watch.
Or stand up. show your strength?
yoksa ayağa kalkıp
gücünü mü göstereceksin?
Or stand up. show your strength?
What about the chick?
Ya, hatun anlamaz mısın?
Prince.
Şehzadeyi
He's protecting his family.
ailesini koruyan o!
He saved me.
Beni kurtaran o!
He saved my father.
Babamı kurtaran o!
He's the one who took Kara Lark.
Kara Toygar'ı esir alan da o!
But. But no food.
-Ama...
-Aması maması yok!
But. But no food.
Come on, I'm tired.
Yetti! Hadi, yorgunum.
Especially with Ertuğrul Gentlemen.
Hele Ertuğrul Beylerle
Seljuk property. Let's get out safely.
Selçuklu mülkiyetinden
emniyetli bir şekilde çıkalım,
Seljuk property. Let's get out safely.
After that. my duty is prince.
Ondan sonrası
benim vazifem şehzadem.
After that. my duty is prince.
Keep your heart fresh.
Gönlünüzü ferah tutun.
In difficult times. You've been very helpful, Afşin Bey.
Zor zamanlarımızda
çok yardımcı oldun, Afşin Bey.
In difficult times. You've been very helpful, Afşin Bey.
Thanks. Estağfurullah prince, our duty.
- Sağ olasın.
-Estağfurullah şehzadem, görevimiz.
Thanks. Estağfurullah prince, our duty.
Father.
Baba.
Son.
Oğlum.
I'm tired of running away, Dad.
Ben kaçmaktan bıktım baba
we are always on the road.
hep yollardayız.
We always run.
Hep kaçıyoruz.
I'm scared running, Dad.
Ben kaçarken korkuyorum baba.
I had a friend here for the first time.
Burada ilk defa bir arkadaşım oldu.
I played games for the first time.
İlk defa oyun oynadım.
Let's not go, Dad.
Ne olur gitmeyelim baba!
Let's stay here.
Burada kalalım.
But we have to go, son.
Ama gitmek zorundayız oğlum.
For your sister.
Ablan için,
for you.
senin için
we have to go.
gitmek zorundayız.
Hey.
Hoon.
Hoo!
This mare for the first time.
Bu kısrağı ilk defa
To deserve the title of Alplik. I saw in the mountains I was sent to.
Alplik sıfatını hak edebilmek
için gönderildiğim dağlarda gördüm.
To deserve the title of Alplik. I saw in the mountains I was sent to.
He was different from all the other mares.
O bütün diğer kısraklardan farklıydı.
More brutal than per se.
Daha vahşi daha başına buyruk.
It was hard to catch him.
Onu yakalamak zor oldu.
Bring it to oboe.
Obaya getirmekse dertli.
She was always upright.
Hep başının dikine giderdi.
Then he drank the oba.
Sonra obanın suyunu içti
he ate his bread.
ekmeğini yedi.
It was tamed.
Ehlileşti.
As I trust, for me. He realized how precious he was.
güvendikçe, benim için
ne kadar kıymetli olduğunu anladı.
As I trust, for me. He realized how precious he was.
He's yours now.
O artık senin.
If you'll excuse me.
Eğer sen de müsaade edersen
I named it Sultan.
adını Sultan koydum.
God willing.
İnşallah
your informal path does not fall apart.
bundan gayrı yolunuz ayrı düşmez.
We have a long way to go.
Birlikte uzun bir yolumuz var.
Even if the end is clear.
Sonu belli olsa da
The road is still ours.
yol hâlâ bizim.
Thank you, Ertuğrul Bey.
Sağ ol Ertuğrul Bey.
I will look upon the Sultan as my eyes.
Sultan'a gözüm gibi bakacağım.
As long as I live. He will live with me.
Ömrüm yettiğince
benimle beraber yaşayacak.
As long as I live. He will live with me.
I'm sorry, sir.
Kusuruma bakma beyim.
We've found out who's provoking the public.
Halkı kimin galeyana getirdiğini öğrendik.
Who ?.
Kimmiş?
Baybora.
Aren't you tired of waiting, Kurdoğlu ?.
Beklemekten sıkılmadın ya Kurdoğlu?
I know,.
Bilirim,
You never like to wait.
beklemeyi hiç sevmezsin.
How can he speak, sir?
O nasıl söz beyim?
We will wait for you if necessary.
Gerekirse sizi ömür bekleriz
get past it, sir.
gelmiş geçmiş olsun beyim.
God has forgiven you.
Allah seni bize bağışladı.
What happened, the past.
Olan olmuş, gelen geçmiş
You tell me.
sen anlat bakalım
What happened in obada when I was gone?
ben yokken obada neler oldu?
Hamza, sir.
Hamza'yı görenler olmuş beyim
işkill impressed enough by recent.
işkillenmişler.
Then they messed up.
Sonrada ortalığı velveleye verdiler.
From God.
Allah'tan
Hayme Ana came out.
Hayme Ana ortaya çıkıp
he declared the limitlessness.
o densizlerin haddini bildirdi.
Hayme said the terms of those who didn't.
Hayme densizlerin hadlerini bildirdi de
What did you do, Kurdoğlu ?.
sen ne ettin, Kurdoğlu?
I.
Ben
first gentlemen in the grass. collected, soothed, sir.
önce beyleri otağda
toplayıp, yatıştırdım beyim.
first gentlemen in the grass. collected, soothed, sir.
They saw it empty.
Otağı boş gördüler,
I wanted them not to think the ob derelict.
obayı sahipsiz sanmasınlar istedim.
Otherwise, things would get out of hand.
Aksi hâlde işler çığırından çıkacaktı.
Do what you need.
Gereğini yapıp
thanks to everything we've set.
her şeyi yoluna koyduk sayende.
Well.
Peki
Or the portents of the principality. What is carrying Kurdoğlu ?.
ya beylik alametlerini
taşımak da neyin nesidir Kurdoğlu?
Or the portents of the principality. What is carrying Kurdoğlu ?.
Guys I ,.
Beyim,
Hayme Hatun,. While dealing with his own problem here.
Hayme Hatun,
burada kendi derdiyle uğraşırken
Hayme Hatun,. While dealing with his own problem here.
and her oba works. I said it would not be appropriate to overwhelm.
bir de oba işleriyle onu
bunaltmak uygun düşmez dedim.
and her oba works. I said it would not be appropriate to overwhelm.
Thanks.
Sağ olasın.
But there's a traitor in the obelisk.
Ama obada bir hain var. Belli.
I told you, sir.
Dedim ya beyim
people, Hamza'yı who saw.
ahaliden, Hamza'yı görenler olmuş.
Akcakoca.
To groom Hamza's wound ,. as they entered and exited the tent.
Hamza'nın yarasını tımar için,
çadıra girip çıkarken fark etmişlerdir.
To groom Hamza's wound ,. as they entered and exited the tent.
Not one.
Bir değil
Kurdoğlu not two.
iki değil Kurdoğlu.
When they hit the object. Someone led them.
Obayı bastıklarında
biri onlara yol göstermiş.
When they hit the object. Someone led them.
Same person.
Aynı kişi
exchange place. He reported Kara Toygar.
takas yapılacak yeri de
Kara Toygar'a haber etmiş.
exchange place. He reported Kara Toygar.
Ertuğrullar did not break the game.
Oyunu Ertuğrullar bozmasaydı
We went to the beginning of the mountain.
telef olup gitmiştik dağ başlarında.
If there is one, sir.
Öyle biri varsa beyim
in the middle of the oba. skin with my own hands.
obanın ortasında,
kendi ellerimle derisini yüzerim.
in the middle of the oba. skin with my own hands.
Do you have another order for me, sir?
Bana başka bir emrin var mı beyim?
Gather the gentlemen at Toy. We will speak the judgment.
Toy'da beyleri toplayıp,
yargıyı konuşacağız.
Gather the gentlemen at Toy. We will speak the judgment.
My intention.
Niyetim
Judge Kara Toygar. send to the sultan.
Kara Toygar'ı yargılaması
için sultana göndermek.
Judge Kara Toygar. send to the sultan.
You back me up, you back up.
Sende bana toyda destek ol, arka çık.
We need to calm the people.
Ahaliyi teskin etmek gerek.
You made the right decision again, sir.
Yine en doğru kararı vermişsin beyim.
Do not worry.
Sen hiç merak etme.
I Khaimah ,. my brave house.
Hayme'm,
benim yiğit evdeşim.
I Khaimah ,. my brave house.
We've had a hard time.
Çok zor günler atlattık.
You have to stop.
Vesveseyi bırakmalısın.
Kurdoğlu did the necessary.
Kurdoğlu gereğini yapmış.
Don't stand on it.
Üstünde durma.
You know the truth, sir.
Sen en doğrusunu bilirsin beyim.
What are you doing in my tent?
Ne işin var senin benim çadırımda
We are already in the circle of fire.
zaten ateş çemberindeyiz.
What does one think if anyone sees?
Bir gören olursa ne düşünür?
Reverse reverse speech Kurdoğlu.
Ters ters konuşma Kurdoğlu.
We're accomplices now.
Artık suç ortağıyız.
We'll go out together.
Ya beraber çıkacağız
or we will sink together.
ya beraber batacağız.
And when you hear what I have to say.
Hem söyleyeceklerimi duyduğunda
You'll be thankful for coming here right now.
buraya hemen geldiğim için şükredeceksin.
Those migratory birds taking refuge in our oba.
Şu bizim obaya sığınan göçmen kuşlar
Do you know who it is?
aslında kimmiş bilir misin?
Okay, Mr. Kurdoğlu.
Tamam Kurdoğlu Bey'im
I'll tell you you're coming to Gundogdu.
Gündoğdu'ya geleceğinizi söylerim.
He'll be so happy.
Çok sevinecektir.
Hayrola Ertuğrul ?.
My tent like lightning. What is the reason for the fall ?.
Yıldırım gibi çadırıma
düşmenin sebebi nedir?
My tent like lightning. What is the reason for the fall ?.
Do you know where Baybora is?
Baybora nerededir bilir misin?
How should I know Ertuğrul ?.
Nereden bileyim Ertuğrul?
But let me get it.
Ama lazımsa buldurayım.
Do not bother.
Sen zahmet etme.
I find.
Ben bulurum.
Sister.
Abla.
Sister. What?.
-Abla.
-Ne?
Sister. What?.
Ertuğrul and Halime.
Ertuğrul'la Halime
they would be alone under a tree.
bir ağacın altında baş başalardı.
Obviously, Ertuğrul Bey. with no intention of going with it.
Belli ki Ertuğrul Bey,
onunla birlikte gitmeye kesin niyetli.
Obviously, Ertuğrul Bey. with no intention of going with it.
I saw it with my eyes, sister.
Gözlerimle gördüm abla.
She gave her a horse. Enough.
-O kıza bir at hediye etti.
-Yeter!
She gave her a horse. Enough.
It's up to me again.
İş yine benim başıma kaldı.
You just sit down and weep.
Sen anca otur ağla Gökçe.
Ertugrul woke up to the matter.
Ertuğrul meseleye uyandı.
Get Baybora.
Baybora'yı hallet.
The end of the chain around our neck. We must tear it off.
Zincirin ucu boynumuza
dolanmadan koparmalıyız.
The end of the chain around our neck. We must tear it off.
Are you allowed, Dad?
Müsaade var mıdır baba?
Come, girl, come.
Gel kızım gel.
How are you, Dad?
Nasılsınız baba?
Is there anything needed?
Bir şeye ihtiyaç var mıdır?
Thanks, girl.
Sağ ol, gelin kız.
How are you?.
Sen nasılsın?
How is Gündoğdu ?.
Gündoğdu nasıl?
Sorry, Dad.
Üzgündür baba.
I'm afraid it's not gonna get any better.
Toparlanamayacak diyedir korkum.
She suffered a lot.
Çok acı çekti.
But most of the Alps died.
Ama en çok Alplerin ölmesi yaraladı onu.
He said the idea of going to Aleppo.
Halep'e gitme fikrini o söyledi.
He found a new dormitory.
Yeni yurt buldu.
But when he gets the news. he was not even happy.
Ama haberi alınca
sevinmeye bile hâli olmadı.
But when he gets the news. he was not even happy.
Ertuğrul at dinner. When I said I was going to Aleppo.
Yemekte Ertuğrul,
Halep'e gideceğim deyince de
Ertuğrul at dinner. When I said I was going to Aleppo.
was thoroughly suffered.
iyice dertlenir oldu.
Had Gündoğdu gone to Aleppo.
Gündoğdu gitseydi Halep'e
maybe he would have recovered.
belki toparlanırdı biraz.
I didn't know either.
Ben de bilemedim.
I wait until I don't know what to do.
Ne yapacağımı bilemeden bekler dururum.
Gundogdu on one side.
Bir yanda Gündoğdu
on one side.
bir yanda da
Gokce.
Ertuğrul and Halime. When he found out you were going to Aleppo.
Ertuğrul'la Halime'nin
Halep'e gideceğini öğrenince
Ertuğrul and Halime. When he found out you were going to Aleppo.
was thoroughly suffered.
iyice dertlenir oldu.
You're a sensitive girl, you know.
Hassas kızdır bacım, bilirsiniz.
Ertuğrul'la shadow of happiness. he will fall.
Ertuğrul'la mutluluklarına gölge
düşecek diye endişelenir.
Ertuğrul'la shadow of happiness. he will fall.
Hey, kid.
Hey evlat.
The iron nugget you beat up.
O dövdüğün demir külçesi.
It's not Black Lark's head.
Kara Toygar'ın kellesi değil.
It's like you got a problem.
Sanki bir derdin var da
huh?
demezsin ha?
What do I say ?.
Desem ne fayda?
Sussan, what good?
Sussan ne fayda?
Look, apprentice.
Bak çırak,
There is such a problem. unlike other troubles.
öyle bir dert vardır ki
diğer dertlere benzemez.
There is such a problem. unlike other troubles.
What a dorm.
Ne yurt tutmaya
nor is it like a joke.
ne de cenk etmeye benzemez.
Sir, there's someone who wants to see you.
Beyim seni görmek isteyen biri var.
Who?.
Kim?
He's such a mess.
Öyle bir derttir ki
nice gentlemen.
nice beyleri
valiant puts this trouble.
yiğitleri zora sokar bu dert.
My problem is such a problem, Master.
Benim derdim öyle bir dert ki Demir Usta
unspoken
dile gelmez.
I will tell you this. I don't know the words.
Ben bu derdi söyleyecek
kelimeleri bilmiyorum.
I will tell you this. I don't know the words.
Language is the interpreter of your heart, son.
Dil yüreğin tercümanıdır evlat
it's not the language, it's the heart.
mesele dilde değil yürekte.
If your heart is true.
Eğer senin yüreğin doğruysa
finds the right way with the word of the language.
dilin de sözünle doğru yolu bulur.
But your problem.
Ama senin derdin
certain son.
belli evlat.
The most frightening of a valiant.
Bir yiğidi en çok korkutan
There is only one worry.
tek bir dert vardır.
He loves it.
O da sevda.
You heart.
Eğer yüreğini
If you open it to your loved one.
sevdiğine açarsan
you grow like a plane tree.
bir çınar gibi büyürsün.
If you don't.
Yok açmazsan
A wolf gnaws at it.
bir kurt içini kemirir.
Even if you're a big plane.
Koca bir çınar bile olsan
You'll fall.
devrilirsin evlat.
How will this be Master?
Nasıl olacak Demir Usta bu?
What from his father. give up your brother.
Ne o babasından,
kardeşinden vazgeçebilir
What from his father. give up your brother.
nor from my homeland.
ne de ben yurdumdan.
Oba oba with your loved one.
Oba sevdiğinle oba.
Dormitory.
Yurt sevdiğinle yurt.
You are Ertuğrul with your loved one.
Sen de sevdiğinle Ertuğrul'sun.
Unless you love it.
Eğer sevdan yoksa
dormitory, what you buy.
ne aldığın yurt,
Nor is the sword that you hit the kefer enough.
ne de kefereye vurduğun kılıç yetmez.
Let's.
Hadi.
Break the chain of your tongue.
Dilinin zincirini kır
Heart.
yüreğin...
May your heart wings.
Yüreğin kanatlansın.
Our funerals are coming.
Cenazelerimiz geliyor.
What is your interest?
Sizin bu işten çıkarınız ne?
Come to our borders. we don't want you to be trouble.
Sınırlarımıza gelip
başımıza bela olmanızı istemiyoruz.
Come to our borders. we don't want you to be trouble.
That's all.
Hepsi bu.
Kara Lark. They say you're a smart guy.
Kara Toygar'ın
anlattıklarına göre zeki biriymişsin.
Kara Lark. They say you're a smart guy.
If he's right. the three of us want the same thing.
Eğer haklıysa
üçümüz de aynı şeyi istiyoruz.
If he's right. the three of us want the same thing.
And your apricots.
Kayıların da
Your salvation.
senin de kurtuluşun
head of the army. It depends on Black Lark.
ordunun başında
Kara Toygar'ın olmasına bağlı.
head of the army. It depends on Black Lark.
Make you gentleman.
Seni bey yapıp
Oban wherever you want. He 's the only one who will make them move.
obanı istediğin yere
göç ettirecek tek adam o.
Oban wherever you want. He 's the only one who will make them move.
You're up to your ass, Kurdoğlu.
Boğazına kadar pisliğe bulaştın Kurdoğlu.
The Alps you will soon be buried in. His blood is already on his hands.
Birazdan toprağa vereceğiniz Alplerin
kanı ellerine bulaştı bile.
The Alps you will soon be buried in. His blood is already on his hands.
This is the blood of oba. You can't clean without.
Bu kanı obanın beyi
olmadan temizleyemezsin.
This is the blood of oba. You can't clean without.
Black Lark. I can't miss it.
Kara Toygar'ı obadan
kaçırmam mümkün değil.
Black Lark. I can't miss it.
But if you're as strong as you say.
Ama dediğin kadar güçlüyseniz
You can save her.
onu sen kurtarabilirsin.
Meet secretly. Where did Alpargu come from?
Gizli gizli buluşmak da
nereden çıktı Alpargu?
Meet secretly. Where did Alpargu come from?
Ertugrul.
learned to provoke the people.
ahaliyi kışkırttığını öğrenmiş.
How?. He must have made two shits.
-Nasıl?
-İki itini konuşturmuş olmalı.
How?. He must have made two shits.
Wicked man.
Aşağılık herif!
I told you.
Söylemiştim ben size.
I said these things are gonna go away.
Bu işler sarpa saracak demiştim.
You didn't listen to me.
Dinlemediniz beni!
Kurdoğlu and you caused it. let this work get here.
Kurdoğlu ve sen sebep oldun
bu işin buraya varmasına.
Kurdoğlu and you caused it. let this work get here.
What am I gonna do?
Ne yapacağım ben şimdi?
Jump on your horse and walk away.
Atına atla ve uzaklaş.
Don't even look back.
Ardına bile bakma.
Where am I going, huh? Where?.
Nereye gideceğim ha? Nereye?
I have kids.
Çocuklarım var benim.
Where do I go?
Onları bırakır da nereye giderim ben?
You come back when we fix this.
Biz bu işi düzeltince dönersin.
When we wash away the dirt. Clean it up, huh?
Elimizin kiri mi hemen yıkayınca
temizlensin de gitsin, ha?
When we wash away the dirt. Clean it up, huh?
How many of us are dead?
Kaç tane erimiz öldü?
All the goods on the caravan are gone.
Kervandaki bütün mallar gitti.
Suleyman Shah, after this. Do you think he will?
Süleyman Şah, bu işin peşini
bırakır mı zannediyorsun?
Suleyman Shah, after this. Do you think he will?
Wake up, Baybora. How do I leave them?
-Kendine gel Baybora!
- Onları bırakıp nasıl giderim?
Wake up, Baybora. How do I leave them?
With this shame, my children. How do they live in obada ?.
Bu utançla çocuklarım
obada nasıl yaşarlar?
With this shame, my children. How do they live in obada ?.
Low.
Alçak!
Do not worry.
Merak etme.
I'll take care of your family.
Ailene ben bakarım.
Oh, uh.
The sooner the person intends.
Er kişi niyetine.
Allahu akbar.
Allahu ekber.
Esselamu aleykum and mercy.
Esselamu aleykum ve rahmetullah.
our brothers.
Kardeşlerimiz
they want the last time halallik.
sizlerden son kez helallik isterler.
Do you make your right halal ?. Good job.
-Hakkınızı helal ediyor musunuz?
- Helal olsun.
Do you make your right halal ?. Good job.
Are you halal? Good job.
- Helal ediyor musunuz?
- Helal olsun.
Are you halal? Good job.
God willing, they will also halal their rights.
İnşallah onlar da haklarını helal ederler.
Our Lord, Muhammad. sallallahu
Efendimiz Hazreti Muhammed
sallallahu aleyhi ve sellem
Our Lord, Muhammad. sallallahu
for the intercession of our master.
efendimizin şefaati için.
For the soul of our brothers.
Kardeşlerimizin ruhu için.
For the obedience and abundance of our oba.
Obamızın dirliği ve bereketi için.
For God's sake.
Allah rızası için
Al Fatiha.
El Fatiha.