Come on, Gundogdu.
Gel bakalım Gündoğdu.
Your anger is flowing through your eyes.
Öfken gözlerinden akıyor.
Rage at me or your father?
Bana mı yoksa babana mı hiddetin?
I don't like cranberry syrup, Black Lark.
Kızılcık şerbetini hiç sevmem Kara Toygar.
Actually, this is what happened. no need Gundogdu.
Aslında bu olanlara
hiç gerek yok Gündoğdu.
Actually, this is what happened. no need Gundogdu.
God forbid.
Allah göstermesin,
Tomorrow is the next day. What if your old dad was a heck?
yarın öbür gün
ihtiyar babanın başına bir halt gelse
Tomorrow is the next day. What if your old dad was a heck?
substitute
yerine geçmen
Wouldn't it be better for apricots?
Kayılar için daha hayırlı olmaz mı?
If I ever become a gentleman.
Eğer ben bir gün bey olursam
Floating your skin,.
senin derini yüzer,
I'll feed the carcass to the dogs.
leşini köpeklere yediririm.
Wow.
Vay be!
When I came to obaya.
Obaya geldiğimde
snorting Ertuğrul I thought a heck.
hırlayan Ertuğrul'u bir halt zannetmiştim.
The real one.
Asıl cevval olan
toothless
dişini göstermeyen öteki enikmiş.
Bring him in.
Getirin onu!
Hamza.
I'm gonna give your father a last chance, Gundogdu.
Babana son bir fırsat vereceğim Gündoğdu.
I'm sending Alpin Hamza to your father.
Alpin Hamza'yı babana yollayacağım.
2 prisoners alone.
2arın tek başına esirleri
I'll kindly ask her to bring it to me.
bana getirmesini kibarca teklif edeceğim.
Unless he accepts my offer.
Teklifimi kabul etmezse
Before you,.
önce seni,
Then I will sword all the Apricots.
sonra bütün Kayıları kılıçtan geçireceğim.
Bona fide,.
İyi niyetli,
homespun. whatever a commander can do.
temiz kalpli
bir komutanın yapabileceği ne varsa
homespun. whatever a commander can do.
I will do it.
onu yapacağım.
That's all I can do.
Elimden ancak bu kadar gelir.
Do you understand me, huh?
Beni anlıyor musun ha?
Aa Aa.
Take them away, Saru Börü.
Götürün bunları Saru Börü.
The bow, the eyebrow.
Kaş dediğin yay,
eyelash is like an arrow.
kirpik dediğin ok gibidir.
You'll take a look at him.
Öyle bir bakacaksın ki erine
You will hit in the heart.
kalbinden vuracaksın.
His eye will see no one but you.
Gözü senden başkasını görmeyecek.
Don't drive too much.
Çok sürme.
I don't want to look hurt.
Ben de yaralanmış gibi gözükmeyeyim.
Do not worry.
Merak etme.
You'll be beautiful.
Çok güzel olacaksın.
Like a gentleman.
Bir bey hatunu gibi.
With your hair.
Sırma saçlarınla,
apple cheeks ,.
elma yanaklarınla,
You'll float with your figure all night.
endamınla süzüleceksin bütün gece.
Everyone will look after you.
Herkes sana bakacak.
But most of all Ertuğrul.
Ama en çok da Ertuğrul.
Is he gonna look?
Bakacak mı sahi?
Sure he will.
Bakacak tabii.
Look at what I promise ,.
Bakmak ne söz,
will be shot in the heart.
kalbinden vurulacak.
Seven will hear.
Yedi cihan duyacak.
Sons.
Evlatlar.
Once upon a time, I mean.
Evvel zaman içinde, yani
We make more. without migrating from the territory.
biz daha ata
topraklarından buralara göçmeden
We make more. without migrating from the territory.
long ago.
çok zaman önce
slaughter our people.
halkımıza katleden,
horses, distracted to herds.
sürülere dalıp atları,
chopper
yılkı atlarını parçalayıp yiyen
There was a dragon.
melun mu melun bir ejderha varmış.
The people will stand in such fear.
Ahali böyle korkudan durup
Don't you have us. a valiant to save this dragon.
yok mu bizi
bu ejderhadan kurtaracak bir yiğit dermiş.
Don't you have us. a valiant to save this dragon.
Oguz Ata said, I have.
Oğuz Ata'm var demiş, var!
There is.
Var.
Of course he's not like me.
Tabii o benim gibi değil.
More brave.
Böyle daha yiğit.
And broadcast, read,. as he took his crow, his sword.
Ve yayını, okunu,
kargısını, kılıcını aldığı gibi
And broadcast, read,. as he took his crow, his sword.
fallen road.
düşmüş yola.
You know your duty.
Vazifeni biliyorsun.
Don't be wild.
Yabanilik yapma.
Say hello to Ertugrul.
Ertuğrul'a selam ver.
Sir, God bless you.
Beyim, Allah razı olsun senden.
Thanks to you in the cold.
Sayende telef olmadık soğuklarda.
Koçyiğit always fall behind. Make your daughter and oba, your son and the army.
Koçyiğitlerin hep böyle ardına düşe.
Kızınla oba kurasın, oğlunla ordu olasın.
Koçyiğit always fall behind. Make your daughter and oba, your son and the army.
God bless you. Don't be missing us.
Allah senden razı olsun.
Başımızdan eksik olma.
God bless you. Don't be missing us.
Amine.
Âmin.
Look at our senses. The goat was locked up again.
Baksana bizim hisli
tekeye, kilitlenip kaldı yine.
Look at our senses. The goat was locked up again.
My Oguz Ata. standing against the dragon.
Oğuz Ata'm
dikilmiş ejderhanın karşısına
My Oguz Ata. standing against the dragon.
She said, Look at me.
bana bak demiş, bana!
I'd hit you so hard with this sword.
Bu kılıçla sana öyle bir vururum ki
your biggest part.
en büyük parçan
Your ears remain.
kulakların kalır demiş. Ya.
To our new homeland.
Yeni yurdumuz şerefine
Alps play sword shield.
Alpler kılıç kalkan oynasın.
Let's keep what we see from ancestors.
Atalardan gördüğümüzü yaşatalım.
Suleyman Shah. he has given you the ceremony.
Süleyman Şah
töredir diye sahip çıktı size.
Suleyman Shah. he has given you the ceremony.
We have.
Böyledir bizde.
And you?
Peki sizde?
In the host.
Misafir olunan yerde
gentleman look at his son. Are you seducing ?.
bey oğluna göz kaş
süzüp ayartmak mı vardır?
gentleman look at his son. Are you seducing ?.
What the hell are you talking about?
Ne diyorsun sen be?
I said I would.
Ben diyeceğimi dedim,
You understood.
sen de anladın.
Stay away from Ertugrul.
Ertuğrul'dan uzak dur.
Halime.
You look like an arrow off the bow. Or do you intend to run away again?
Yayından fırlamış ok gibisin.
Yoksa yine obadan kaçmaya mı niyetlisin?
You look like an arrow off the bow. Or do you intend to run away again?
Obviously you've heard of it.
Belli ki duymuşsun olanları.
Yeah, we tried to escape.
Evet, kaçmaya çalıştık.
But we couldn't escape, unfortunately.
Ama kaçamadık maalesef.
Nobody wants you to go.
Kimse gitmenizi istemiyor.
For us, the guest is sacred.
Bizim için misafir kutsaldır.
This is our custom.
Töremiz böyledir.
Ertuğrul Bey ,.
we carry the dark clouds above us.
biz kara bulutları üzerimizde taşırız.
Let's go oba. Let the dark clouds disperse.
Gidelim ki obanın
üstünden kara bulutlar dağılsın.
Let's go oba. Let the dark clouds disperse.
So I'm from Aleppo. You would have gone by the time I got back.
Demek ben Halep'ten
döndüğümde gitmiş olacaktınız öyle mi?
So I'm from Aleppo. You would have gone by the time I got back.
You would have stepped in.
Sırra kadem basmış olacaktın.
It would hurt.
Canım yanacaktı.
My heart would be shattered.
Yüreğim paramparça olacaktı ama
They're after us. will never leave Ertugrul.
onlar bizim peşimizi
asla bırakmayacak Ertuğrul.
They're after us. will never leave Ertugrul.
Who are they Halime ?.
Kim onlar Halime?
What do they want from you?
Ne istiyorlar sizden?
Who we are. You better not know Ertuğrul.
Bizim kim olduğumuzu hiç
bilmesen daha iyi Ertuğrul.
Who we are. You better not know Ertuğrul.
Sir, we've got a leper.
Beyim, cüzzamlı birini yakaladık.
Stand back.
Geri dur!
Stay away.
Uzak dur!
Don't keep it alive, kill it. Who are you?.
-Yaşatmayın bunu, öldürün!
- Kimsin?
Don't keep it alive, kill it. Who are you?.
Sir, to the food boilers. We caught this woman pouring something.
Beyim, yemek kazanlarına
bir şey dökerken yakaladık bu kadını.
Sir, to the food boilers. We caught this woman pouring something.
Thirsty?
Eceline mi susadın?
What did you pour into the boilers? Talk.
Ne döktün kazanlara? Konuş!
You Temple. I brought greetings from the knights Ertuğrul.
Sana Tapınak
Şövalyelerinden selam getirdim Ertuğrul.
You Temple. I brought greetings from the knights Ertuğrul.
Put the boilers and this woman in a hole.
Kazanları ve bu kadını bir çukura koyun.
Near.
Yakın!
What do these Templars want from you?
Bu Tapınakçılar senden ne ister?
To kill you in Aleppo. you told them they were working this morning.
Halep'te seni öldürmeye
çalıştıklarını daha bu sabah anlatmışken
To kill you in Aleppo. you told them they were working this morning.
All your melancholy on the night. they try to spread our oba.
gecesinde bütün melanetlerini
obamıza yaymaya çalışırlar.
All your melancholy on the night. they try to spread our oba.
It's all about your visiting family. It started with saving them from their hands.
Her şey senin şu misafir aileyi
onların elinden kurtarmanla başladı.
It's all about your visiting family. It started with saving them from their hands.
What is this ?.
Bu ne iştir?
It's deeper than it looks, Dad.
Mesele göründüğünden daha derin baba.
I don't think so. you've only been involved with the Halimis.
Zannetmem ki konu
sadece Halimelerle alakalı oldun.
I don't think so. you've only been involved with the Halimis.
It's the main reason why the Templars attacked.
Tapınakçıların esas saldırma sebebi
crusaders it must have been a homeland.
haçlıların dibinde
yurt tutmamızdan olsa gerek.
crusaders it must have been a homeland.
You can't make them.
Sen onlara konduramazsın.
But our guests are from us. There is a secret that he hides.
Ama misafirlerimizin bizden
gizlediği bir sır var.
But our guests are from us. There is a secret that he hides.
And this secret.
Ve bu sır
dangerous secret.
tehlikeli bir sır.
Of course they are our guests.
Elbet onlar misafirimizdir.
It's the crown of our heads.
Başımızın tacıdır.
However, Ertuğrul will not be more than that.
Lâkin bundan ötesi olmaz Ertuğrul.
Father.
Baba.
Ertugrul.
My son.
Evladım.
The daughter of the wild cannot be the daughter of oba.
Yabanın kızından obanın kızı olmaz.
Keep that in mind.
Bunu aklından çıkarma.
And you, Gökçe. we want to look at our daughter head.
Hem seni tez vakitte Gökçe
kızımızla baş göz etmek isteriz.
And you, Gökçe. we want to look at our daughter head.
We talked to Hayme Anan.
Hayme Ananla konuştuk.
I saw it as appropriate.
Ben de münasip gördüm.
Anyway.
Neyse.
The evil of the day is better than the good of the night.
Gündüzün şerri gecenin hayrından yeğdir.
Come in the morning.
Sabah aşına gel.
Then we'll talk.
O zaman konuşuruz.
What's your dungeon night?
Geceni zindan eden nedir oğul?
Mother.
Ana.
What's my dad say?
Babam ne der?
My sisterinlaw is going to benefit me.
Gökçe bacım bana yâr olacakmış.
Gökçe is the daughter of the gentleman.
Gökçe, bey kızıdır.
He grew up in our quarry.
Ocağımızda büyümüştür.
Juice, water.
Huyunu suyunu,
We know your lineage.
soyunu sopunu biliriz.
You know that, Ana.
Onu bilirsin de ana
Do you know my heart?
benim gönlümü bilir misin?
Halime.
There is today, not tomorrow.
...bugün var, yarın yok.
We don't know who they are.
Kim olduklarını bilmeyiz.
They say we're merchants.
Tüccarız derler.
Your father doesn't sound.
Baban ses etmez.
But he knows.
Ama bilir ki
they are not merchants.
tüccar da değiller.
They say he is the guest of Ta'ala.
Onlar Hak Teâlâ'nın misafiridir der.
Where the tip goes.
Ucu nereye gider,
will not track.
izini sürmez.
Ancestor's word.
Atanın sözü
If oba 's salvation.
obanın selametiyse sana
Gökçe says, nothing else.
Gökçe der, başka bir şey demez.
Mother.
Ana.
Trick. He brought him out with a gazelle.
Hak çalımı
bir ceylanla çıkardı onu karşıma.
Trick. He brought him out with a gazelle.
How can I cut into those beautiful eyes?
Nasıl kıyarım o güzel gözlere?
That sweet tongue?
O tatlı dillere?
One day I dare and ask.
Bir gün cesaret eder de sorarsam
Do you have heart.
gönlün var mı bende diye...
If he says my way is your way.
...o da yolum senin yolundur derse
How do I tell her to go?
nasıl git derim ona ana?
Are you sleeping?.
Uyuyor musun?
A moment in my eyes. What I would not give to close.
Gözlerimin bir an
kapanabilmesi için neler vermezdim.
A moment in my eyes. What I would not give to close.
I spoke to Ertuğrul.
Ertuğrul'la konuştum.
Her father's healed.
Kızın babası iyileşti.
Oba goes without migrating.
Oba göç etmeden giderler.
Guys I ,.
Beyim,
I called you Gökçe.
sana Gökçe'yi ben dedim.
But I'm not comfortable at all.
Ama içim hiç rahat değil.
Ertugrul has the heart of the other girl.
Ertuğrul'un öbür kızda gönlü var.
The Alpine heart goes on the trail of the obe Hayme.
Alpin gönlü obasının izinde gider Hayme.
He's young, he's young.
Gençtir, delikanlıdır.
His heart rises, swells.
Yüreği coşar, kabarır.
. When Oba settled and the tent was established.
Oba göçüp çadır kurulduğunda
the heart goes dry.
gönlündeki de kurur gider.
Come on, God rest.
Hadi. Allah rahatlık versin.
What a happy morning this is.
Ne kutlu bir sabah bu böyle.
Come on, keep it fresh.
Hadi artık ferah tut gönlünü.
Rejoice as much as you can.
Sevin sevinebildiğince.
Mr. Suleyman also said. that Ertuğrul will marry you.
Süleyman Bey'imiz de söylemiş
işte Ertuğrul'a sizi evlendireceğini.
Mr. Suleyman also said. that Ertuğrul will marry you.
I don't know, sister.
Ne bileyim abla.
Butterflies fly in me like this.
Böyle içimde kelebekler uçuşuyor ama
on the other hand. as if a dark cloud never goes.
öte yandan da
bir kara bulut hiç gitmiyor sanki.
on the other hand. as if a dark cloud never goes.
Take a oh, throw it all. through the evils.
Bir oh çek, at bütün
kötülükleri üzerinden.
Take a oh, throw it all. through the evils.
All right, this.
Tamamdır bu iş.
Let the sunrise return.
Gündoğdu dönsün hele.
No more informal.
Gayrı da bir şey yok artık.
Ertuğrul did not come?
Ertuğrul gelmedi mi?
He didn't come, sir.
Gelmedi beyim.
He's in his tent, he sleeps.
Çadırındadır, uyur.
Gökçe girl.
Gökçe kızım.
Let him come in the morning.
Git haber ediver. Sabah aşına gelsin.
Mr. Ertugrul.
Ertuğrul Bey'im.
Come, Gökçe.
Gel Gökçe.
Suleiman Shah, you morning. I'm waiting for the Ertuğrul Bey.
Süleyman Şah'ım seni sabah
aşına bekler Ertuğrul Bey'im.
Suleiman Shah, you morning. I'm waiting for the Ertuğrul Bey.
Gokce sister.
Gökçe bacım.
I am coming.
Geliyorum.
The deal is complete.
Anlaşma tamamdır.
He wants El Aziz. We will give as many soldiers.
El Aziz'e istediği
kadar asker vereceğiz.
He wants El Aziz. We will give as many soldiers.
We'll pay taxes.
Vergileri ödeyeceğiz.
Dormitory is our acceptance.
Gösterdiği yurt kabulümüzdür.
You leave tomorrow morning at your thesis.
Yarın sabah tez vakitte yola çık.
Greetings.
Selamlarımı ilet.
When we settled in our new home.
Yeni yurdumuza yerleştiğimizde
let him know I'm going to visit him.
kendisini ziyaret edeceğimi bildiriver.
Aye, Dad.
Başüstüne baba.
Good for new. When we settled in our country.
Hayırlısıyla yeni
yurdumuza yerleştiğimizde
Good for new. When we settled in our country.
We will have your wedding with Gökçe.
Gökçe'yle düğününüzü yapacağız.
So, I want a grandchild, Ertugrul.
Ee, artık bir torun istiyorum Ertuğrul.
Father.
Baba.
If you let me.
Müsaade ederseniz...
Get water, come on.
Kalk su getir hadi.
I need to see our master. Wait, let me tell our master.
- Beyimizi görmem lazım.
-Bekle, beyimize haber vereyim.
I need to see our master. Wait, let me tell our master.
Most gracious, who is that?
Rahman, kimdir o gelen?
Hamza is here, sir.
Hamza geldi beyim. Sizinle görüşmek ister.
Come on, now.
Gelsin hemen.
I hope it's good.
Hayırdır inşallah.
Bey.
Beyim.
Kara Lark.
Kara Toygar.
Black Lark stepped on the caravan. Black Lark?
-Kara Toygar kervanı bastı.
-Kara Toygar mı?
Black Lark stepped on the caravan. Black Lark?
What are you talking about, man?
Ne diyorsun sen be adam?
Where is Gündoğdu ?.
Gündoğdu nerede?
Where are my other alps?
Diğer alplerim nerede?
They're all dead, sir.
Hepsi öldü beyim.
All.
Hepsi.
Mr. Gündoğdu. Kara Lark has taken prisoner.
Gündoğdu Bey'imizi de
Kara Toygar esir aldı.
Mr. Gündoğdu. Kara Lark has taken prisoner.
What do you mean he took it?
Esir aldı ne demek?
How can you leave your brain?
Sen nasıl bırakırsın beyini ha?
How?. How did they leave you?
-Nasıl?
-Seni nasıl bıraktılar?
How?. How did they leave you?
What did he want, this Black Snake?
Ne istermiş bu Kara Toygar denilen yılan?
Mr. Ertuğrul. The guests brought by the lord.
Ertuğrul Bey'in
getirdiği misafirler beyim.
Mr. Ertuğrul. The guests brought by the lord.
Kara Lark wants them.
Kara Toygar onları istiyor.
If you don't give it tomorrow.
Eğer yarın vermezsen
They will kill our Gundogdu.
Gündoğdu Bey'imizi öldürecekler.
You caused them.
Sen sebep oldun bunlara.
It's all because of you.
Hepsi senin yüzünden.
You've brought the trouble of God.
O Allah'ın belalarını getirdin buraya,
There is no work left to us.
başımıza gelmeyen iş kalmadı!
Selcen.
Selcan, come, girl.
Selcan, gel. Gel kızım.
Come. Rahman.
- Gel.
-Rahman.
Come. Rahman.
Send the men you trust. Have them bring our bodies.
Güvendiğin adamları gönder.
Cenazelerimizi alıp getirsinler.
Send the men you trust. Have them bring our bodies.
And Hamza to anyone. take him to a tent without showing.
Hamza'yı da kimseye
göstermeden bir çadıra götür.
And Hamza to anyone. take him to a tent without showing.
Take care of Akcakoca.
Akçakoca ilgilensin.
It's obada. I don't want anyone to know.
Olanı biteni obada
kimsenin bilmesini istemiyorum.
It's obada. I don't want anyone to know.
Bring me Numan. Yes, sir.
-Bana da Numan'ı getir!
-Emredersin beyim.
Bring me Numan. Yes, sir.
Ertugrul.
What an unsupported man you are.
Sen ne destursuz adamsın be!
How do you get into the tent of the hand?
Böyle girilir mi elin çadırına?
Halime.
Suleiman Shah will wait for you in his tent.
Süleyman Şah'ım seni otağında bekler.
Hurry up.
Acele et.
Halime. Hurry up.
-Halime.
-Çabuk ol!
Halime. Hurry up.
Your master.
Numan Efendi.
It is no?.
Hayırdır?
Don't worry Afşin Nothing.
Merak etme Afşin. Bir şey yok.
Father.
Baba.
My sisterinlaw. Where are they taking my prince?
Halime bacım,
şehzademi nereye götürüyorlar?
My sisterinlaw. Where are they taking my prince?
Suleyman Shah wanted to see.
Süleyman Şah görmek istemiş.
I knew this was gonna happen.
Bunun böyle olacağını biliyordum ben.
I knew this would happen to us.
Başımıza bunların geleceğini biliyordum.
If Gundogdu's hair is damaged.
Eğer Gündoğdu'nun kılına zarar gelirse
I take the life of that girl and her family.
o kızın da ailesinin de canını alırım.
Wait, girl, stop.
Dur hele kızım, dur!
It's worthy to be steadfast to Mr. chick.
Bey hatununa metanetli olmak yakışır.
Gather yourself.
Topla kendini!
Here you go, sir.
Buyurun beyim.
You called me.
Beni çağırmışsınız.
Come this way.
Gelin bu tarafa.
A messenger arrived this morning.
Bu sabah bir haberci geldi.
The alps of my caravan. He told that they were killed.
Bana kervanımızı basıp alplerimin
canına kıydıklarını haber verdi.
The alps of my caravan. He told that they were killed.
It's Kara Toygar. my son Gundogdu'yu taken prisoner.
Bunu yapan Kara Toygar,
oğlum Gündoğdu'yu da esir almış.
It's Kara Toygar. my son Gundogdu'yu taken prisoner.
Guys I ,.
Beyim,
what is called the test. So, I don't know.
ne denir imtihanın
böylesine, bilmiyorum.
what is called the test. So, I don't know.
God give patience.
Allah sabır versin.
May you say goodbye here.
Seni buraya hayır duası edesin,
I didn't call him to report his grief.
teessürlerini bildiresin diye çağırmadım.
That I invited you here.
Seni buraya çağırmamdan
bandits holding my son hostage. You understand what they want from me.
oğlumu rehin tutan eşkıyaların
benden ne istediklerini anlamışsındır.
bandits holding my son hostage. You understand what they want from me.
Now I'm going to ask you one question.
Şimdi sana tek bir soru soracağım.
And in return. I want one answer from you.
Ve karşılığında
senden tek bir cevap istiyorum.
And in return. I want one answer from you.
Who are you?.
Kimsin sen?
On the one hand, my husband, on the other. this is the soul of the uncertain.
Bir yanda kocam, bir yanda
bu ne idiği belirsizlerin canı.
On the one hand, my husband, on the other. this is the soul of the uncertain.
They killed all the alpis. They took Gündoğdu prisoner.
Onca alpi öldürdüler,
Gündoğdu'yu esir aldılar.
They killed all the alpis. They took Gündoğdu prisoner.
But I'm telling you ,.
Lakin sana söylüyorum,
there's something they're hiding from us.
bunların bizden sakladığı bir şey var.
But I'm gonna find out.
Ama ben onu öğreneceğim.
And then I'm gonna pay for it.
Sonra da bunun hesabını soracağım.
Location mountains. girl holds a ceremony.
Yeri dağlar,
töreyi beyler tutar kızım.
Location mountains. girl holds a ceremony.
It's the job of the privates you say.
O senin söylediğin erlerin işidir.
Their plague. Because of the obada sooner or later?
Onların musibetleri
yüzünden obada er mi kaldı be ana?
Their plague. Because of the obada sooner or later?
Go after him. Don't let him mess around.
Git şunun peşinden.
Daha çok ortalığı karıştırmasın.
Go after him. Don't let him mess around.
Guys I ,.
Beyim,
tell you that. But my neck owes.
size bunu söylemek
boynumun borcudur. Fakat
tell you that. But my neck owes.
be sure.
emin olun ki...
up to my own safety. the safety of my family.
...kendi emniyetim kadar,
ailemin emniyeti kadar
up to my own safety. the safety of my family.
I also think of your safety.
sizin emniyetinizi de düşünmemdendir.
Sir, if I tell you who we are.
Beyim, kim olduğumuzu söylersem ben
the disasters you've been through today.
bugün yaşadığınız felaketler
Make sure from now. floor and floor will be more.
emin olun şimdikinden
kat ve kat fazla olacaktır.
Make sure from now. floor and floor will be more.
Not that.
Lakin...
I owe you a life.
...size bir can borcum var.
I am ready for every sacrifice for you.
Sizin için her fedakârlığa hazırım.
My own, dear. the lives of my children are included.
Buna kendi canım,
evlatlarımın canı dahildir.
My own, dear. the lives of my children are included.
I said one answer.
Sana tek bir cevap dedim. Tek bir cevap!
I.
Ben...
Ali Seljuk. Muzafferüddin Davud from the dynasty.
...Âli Selçuklu
Hanedanından Muzafferüddin Davud.
Ali Seljuk. Muzafferüddin Davud from the dynasty.
Son of Muhiddin Masud Shah.
Muhiddin Mesud Şah'ın oğlu.
I am the grandson of Sultan İzzettin Kılıçarslan.
Sultan İzzettin Kılıçarslan'ın torunuyum.
I am the Seljuk Prince.
Selçuklu Şehzadesiyim.
Halime.
Hear me.
İyice işit beni.
Here. You will curse the day you come.
Buraya
geldiğin güne lanet edeceksin.
Here. You will curse the day you come.
That's what you did. obaya, you will pay as many times.
Sen ki her ne yaşattın bu
obaya, misli misli ödeyeceksin.
That's what you did. obaya, you will pay as many times.
You understand me now?
Anladın mı şimdi beni?
If it's up to me.
Eğer iş bana düşerse
without blinking. I will be your fate, your fate.
gözümü kırpmadan
eceliniz olurum sizin, eceliniz!
without blinking. I will be your fate, your fate.
Slow down, chick.
Yavaş ol hatun.
What would you attack like a rabid dog?
Kudurmuş it gibi ne saldırırsın?
Our caravan because of you. Our valiants were killed.
Sizin yüzünüzden kervanımız
basıldı, yiğitlerimiz öldürüldü.
Our caravan because of you. Our valiants were killed.
It's Black Lark. took my rascal husband captive.
Kara Toygar denen
namussuz kocamı esir aldı.
It's Black Lark. took my rascal husband captive.
. Let his hair be damaged.
Hele onun kılına bir zarar gelsin,
Especially my dear one burn,.
hele benim canım bir yansın,
You'll see what you're raving about.
sen kudurmak neymiş o zaman göreceksin.
Sister OK.
Abla! Tamam!
Let's go.
Hadi gidelim.
We will not go Gökçe They will go.
Biz gitmeyeceğiz Gökçe. Onlar gidecek.
Dead or alive.
Ölü ya da diri.
They will go . Selcen.
Get yourself out of here.
Kendine gel. Çıkar şunu dışarı.
Whatever you just heard from my bride.
Biraz önce gelinimden her ne duyduysan
don't tell anyone about it.
bundan kimseye bahsetme.
Stay in the tent.
Çadırda kalın.
Because after that. none of us know what will happen.
Zira bundan sonra
neler olacağını hiçbirimiz bilemeyiz.
Because after that. none of us know what will happen.
Do you have destur?
Destur var mı Halime bacım?
I heard it all.
Hepsini duydum.
That's not good.
Bu hiç iyi olmadı.
What are we going to do, Mr. Afşin?
Ne yapacağız Afşin Bey?
Bride come and give something to her husband. threatened to kill us.
Gelini gelip kocasına bir şey
olursa bizi öldürmekle tehdit etti.
Bride come and give something to her husband. threatened to kill us.
Of course we'll take care of it.
Bir çaresine bakacağız elbet.
Obviously Suleyman Shah. will keep the funeral news.
Belli ki Süleyman Şah
cenaze haberini saklayacak.
Obviously Suleyman Shah. will keep the funeral news.
If the news is heard. never know what people will do.
Eğer haber duyulursa
ahalinin ne yapacağı hiç belli olmaz.
If the news is heard. never know what people will do.
God forbid.
Allah korusun.
What a thing to our princes. nor to Gundogdu.
Ne şehzadelerimize bir şey
olsun ne de Gündoğdu'ya.
What a thing to our princes. nor to Gundogdu.
Kara Toygar's intentions are clear.
Kara Toygar'ın niyeti belli.
For Gündoğdu.
Gündoğdu'ya karşılık...
to ask our princes.
...şehzadelerimizi isteyecek.
You don't leave the tent.
Siz çadırdan çıkmayın.
Whatever I needed. I will.
Ben ne gerekiyorsa
yapacağım. Müsaadenizle.
Whatever I needed. I will.
For years. We're tired of running, sir.
Yıllardır
kaçmaktan yorulduk artık beyim.
For years. We're tired of running, sir.
With my presence. I ran away from those who threatened my state.
Benim varlığımla
devletimi tehdit edenlerden kaçtım.
With my presence. I ran away from those who threatened my state.
The Templars, the Mongols. I ran away from the rebellion enthusiasts.
Tapınakçılardan, Moğollardan,
isyan çıkarma meraklılarından kaçtım.
The Templars, the Mongols. I ran away from the rebellion enthusiasts.
Of those who came after me. My only son for the survival of my state.
Peşime düşenlerden,
devletimin bekası için biricik oğlum,
Of those who came after me. My only son for the survival of my state.
do not damage my valiant. I ran away from my state.
yiğidime zarar gelmesin
diye de devletimden kaçtım.
do not damage my valiant. I ran away from my state.
Sir, I own it. I gave up my life a long time ago.
Beyim, ben kendi
canımdan vazgeçeli çok oldu.
Sir, I own it. I gave up my life a long time ago.
This is the end.
Buraya kadarmış.
Now this is work. it's time to put an end to it.
Artık bu işe
bir son vermenin zamanı geldi.
Now this is work. it's time to put an end to it.
Black Lark wants a trade, Dad.
Kara Toygar takas istiyor baba.
But let's give him what he wants. it will still kill you.
Ama istediğini ona versek
bile yine de sizi öldürecektir.
But let's give him what he wants. it will still kill you.
When you take princes. His anger against you will not end.
Şehzadeleri alınca
sana olan öfkesi bitmeyecek.
When you take princes. His anger against you will not end.
He'll kill you and my brother.
Seni de ağabeyimi de öldürür.
You're right, son.
Doğru söylersin oğul.
Gundogdu first from his hands. We have to find a way to save it.
Önce Gündoğdu'yu onun elinden
kurtarmanın bir yolunu bulmalıyız.
Gundogdu first from his hands. We have to find a way to save it.
Not just my brother. I won't turn you over to him, Dad.
Sadece ağabeyimi değil,
seni de ona teslim etmem baba.
Not just my brother. I won't turn you over to him, Dad.
Why don't I go with my Alps? Does not live Gundogdu.
Alplerimle üzerine gitsem
Gündoğdu'yu yaşatmaz.
Why don't I go with my Alps? Does not live Gundogdu.
And with blood to shed. oba never prosper again.
Hem dökülecek kanla
oba bir daha iflah etmez.
And with blood to shed. oba never prosper again.
We'll break up.
Dağılır gideriz.
First, let my brother go. You have to convince her to quit, Dad.
İlk önce ağabeyimi serbest
bırakmaya onu ikna etmelisin baba.
First, let my brother go. You have to convince her to quit, Dad.
And then him. headquarters
Sonra da onu
karargâhından çıkmaya.
And then him. headquarters
If he wants to trade. we will determine the rules.
Madem takas istiyor,
kuralları biz belirleyeceğiz.
If he wants to trade. we will determine the rules.
Why would he leave Gündoğdu?
Gündoğdu'yu niye bıraksın ki?
He has to quit, Dad.
Bırakmak zorunda baba.
The Templars have me in Aleppo. Why did he try to kill him?
Tapınakçılar beni Halep'te
neden öldürmeye kalktı?
The Templars have me in Aleppo. Why did he try to kill him?
Why to poison the oba. They sent a woman with lepers.
Neden obayı zehirlemek için
cüzzamlı bir kadın yolladılar?
Why to poison the oba. They sent a woman with lepers.
Why the Templars.
Neden Tapınakçılar
They were taking the princes to Kara Toygar.
şehzadeleri Kara Toygar'a götürüyorlardı?
The Templars land Lark.
Tapınakçılar Kara Toygar'ın
palace They wanted to get it.
sarayda önemli bir mevki
elde etmesini istiyorlardı.
palace They wanted to get it.
Serve them.
Onlara hizmet etmesini.
Kara Toygar's master. He wants princes father.
Kara Toygar'ın asıl
istediği şehzadeler baba.
Kara Toygar's master. He wants princes father.
He does everything for them.
Onlar için her şeyi yapar.
As long as we know how to ask.
Yeter ki istemeyi bilelim.
What if it's not what you say?
Ya dediğin gibi olmazsa?
Then we all die, Dad.
O zaman hepimiz ölürüz baba.
But at least we have it. Our sword, we die with honor.
Ama en azından elimizde
kılıcımız, onurumuzla ölürüz.
But at least we have it. Our sword, we die with honor.