Said.
Söyle!
Who asked you to kill Ertugrul?
Senden Ertuğrul'u öldürmeni isteyen kim?
Answer me.
Cevap ver!
Suleyman Shah's son. Who wants you to kill?
Süleyman Şah'ın oğlunu
öldürmeni isteyen kim?
Suleyman Shah's son. Who wants you to kill?
Hasn't he talked yet?
Hâlâ konuşmadı mı bu alçak?
He'll talk.
Konuşacak elbet.
We know you're not alone.
Yalnız olmadığını biliyoruz.
Who helped you through the palace?
Sana sarayın içinden yardım eden kim?
Tell him, uncle. If he speaks, I will spare his life.
Söyle ona dayıcığım,
eğer konuşursa hayatını bağışlayacağım.
Tell him, uncle. If he speaks, I will spare his life.
Answer me.
Cevap ver.
To kill the Emir's guest. Who helped?
Sana Emir'in misafirini öldürmen için
kim yardım etti?
To kill the Emir's guest. Who helped?
You helped.
Sen yardım ettin.
Answer like a man.
Adam gibi cevap ver!
. Who helped you? Who?.
Sana yardım eden kim? Kim?
Who helped you?
Sana kim yardım etti?
El Aziz's ancestor. Sahabettin Tugrul helped.
El Aziz'in atabeyi
Şahabettin Tuğrul yardım etti.
El Aziz's ancestor. Sahabettin Tugrul helped.
My Dear uncle ,.
Dayıcığım,
What does this guy say ?.
bu adam ne diyor?
He talks, you bastard.
Konuşur elbet şerefsiz.
There's an incoming.
Gelen var!
Get ready, quick. Master Titus is waiting for us.
Hazırlanın çabuk!
Efendi Titus bizi bekliyor!
Get ready, quick. Master Titus is waiting for us.
Practice is over.
Talim bitti. İçeridekilere de haber verin.
Everybody get ready.
Herkes hazırlansın.
My father said he trusted you the most.
Babam en çok sana güvendiğini söylerdi.
I trust you too.
Ben de sana çok güveniyorum.
Your favor, Altes.
Lütfunuzdur Altes!
I trust more than my uncle.
Amcamdan bile daha çok güveniyorum.
Please, Altes Elenora.
Lütfen Altes Elenora
with me Master. Please do not mention by comparing.
beni Üstat ile
mukayese ederek bahsetmeyiniz.
with me Master. Please do not mention by comparing.
Before Titus left the castle. He told me about a dungeon.
Titus, kaleden ayrılmadan önce
bana bir zindandan bahsetti.
Before Titus left the castle. He told me about a dungeon.
Before my father was killed. He wanted to say he was thrown into a dungeon.
Babamın öldürülmeden önce
bir zindana atıldığını mı söylemek istedi?
Before my father was killed. He wanted to say he was thrown into a dungeon.
I don't know, if you ask him about Master Titus. more accurate.
Bilemiyorum, onu Efendi Titus'a sorsanız
daha isabetli olur.
I don't know, if you ask him about Master Titus. more accurate.
You were always with my father before he died. but you didn't tell me about a dungeon.
Babam ölmeden önce sen hep onunlaydın
ama bana bir zindandan bahsetmedin.
You were always with my father before he died. but you didn't tell me about a dungeon.
Maybe maybe. my father is still in the dungeons.
Belki de... Belki de
babam hâlâ zindanlardadır.
Maybe maybe. my father is still in the dungeons.
I'm ready to know the truth, Mario.
Gerçeği bilmeye, duymaya hazırım Mario.
No, this is for both of you. Both of us? My father and I?.
-Hayır, bu ikiniz için de...
-İkimiz? Babam ve ben?
No, this is for both of you. Both of us? My father and I?.
No no,. I meant you and Master Titus.
Hayır, hayır,
ben siz ve Efendi Titus demek istemiştim.
No no,. I meant you and Master Titus.
Okay, put it like this.
Ah. Tamam, şöyle koy onu.
Put it like this.
Şöyle koyun.
If he's ready, remove those shods.
O hazırsa şu çaputları sökün.
Lambs, come on, get your lamb. I need that crate.
Kuzular, hadi alın kuzunuzu.
O sandık lazım.
Lambs, come on, get your lamb. I need that crate.
. Well, you guys have to do something.
Siz de bir işin ucundan tutun ha!
Fucking goat.
Ulan hisli teke
If I thought forty years I wouldn't have thought.
vallahi kırk yıl düşünsem aklıma gelmezdi
Our Ertuğrul Bey is like you. that love will deign to the work of the mesh.
Ertuğrul Bey'imizin senin gibi
bu aşk meşk işlerine tenezzül edeceği.
Our Ertuğrul Bey is like you. that love will deign to the work of the mesh.
Brother, this isn't clear.
Kardeşim, bu işler belli olmaz.
It'll happen to you.
Bir bakarsın senin de başına gelir.
. You'd think I wouldn't be ruined if the worlds came.
Dünyalar gelse yıkılmam sanırsın
but it comes with a double eye.
ama bir çift göz gelir
strikes the floor.
yere çarpar adamı.
Who the hell does this tree stump?
Kim ne yapsın bu ağaç kütüğünü be?
And to steal it on the ground. I need a pair of eyes, not a pair of wrists.
Hem bunu yere çalmak için
bir çift göz değil, bir çift bilek lazım.
And to steal it on the ground. I need a pair of eyes, not a pair of wrists.
He has me, too, evelallah.
O da bende mevcut evelallah.
Stop it, Dogan. It's not the time for the fool.
Dur hele Doğan gardaşım.
Soytarılığın sırası değil.
Stop it, Dogan. It's not the time for the fool.
I need to understand this.
Şu meseleyi anlamam lazım.
Mr. Ertugrul. Doesn't she love this girl now?
Ertuğrul Bey'imiz
şimdi bu kızı sevmiyor mu?
Mr. Ertugrul. Doesn't she love this girl now?
Well, let her ask her father.
E babasından istesin o zaman.
Is it that easy, bro?
O işler o kadar kolay mı kardeşim?
I do not understand.
Anlamıyorum.
Mr. Ertuğrul will ask. his father won't?
Ertuğrul Bey'imiz isteyecek de
babası vermeyecek mi?
Mr. Ertuğrul will ask. his father won't?
Not the most.
En olmadı
The Sultan of Halime.
kaçururuk artuk Halime Sultan'u.
What does it say?
Neler söyler gönlündeki?
Open up your problem. If there is anything we know, let's say.
E derdini aç ki
bildiğimiz bir şey varsa söyleyelim.
Open up your problem. If there is anything we know, let's say.
Sultan.
Sultan'ım
He wants the hell out of the palaces. get rid of it as soon as possible.
ister ki sarayların cehenneminden
bir an evvel kurtulsun.
He wants the hell out of the palaces. get rid of it as soon as possible.
Muhammadi Hanei is in Saadet.
Muhammed-i Hane-i Saadet'te
Keep your Lord busy.
Rabb'iyle meşgul olsun.
Shah Ibrahim Ethem. crown leave the throne.
Şah İbrahim Ethem misali
tacı tahtı terk edip
Shah Ibrahim Ethem. crown leave the throne.
Are you murad ?.
ermek midir muradın?
But to leave the post in this case.
Fakat bu demde makamı bırakıp gitmek
And the ones who trust you in the way. will leave and go.
sana güvenip yola revan olanları da
bırakıp gitmek olacaktır.
And the ones who trust you in the way. will leave and go.
You will perform your service at the palace.
Sen hizmetini sarayda ifa edeceksin.
What about the state of Islam?
Peki bu Âlem-i İslam'ın hâli ne olacak?
He owns the world. Allah is the owner of Islam.
O âlemin sahibi de
İslam'ın sahibi de Allah'tır.
He owns the world. Allah is the owner of Islam.
It's up to you.
Sana düşen
It is an effort in the way of right.
Hak yolunda gayrettir.
I've never been out of service.
Hizmetten asla yüksünmedim.
Wherever they were assigned. My head is on my eye.
Her nerede ne görev verildiyse
başım gözüm üstüne.
Wherever they were assigned. My head is on my eye.
Not that.
Lakin...
What is it that makes you eat?
Nedir seni yeise düşüren bu lakin?
Emir El Aziz is my nephew.
Emir El Aziz. Yeğenim.
He's like a child.
Bir çocuktan farksız.
It's not like I'm gettin 'his back. I did not make an effort.
Onun önünü arkasını toplamaktan gayrı
bir gayretim olmadı.
It's not like I'm gettin 'his back. I did not make an effort.
Not that.
Lakin
messengers bring new news day by day.
ulaklar gün be gün yeni haber getirmekte.
In the palace of the Abbasid Caliph. Harezmshah's payitaht.
Abbasi Halifesi'nin sarayında,
Harezmşahların payitahtında
In the palace of the Abbasid Caliph. Harezmshah's payitaht.
In Cairo, Baghdad.
Kahire'de, Bağdat'ta
Wherever ummah is concerned. If there is a vizier, a governor who is troubled.
her nerede ümmetin derdiyle
dertlenen bir vezir, bir vali varsa
Wherever ummah is concerned. If there is a vizier, a governor who is troubled.
one by two.
birer ikişer katledilmekte.
Who is who, even in our own palace. we know who serves whom.
Kendi sarayımızda dahi kim kimdir
kim kime hizmet eder bilemez olduk.
Who is who, even in our own palace. we know who serves whom.
This is what you count.
Bu saydıkların
from your duty. Is the excuse to stand back.
sana verilen vazifeden
geri durmak için bahane midir
from your duty. Is the excuse to stand back.
If you don't have to work more. Why?
yoksa daha fazla çalışmak için
sebep midir?
If you don't have to work more. Why?
After you're hard at work. God is your assistant.
Sen gayretinde sabit kadem olduktan sonra
Allah senin yardımcını da
After you're hard at work. God is your assistant.
And the people you're gonna help. will surely confront.
senin yardım edeceğin er kişileri de
mutlaka karşına çıkaracaktır.
And the people you're gonna help. will surely confront.
Sorry.
Efendim
if you command a poor himmet?
şu fakire bir himmet buyursanız?
Himmat ?.
The sooner the person says, &quot;Father, Himmet&quot;.
Er kişi dese ki "Baba, himmet."
They say to him, &quot;Son, service.&quot;
ona derler ki "Oğul, hizmet".
Keep in mind.
Unutma
believes in superstition.
inandığı batıl için kendinden vazgeçeni
A Muslim who cannot afford to fight for the truth. It makes the forensic divine.
Hak için savaşmayı göze alamayan Müslümana
galip kılar adl-i ilahi.
A Muslim who cannot afford to fight for the truth. It makes the forensic divine.
Son of God. waiting for you in your kingdom in paradise.
Tanrı'nın oğlu
seni cennetindeki krallığında bekliyor.
Son of God. waiting for you in your kingdom in paradise.
His troubles for our salvation. You took it for us.
Onun kurtuluşumuz için çektiği sıkıntıları
sen de bizim için çektin.
His troubles for our salvation. You took it for us.
What's inside?
İçindeki ne?
Argus.
This will bring you back to the Son of God.
Bu seni Tanrı'nın oğluna kavuşturacak.
The next time you see me. It's time to get to God.
Beni bir daha gördüğünde
Tanrı'ya kavuşma vakti gelmiş demektir.
The next time you see me. It's time to get to God.
[Street noise.
[Sokak gürültüsü
What is the status of the palace ?.
Nedir sarayın durumu?
Almost every position. we have placed one of us.
Hemen her mevkiye
bizden birilerini yerleştirmiş durumdayız.
Almost every position. we have placed one of us.
What about Atabey? Şahabettin.
-Peki ya Atabey?
-Şahabettin.
What about Atabey? Şahabettin.
His eyes are always on his nephew.
Gözleri sürekli yeğeninin üzerinde.
But.
Ama
I have plans about that.
onun hakkında da planlarım var.
Beautiful.
Güzel.
Soon all Muslim capitals. The raging death cries will rise.
Yakında tüm Müslüman başkentlerinden
canhıraş ölüm çığlıkları yükselecek.
Soon all Muslim capitals. The raging death cries will rise.
Everyone will ask for help from their neighbors.
Herkes komşularından yardım isteyecek.
Letters to Aleppo. your answers.
Halep'e gelen mektuplara
verilecek cevapların
Letters to Aleppo. your answers.
Saint's seal. But it's important to write with your pen.
Aziz'in mührüyle
ama senin kaleminle yazılması çok önemli.
Saint's seal. But it's important to write with your pen.
Without pulling the crusaders here.
Haçlı ordularını buraya çekmeden
of all Muslim palaces. We need to take over their communications.
tüm Müslüman saraylarının
muhaberelerini ele geçirmemiz lazım.
of all Muslim palaces. We need to take over their communications.
I understand, sir.
Anladım efendim. Merak buyurmayınız.
Unless you have another order. I would love to return to the palace.
Başka bir emriniz yoksa
saraya dönmek isterim.
Unless you have another order. I would love to return to the palace.
Don't let me go. What did you do with the apricot?
-Yokluğum fark edilmesin.
-Kayılarla ilgili işi ne yaptınız?
Don't let me go. What did you do with the apricot?
Suleyman Shah's obas.
Süleyman Şah'ın obasını
somewhere away from us. Can you move it ?.
bizden uzakta bir yere
taşıttırabilecek misin?
somewhere away from us. Can you move it ?.
When Atabey took care of Şahabettin.
Atabey Şahabettin'le ilgili işi halledince
that matter. The Lord will take care of himself.
o mesele de
kendiliğinden hallolacak Efendimiz.
that matter. The Lord will take care of himself.
Titus said something like that.
Titus da buna benzer şeyler söylemişti.
He said, &quot;The apricots will never come under our noses.&quot;
"Kayılar asla burnumuzun dibine
gelemeyecekler." demişti.
He said, &quot;The apricots will never come under our noses.&quot;
But today, tomorrow they are on their way.
Ama bugün, yarın yola koyuluyorlar.
Sir, the presence of apricots at the border. Why does it make you so nervous?
Efendim, Kayıların sınırdaki varlığı
neden sizi bu kadar tedirgin ediyor?
Sir, the presence of apricots at the border. Why does it make you so nervous?
He can take up to two thousand cavalry. why are you so worried for an oba ?.
En fazla iki bin süvari çıkartabilecek
bir oba için neden bu kadar endişelisiniz?
He can take up to two thousand cavalry. why are you so worried for an oba ?.
I am the way to Jerusalem from Antioch. Preparing for a new crusade.
Ben Antakya Kudüs yolunu
yeni bir Haçlı seferi için hazırlarken
I am the way to Jerusalem from Antioch. Preparing for a new crusade.
The last thing I want is holding a dorm around here. is a warrior Turkmen tribe.
istediğim en son şey bu civarda yurt tutan
savaşçı bir Türkmen kabilesidir.
The last thing I want is holding a dorm around here. is a warrior Turkmen tribe.
Today, if we let the apricots.
Bugün Kayılara göz yumarsak
they don't make us look tomorrow.
yarın göz açtırmazlar bize.
Remember Selahattin Eyyubi.
Selahattin Eyyubi'yi unutma!
He's from thousands of farms in Iraq. was born on a farm.
O Irak'taki binlerce çiftlikten
bir çiftlikte doğdu.
He's from thousands of farms in Iraq. was born on a farm.
Then Nurettin Zengi. became a soldier.
Sonra Nurettin Zengi'nin
komutasında asker oldu.
Then Nurettin Zengi. became a soldier.
Rises.
Yükseldi.
He was just a commander of hundreds of commanders.
Yüzlerce komutandan bir komutandı sadece.
Then you know.
Sonrasını biliyorsun.
If we could stop him on time.
Onu vaktiyle engelleyebilseydik
Jerusalem is still today. it would remain in our hands.
Kudüs bugün hâlâ
bizim ellerimizde kalırdı.
Jerusalem is still today. it would remain in our hands.
I'm with guys like you. I wouldn't have to.
Ben de senin gibi adamlarla
uğraşmak zorunda kalmazdım.
I'm with guys like you. I wouldn't have to.
I understand, Master.
Anladım Efendimiz.
Let them prepare the horses, Markus.
Atları hazırlasınlar Markus.
Back to the castle.
Kaleye dönüyoruz.
. Once in Baghdad.
Bir zamanlar Bağdat'ta
There was a famous carpenter.
ünlü bir marangoz varmış.
In the End Times of Your Life. It was a beautiful pulpit.
Ömrünün ahir zamanında
çok güzel bir minber oymuş.
In the End Times of Your Life. It was a beautiful pulpit.
But it's so beautiful.
Ama çok güzel.
Inlaid with mother of pearl.
Sedef kakmalı.
Walnut tree is adorable.
Ceviz ağacından. Alımlı mı alımlı.
All who saw him were fascinated by his beauty.
Her gören onun güzelliğiyle büyüleniyordu.
E is the name of this beautiful pulpit. took walked.
E bu güzel minberin namı
aldı yürüdü.
E is the name of this beautiful pulpit. took walked.
So that anyone who comes to Baghdad, go to him.
Öyle ki Bağdat'a her gelen, ona gidip
Let's get that pulpit to us.
"Şu minberi bize sat
falanca camiye götürelim."
Let's get that pulpit to us.
His answer is always the same.
Onun verdiği cevap da hep aynı.
He said no. &quot;This pulpit will stop at AlAqsa Mosque.&quot;
"Hayır." diyordu.
"Bu minber Mescid'i Aksa'da duracak."
He said no. &quot;This pulpit will stop at AlAqsa Mosque.&quot;
The people are surprised.
Ahali şaşırıyor tabii.
&quot;Well in Jerusalem, under the occupation of the Crusaders&quot;.
"İyi de Kudüs, Haçlı işgali altında."
Before joining the carpenter. always giving the same answer.
Marangoz yüksünmeden
hep aynı cevabı veriyordu.
Before joining the carpenter. always giving the same answer.
&quot;That's what I can do. I'm a craftsman.
"Benim elimden gelen bu.
Ben zanaatkarım.
&quot;That's what I can do. I'm a craftsman.
I carve a pulpit.
Minber yontarım.
Let a father grow up, Jerusalem. Let this pulpit sit down &quot;.
Bir babayiğit de çıksın, Kudüs'ü
geri alsın. Bu minberi yerine oturtsun."
Let a father grow up, Jerusalem. Let this pulpit sit down &quot;.
This is the story of the pulpit. There is no city left to speak.
Şöyle böyle derken bu minber hikâyesinin
konuşulmadığı hiçbir şehir kalmadı.
This is the story of the pulpit. There is no city left to speak.
Everyone, the beauty of the pulpit. one to five
Herkes minberin güzelliğini
bire beş katarak birbirine anlatırken
Everyone, the beauty of the pulpit. one to five
The same story. A child about seven to eight years old also heard.
aynı hikâyeyi
yedi sekiz yaşlarında bir çocuk da işitti.
The same story. A child about seven to eight years old also heard.
But it.
Ama o
rather than beauty of the work. he listened to the will of the enterprise.
eserin güzelliğinden ziyade
müessirin vasiyetine kulak verdi.
rather than beauty of the work. he listened to the will of the enterprise.
It's been 40 years.
Aradan 40 yıl geçti.
And that pulpit.
Ve o minberi
where it should stop. He placed the Masjid in Aqsa.
durması gereken yere,
Mescid'i Aksa'ya yerleştirdi.
where it should stop. He placed the Masjid in Aqsa.
The languages called him Selahattin Eyyubi.
Diller onu Selahattin Eyyubi diye andı.
This is how it works.
Bu işler böyledir.
We're like carpenters. we carve new pulpits.
Biz o marangoz misali
yeni minberler yontarız.
We're like carpenters. we carve new pulpits.
. He'll replace our trust .
Bizim emanetimizi yerine koyacak
sooner or later people will come out .
er kişiler elbette çıkacaktır.
Gundogdu.
Master?
Buyur usta?
I'm Suleyman Shah. He would be proud to see you in the toy.
Süleyman Şah'ım
seni toyda görseydi gurur duyardı.
I'm Suleyman Shah. He would be proud to see you in the toy.
I wanted to know. Thank you.
- Bil istedim.
-Eyvallah.
I wanted to know. Thank you.
We'll cut this circle of fire together.
Bu ateş çemberini birlikte yaracağız.
Remember, you're his son.
Unutma, sen onun oğlusun.
The original wolf is the wolf.
Aslı kurt olanın nesli de kurt olur.
Mr. Gündoğdu.
Gündoğdu Bey'im.
No, it's Akcakoca ?.
Hayırdır Akçakoca?
I have things to talk to you about.
Seninle konuşmam gereken şeyler var.
I aykız.
Aykız'ım
Gökçe is not the state of the girl.
Gökçe kızın hâli hâl değildir.
His problem has exceeded his height. but he still shuts up, doesn't talk.
Derdi boyunu aştı
ama hâlâ susar, konuşmaz.
His problem has exceeded his height. but he still shuts up, doesn't talk.
He's afraid of me.
Benden de çekinir.
Why don't you talk?
Sen bir konuşsan?
I'll see you too, Mother.
Ben de görürüm Hayme Ana.
But you know.
Ama sen de bilirsin
I don't have the cure for his troubles.
onun derdinin dermanı bende değildir.
I know.
Bilirim.
Bilirim de
I know.
Gökçe girl resembles her deceased mother.
Gökçe kız, rahmetli anasına benzer.
Smolder.
İçin için yanar.
But not so quiet. That's not a good thing.
Ama bu kadar susmak da
iyi bir şey değil ki.
But not so quiet. That's not a good thing.
I aykız.
Aykız'ım.
Gokce.
I'll help you.
Ben de sana yardım edeyim.
There's not much left.
Çok bir şey kalmadı zaten.
You are now Mr. Ertugrul. you're upset.
Sen şimdi Ertuğrul Bey'i
suçlarlar diye üzülürsün.
You are now Mr. Ertugrul. you're upset.
Do not be sad.
Üzülme.
The truth is, of course, revealed.
Gerçek elbet ortaya çıkar.
Sure, take it off.
Çıkar elbet.
Let's hope they get better.
Dua edelim onlar iyi olsunlar.
We couldn't say goodbye while Turgut was leaving.
Turgut yola çıkarken vedalaşamadık.
Something bad inside me. It feels like it will be.
İçimde kötü bir şeyler
olacakmış gibi bir his var.
Something bad inside me. It feels like it will be.
He's always on my mind.
Aklım hep onda.
Hope, even your biggest fears. Aykız is the drug.
Umut, en büyük korkuların bile
ilacıdır Aykız.
Hope, even your biggest fears. Aykız is the drug.
You know, too.
Sen de bilirsin.
Turgut will return to obaya.
Turgut, obaya dönecek.
It'll be back to oba, back to you.
Obaya dönmesi, sana dönmesi olacak.
You'll reunite.
Sevdiğine kavuşacaksın.
But the distance between me and Ertuğrul. roads are not.
Ama Ertuğrul'la benim aramdaki mesafeler
yollar değil.
But the distance between me and Ertuğrul. roads are not.
If he turns that way.
O yoldan dönse
If it sits here. I'll stay at the furthest again.
şuracığa otursa,
ben yine en uzağında kalacağım.
If it sits here. I'll stay at the furthest again.
Behind the impenetrable mountains. like looking at a sun.
Aşılmaz dağların ardındaki
bir güneşe bakar gibi
Behind the impenetrable mountains. like looking at a sun.
I will look at her from afar.
ona uzaktan bakacağım.
cause of famine first. I thought it was nothing.
önce kıtlıktan sebep
önemsiz bir maraz sandım.
cause of famine first. I thought it was nothing.
But the situation is grave.
Lakin vaziyet vahimdir.
What is your opinion?
Nedir kanaatin?
Plague.
Veba.
Plague?
Veba mı?
What do we have to do?
Ne yapmamız icap eder?
I swear to God, I have wandered the whole obe.
Vallahi Beyim, bütün obayı dolaştım,
diseased animals. individually marked with red ink.
hastalıklı hayvanları
tek tek kırmızı mürekkeple işaretledim.
diseased animals. individually marked with red ink.
. Then I put it all here.
Sonra hepsini burada topladım.
If we cull it all.
Şayet hepsini itlaf edersek
Allahu universe will prevent this disaster.
Allah-ü Âlem bu felaketi önleriz.
Hopefully, Akcakoca, hopefully.
İnşallah Akçakoca, inşallah.
I hope, sir.
İnşallah Beyim.
Do what we need to do.
Ne yapmamız icap ederse yap.
Find someone with a tight mouth for this job.
Bu iş için ağzı sıkı birini bul.
It's complicated.
Zaten ortalık karışık
and a catastrophe. obada
bir de felaket tellalları
dolaşmasın obada.
and a catastrophe. obada
I hope it's good.
Hayırdır inşallah.
Thank you, sir.
Eyvallah Beyim.
It's too complicated.
Ortalık zaten çok karışık.
Why me here. Call Selcan Hatun ?.
Neden beni buraya
çağırtırsın Selcan Hatun?
Why me here. Call Selcan Hatun ?.
What worries you when you see me, Kurdoğlu ?.
Beni gördüğüne ne telaşlanırsın Kurdoğlu?
When you wake up, Solomon Shah. Think of what you will do.
Sen asıl Süleyman Şah uyanınca
ne yapacaksın, onu düşün.
When you wake up, Solomon Shah. Think of what you will do.
Not my father, not his father. This is the problem of the husband trying to benefit.
Benim değil, babasının yokluğundan
faydalanmaya çalışan kocanın derdidir bu.
Not my father, not his father. This is the problem of the husband trying to benefit.
You made me believe in the toy. You're a gentleman.
Sen beni toyda inandırdığın
beylerden belledin.
You made me believe in the toy. You're a gentleman.
I don't know what you're up to.
Ne işler karıştırdığını bilmez miyim?
And don't waste your breath on me.
Boşuna nefesini tüketme de bana de hele
You took care of Gündoğdu.
Gündoğdu'yu toyda hallettin
What the hell are you gonna do when Solomon Shah wakes up?
Süleyman Şah uyanınca ne halt edeceksin?
Don't worry about it, Selcan Hatun. I'll find a way.
Sen buna kafanı yorma Selcan Hatun.
Ben bir yolunu bulurum.
Don't worry about it, Selcan Hatun. I'll find a way.
Suleyman Shah will leave tomorrow.
Süleyman Şah yarın yola çıkacaktır.
They'll go to Aleppo to find some trouble.
Halep'e derdine derman bulmaya gidecekler.
If he gets up again. Then think about it.
Eğer tekrar ayağa kalkarsa
sen o zaman düşün.
If he gets up again. Then think about it.
What do you mean?
Ne demeye getirirsin?
Open up your heart, and you'll have to eat it.
Gönlündeki sözü tastamam açık et hele.
Bed scorched in flames. Suleyman Shah.
Yatağında ateşler içinde kavrulan
Süleyman Şah'ımız
Bed scorched in flames. Suleyman Shah.
maazaLLah ,. If tonight had the mercy of Hakk.
maazallah,
bu gece Hakk'ın rahmetine kavuşsa
maazaLLah ,. If tonight had the mercy of Hakk.
even I know it from the Grim Reaper.
ben bile Azrail'den bilirim bunu.
Condolences. I cry at the grave.
Taziyesini tutar,
mezarının başında ağlarım.
Condolences. I cry at the grave.
How will this work ?.
Nasıl olacak bu iş?
This night.
Bu gece
Gündoğdu and Mother Hayme. away from the tent.
Gündoğdu'yu ve Hayme Ana'yı
çadırdan uzaklaştıracağım.
Gündoğdu and Mother Hayme. away from the tent.
The rest is up to you.
Gerisi sana kalmış.
If Suleyman Shah dies. I will avenge my father.
Süleyman Şah ölürse
ben babamın intikamını almış olacağım
If Suleyman Shah dies. I will avenge my father.
You will be Kayi's lord.
sen de Kayı'nın beyi olacaksın.
At the invitation of Master Titus. 30 knights have been sent.
Efendi Titus'un çağrısı üzerine
30 şövalye gönderildi.
At the invitation of Master Titus. 30 knights have been sent.
Master, in your room. You have guests from the Vatican.
Efendimiz, odanızda
Vatikan'dan gelen misafiriniz var.
Master, in your room. You have guests from the Vatican.
He's waiting for you.
Sizi bekliyor.
My dear friend Petruccio.
Sevgili dostum Petruccio.
Cardinal Thomas, what an honor to see you.
Kardinal Thomas, sizi görmek ne şeref.
I wish you'd let us know your future.
Keşke haber verseydiniz geleceğinizi.
I didn't want to interrupt your Aleppo getaway.
Halep kaçamağınızı bölmek istemedim.
The sight of our Holy Father. You continue to be the hearing ear.
Kutsal Baba'mızın gören gözü
işiten kulağı olmaya devam ediyorsunuz.
The sight of our Holy Father. You continue to be the hearing ear.
His Holiness. appreciates your work.
Papa Hazretleri
çalışmalarınızı takdir ediyor
His Holiness. appreciates your work.
but they have doubts about you.
ama sana karşı şüpheleri var.
Crusades. to start again.
Haçlı Seferleri'nin
yeniden başlayabilmesi için
Crusades. to start again.
persuasion.
ikna edilmesi gerekiyor.
How can you be convinced ?.
Nasıl ikna olabilecek?
That infidel Muhammad stole from us. you must take back the sacred relics.
O kafir Muhammedilerin bizden çaldığı
kutsal emanetleri geri almalısın.
That infidel Muhammad stole from us. you must take back the sacred relics.
Guess who has the relics. You know very well.
Sanırım emanetlerin kimde olduğunu
gayet iyi biliyorsun.
Guess who has the relics. You know very well.
Hello Brother.
Merhaba kardeşim.
Brother, huh?
Kardeş, ha?
Very wrong, too.
Çok yanlış, çok.
Our mother. I remember the day he had you.
Annemizin
seni doğurduğu günü hatırlıyorum da...
Our mother. I remember the day he had you.
Pity, brothers to each other. should not behave like this.
Yazık, kardeşler birbirine
böyle davranmamalı.
Pity, brothers to each other. should not behave like this.
Get out of here.
Defol git buradan!
Not just your brother.
Sadece kardeşini değil
You destroyed your whole family in pieces.
tüm aileni parça parça ettin.
Was it worth it?
Değer miydi buna?
You're stalking a Bedouin.
Takıldın bir Bedevinin peşine
wife, children, case. You destroyed everything with your own hands.
eşini, çocuklarını, davanı
her şeyi yok ettin kendi ellerinle.
wife, children, case. You destroyed everything with your own hands.
But we're brothers.
Ama biz kardeşiz.
If that's what Ibn'larabi thought to me. if you can bring back our relics.
Eğer bana İbnü'l-Arabî'nin sandığındaki
emanetlerimizi geri getirebilirsen
If that's what Ibn'larabi thought to me. if you can bring back our relics.
I can give you your family.
ben de sana aileni bahşedebilirim.
That I could betray my sheik. Do you still have hope?
Şeyhime ihanet edebileceğime dair
hâlâ umudun var mı?
That I could betray my sheik. Do you still have hope?
Don't ever talk to me about loyalty again.
Bana bir daha sadakatten bahsetme.
Leave the son of God.
Tanrının oğlunu terk edip
Selling the Knights Templar.
Mabet Şövalyeleri'ni satarken
how loyal he is. You prove it.
ne denli sadık biri olduğunu
ispatlamıştın.
how loyal he is. You prove it.
Why don't you do the same now?
Aynını neden şimdi de yapmayasın?
I promise you.
Sana söz veriyorum
Our relics in that chest. if you can bring it back.
o sandıktaki emanetlerimizi
geri getirebilirsen
Our relics in that chest. if you can bring it back.
you can have your whole family again.
tüm ailene kavuşabilirsin yeniden.
I know you don't trust me anymore.
Bana artık güvenmediğini biliyorum.
To show me you can trust me.
Bana güvenebileceğini göstermek için
You midnight tonight. I can meet your little girl.
seni bu gece yarısı
küçük kızınla buluşturabilirim.
You midnight tonight. I can meet your little girl.
Is my Elenora here?
Elenora'm burada mı?
Beautiful.
Güzel.
All birds in the same cage.
Bütün kuşlar aynı kafeste.
Gökçe, you go to bed. OK, sister.
-Gökçe, sen de yat artık.
-Tamam abla.
Gökçe, you go to bed. OK, sister.
Run Run Run Call Mother.
Koş! Koş Hayme Ana'yı çağır.
Get Mother Hayme.
Hayme Ana'yı çağır!
Sunrise, something's happening.
Gündoğdu, bir şey oluyor.
Gündoğdu, bir şey oluyor!
Sunrise, something's happening.
All right, chick, all right, be patient. I'm taking the midwife chick.
Tamam hatun, tamam, sabret.
Ebe hatunu alıp geliyorum.
All right, chick, all right, be patient. I'm taking the midwife chick.
Thesis.
Tez yetiş!
Hayme Ana. Come on, girl.
-Hayme Ana.
-Gel kızım.
Hayme Ana. Come on, girl.
Gökçe, what is this rush? What happened?.
Gökçe, ne bu telaşın? Ne oldu?
Mother Hayme, my sister's in pain. He told me to call you.
Hayme Ana'm, ablamın sancısı tuttu.
Seni çağırmamı söyledi.
Mother Hayme, my sister's in pain. He told me to call you.
I hope it's good.
Hayırdır inşallah.
Akcakoca, midwife chick, destur?
Akçakoca, ebe hatun, destur var mıdır?
Here, Mr. Bey Akçakoca went somewhere.
Buyur Beyim. Akçakoca bir yerlere çıktı.
There's nothing bad, I hope. No no.
-Kötü bir şey yoktur inşallah.
-Yok yok.
There's nothing bad, I hope. No no.
Selcan's in pain. we need to go to the tent.
Selcan'ın sancısı tuttu,
tez çadıra gitmemiz lazım.
Selcan's in pain. we need to go to the tent.
Let me put some clothes on.
Üzerime bir şeyler giyip geleyim.
Is Selcan Hatun pregnant? Hopefully, come on, come on.
-Selcan Hatun gebe midir Beyim?
-İnşallah. Hadi, hadi.
Is Selcan Hatun pregnant? Hopefully, come on, come on.
My daughter. I can't stand it, Mother.
-Kızım.
-Dayanamıyorum ana!
My daughter. I can't stand it, Mother.
Come.
Gel.
Calm down, girl, calm down.
Sakin ol kızım, sakin ol.
Ah. Let me see.
-Ah!
-Ben bir bakayım.
Ah. Let me see.
Okay, take it easy.
Tamam, sakin ol. Ben bir bakayım.
Making.
Yapma!
Oh, come on.
Yapma! Ah!
I hope no.
Hayırlar olsun inşallah.
Do not do like that.
Öyle yapma!
Is my father alone?
Bey babam yalnız mı kaldı ana?
No, you have the most gracious.
Hayır, Rahman var yanında. Merak etme sen.
You go to my father Gundogdu ,. Don't be alone.
Sen de git babamın yanına Gündoğdu,
yalnız kalmasın.
You go to my father Gundogdu ,. Don't be alone.
I said go.
Git dedim.
The Kurdoğlu.
You have passed the test of Mertlik.
Mertlik imtihanını geçtiniz.
Wolves, bears.
Kurtlarla, ayılarla
dangers of life and death. You fought, you returned to oban.
her türlü ölüm kalım tehlikeleriyle
savaştınız, obanıza döndünüz.
dangers of life and death. You fought, you returned to oban.
No more alpine. You have the right to carry with honor.
Artık alplik unvanını
şerefle taşımaya hakkınız vardır.
No more alpine. You have the right to carry with honor.
But now the lesson you need to take. more important than all these difficulties.
Lakin şimdi almanız gereken ders,
tüm bu zorluklardan daha mühimdir.
But now the lesson you need to take. more important than all these difficulties.
Alplik does not saturate the abdomen in the absence.
Alplik, yoklukta karın doyurmak değil
The challenge is to stand upright.
zorlukta dik durmaktır.
Suleyman Shah.
Süleyman Şah
Kurdoğlu, Alp Sungur.
Take an arrow from your shavers.
tirkeşlerinizden birer ok alın.
Break.
Kırın!
Your tirkes. Take another arrow and give it to me.
Tirkeşlerinizden
birer ok daha alıp bana verin.
Your tirkes. Take another arrow and give it to me.
Here you follow the advice of the horse. unity.
İşte siz de ata öğüdüne uyup
birlik olursanız
Here you follow the advice of the horse. unity.
You will not break like these arrows.
bu oklar gibi kırılmazsınız.
Informal after that. never leave your name and body.
Gayrı bundan sonra
isminiz de cisminiz de hiç ayrılmasın.
Informal after that. never leave your name and body.
Let those who remember you all together.
Ananlar, sizi hep birlikte ansınlar.