Why is this place dark?
Burası neden karanlık?
Rahman.
Here you go, sir.
Buyur beyim.
Why aren't these oil lamps burning, Rahman?
Bu kandiller neden yanmıyor Rahman?
I don't know, sir.
Bilmiyorum beyim.
You will not know if the apocalypse breaks.
Kıyamet kopsa haberiniz olmayacak!
Bey.
Beyim.
Find something and close that crevasse. Okay, sir.
-Bir şeyler bulup şu yarığı kapat.
-Tamam beyim.
Find something and close that crevasse. Okay, sir.
What happened here. Nobody will know.
Burada olanlardan
hiç kimsenin haberi olmayacak.
What happened here. Nobody will know.
Don't leave my father for a moment.
Babamın yanından bir an bile ayrılma.
Yes, sir.
Emredersin beyim.
Luckily, they were signs of pain.
Çok şükür hayra alamet sancılarmış.
So, motherfuckers.
Ee, analığın başı zahmet,
the end is mercy.
sonu da rahmettir.
You made us all happy in this tight time.
Bu dar zamanda hepimizi mutlu ettin.
Oh, my God. God willing to take us in our arms.
Allah’ım sağ salim
kucağımıza almayı nasip eder inşallah.
Oh, my God. God willing to take us in our arms.
God willing, mother.
İnşallah ana.
My father is at thesis time. he'll be glad if he regains his health.
Bey babam da tez vakitte
sağlığına kavuşursa sevinecektir.
My father is at thesis time. he'll be glad if he regains his health.
Doesn't he rejoice?
Sevinmez mi hiç?
How long have we been watching the grandchildren?
Kaç zamandır torun yolu gözler dururduk.
Sure will.
Sevinir elbet.
My sister.
Ablam.
Gökçe.
Gökçe’m.
Gundogdu.
Son, our eyes are bright.
Oğul, gözümüz aydın.
Selcan bride conceived.
Selcan gelin gebe.
Line up, boy, line up.
Boyumuza soy, soyumuza bey olur inşallah.
God willing.
İnşallah.
Thanks, mother.
Sağ ol, var ol ana.
Happy birthday, my master.
Kutlu olsun ağam.
Thank you, Gokce Hatun.
Sağ ol Gökçe Hatun.
If you hadn't put my father alone.
Bey babamı yalnız koymasaydın.
She's not alone, she's with Rahman.
Yalnız değil hatun, Rahman yanında.
You be good and don't worry.
Sen iyi ol da. Merak etme.
Look at the bitch. First he sent me to the tent.
Kancığa bak hele!
Önce beni çadıra yolladı,
Look at the bitch. First he sent me to the tent.
And then he released her husband upon me.
sonra da üzerime kocasını saldı.
He killed Suleiman Shah.
Süleyman Şah’ı öldürtüp
his father, Alp Sungur. He wanted revenge.
babası Alp Sungur’un
intikamını almak istemiş demek.
his father, Alp Sungur. He wanted revenge.
When you think of me. He was going to feed Gündoğdu.
Aklınca beni de
Gündoğdu’ya yem edecekti.
When you think of me. He was going to feed Gündoğdu.
Two birds with one stone.
Bir taşla iki kuş.
We couldn't account for the bitch's game.
Kancığın oyununu hesap edemedik.
When the wolf was a husband, it would be the dog's jerk.
Kurt kocayınca köpeğin maskarası olurmuş.
What do you say, Alpargu, are we husbands?
Ne dersin Alpargu, kocadık mı yoksa?
My heart doesn't stand these sounds. I wish we had killed and burned Akçakoca.
Bu seslere yüreğim dayanmıyor.
Keşke öldürüp yaksaydık Akçakoca.
My heart doesn't stand these sounds. I wish we had killed and burned Akçakoca.
This disease is what you know. not from diseases, son.
Bu hastalık senin bildiğin
hastalıklardan değil evlat.
This disease is what you know. not from diseases, son.
You touched the flesh and blood of these animals. Does all the oba is ruined, it becomes a waste.
Bu hayvanların etine, kanına dokundun
mu bütün oba mahvolur, telef olur.
You touched the flesh and blood of these animals. Does all the oba is ruined, it becomes a waste.
Our Holy Mother.
Kutsal Ana’mız,
Give me a light to illuminate me.
bana içimi aydınlatacak bir ışık ver.
If my father is alive and I can get him back.
Babam yaşıyorsa ve ona kavuşabileceksem
Show me a sign.
bana bir işaret göster.
Altes, are you here?
Altes, burada mısınız?
Amen.
To me to learn the truth. You said you were ready.
Bana gerçekleri öğrenmeye
hazır olduğunuzu söylemiştiniz.
To me to learn the truth. You said you were ready.
Then come with me.
Benimle gelin o hâlde.
.
This place? Yeah.
-Burası mı?
-Evet.
This place? Yeah.
You've never seen me, Altes.
Beni hiç görmediniz Altes.
Is my father behind this door?
Babam bu kapının ardında mı?
Father.
Baba!
My daughter?.
Kızım?
Father.
Baba!
My daughter.
Kızım!
Father….
Baba…
Father. My daughter.
-Baba!
-Kızım!
Father. My daughter.
Dad, it's yours for years. I thought he was killed.
Baba, yıllarca senin
öldürüldüğünü zannediyordum.
Dad, it's yours for years. I thought he was killed.
You've been on my mind for years.
Yıllardır hep aklımdaydınız.
My hope of meeting you has kept me alive.
Size kavuşma umudum beni hayatta tuttu.
Dad, why are you here?
Baba, neden buradasın?
Your mother, your sister, you.
Annen, ablan, sen,
every night you're in my dreams.
her gece rüyalarımdasınız.
My mother.
Annem.
What happened to your mother, girl?
Annene ne oldu kızım?
Dad, why are they keeping you here?
Baba, seni neden burada tutuyorlar?
Does my uncle know you're here?
Amcam senin burada olduğunu biliyor mu?
Talk to him and see you. I'll get it out of here right now.
Onunla konuşup seni
buradan hemen çıkartacağım.
Talk to him and see you. I'll get it out of here right now.
My daughter.
Kızım!
Father.
Baba!
My daughter.
Kızım!
Father. My daughter.
-Baba!
-Kızım!
Father. My daughter.
Baby.
Yavrum!
I Elenora.
Elenora’m!
Baby.
Yavrum!
I Elenora.
Elenora’m!
Medet or Lord.
Medet ya Rab!
Velhasıl Ertuğrul Bey ,. As the bard says:.
Velhasıl Ertuğrul Bey’im,
ozanın da dediği gibi:
Velhasıl Ertuğrul Bey ,. As the bard says:.
I'm burned, done, burned .
Yandım, bittim, kül oldum
I'm the path to the troubled .
Dertlilere yol oldum
I was a servant, I became a servant .
Şahbaz idim, kul oldum
Thanks to the fire of love .
Şol aşkın ateşiyle
Excuse me, sir.
İzninle beyim.
It's your turn to watch.
Nöbet sırası sendedir.
I could not sleep.
Uyku tutmadı.
Halime.
You know,.
Bilirsin,
There are a thousand kinds of trouble.
bin türlü derdin vardır ama
in the strength of its strength.
dermanı gücünde,
power is also in the faith.
gücün de imanındadır.
But there is one of your troubles ,.
Ama bir tanesi var ki dertlerin,
both are the most beautiful.
hem en güzelidir
… It also burns my heart.
…hem de yüreğimi yakar.
You're the only one who has the cure.
Onun da dermanı sadece sendedir.
That beautifuleyed gazelle.
O güzel gözlü ceylan ki
It took me, it got in the way.
beni aldı, yoluna kattı.
He brought it to you and threw it in love.
Senin yanına getirip aşka attı.
I was just about to take his life.
Ben tam onun canını almaya meyletmiştim ki
Burned my heart with love fire.
yüreğimi aşk ateşiyle yaktı.
I don't mean that.
Demem o ki...
Ever since I first saw you.
...ben seni ilk gördüğüm günden beri...
Don't say Ertugrul, shut up.
Deme Ertuğrul, sus!
I shut up.
Susmam!
You with my own hands. I can't send it away from me.
Seni kendi ellerimle
benden uzaklara yollayamam.
You with my own hands. I can't send it away from me.
Go.
Gitme.
Stay with me.
Benimle kal.
Queen of my heart,.
Gönlümün sultanı,
mother of my children,.
çocuklarımın anası,
Be the candle of my life.
ömrümün candaşı ol.
Brave, honest, kindhearted. You are a brave man.
Cesur, dürüst, güzel yürekli
bir yiğitsin sen Ertuğrul Bey.
Brave, honest, kindhearted. You are a brave man.
What we owe you is no longer one, get on.
Sana can borcumuz artık bir değil, bindir.
But my destiny is long written.
Ama benim kaderim çok önceden yazılmıştır.
My father and my brother. I can't go after the love.
Babamı ve kardeşimi meçhule
bırakıp sevda peşinden gidemem.
My father and my brother. I can't go after the love.
Not even the sultan of the palace I was born in.
Doğduğum sarayın bile sultanı olamamışken
I cannot be the sultan of your heart.
senin yüreğinin sultanı olamam.
That's what your language says.
Bunu dilin söyler.
What about your heart?
Ya yüreğin?
What's your heart, Halime?
Yüreğin ne der Halime?
Whatever my tongue says. that is what my heart says.
Dilim ne söylerse
yüreğimin de söylediği odur.
Whatever my tongue says. that is what my heart says.
Go.
Gitme!
Ah.
Halime.
Halime. Halime ?.
Halima? Halime ?.
Ah.
Halime Halime my daughter.
Halime. Halime kızım.
Take the back.
Ayrılın! Arkayı tut.
We'll meet in Aleppo.
Ayrılalım, Halep'te buluşuruz.
Let's split up.
Ayrılalım.
Halime.
Ah.
Sister. Come on, lion, come on.
-Abla!
- Hadi aslanım, hadi!
Sister. Come on, lion, come on.
Sister. Let's.
-Abla!
- Hadi!
Sister. Let's.
Sister. Come on, we're going.
- Abla!
-Hadi yürü, gidiyoruz.
Sister. Come on, we're going.
Come on, go, go, go.
Hadi hadi, yürü yürü!
Sir, they're on the run.
Efendim, kaçıyorlar.
Ertuğrul is already trapped.
Ertuğrul zaten kapana kısıldı.
Let's catch the little prince. Let's please Master.
Küçük şehzadeyi yakalayalım
da Üstad'ı memnun edelim.
Let's catch the little prince. Let's please Master.
Horses.
Atlara!
Ihr. Ah.
-Ih!
-Ah!
Ihr. Ah.
Ah.
AA.
You go on, prince, I'll catch up.
Siz devam edin şehzadem, ben yetişirim.
Come on come on.
Hadi! Hadi!
Oh, Ah.
Ihr.
Ih!
Ha Ha Ha.
Ah.
HeyTim.
Heyt!
. Sir, you catch up, we'll watch your back.
Beyim sen yetiş, biz arkanı kollarız.
Come on, horses.
Haydi atlara!
That bitch called Selcan. I will regret your birth, Yiva.
Selcan denen o kancığı
doğduğuna pişman edeceğim Yiva.
That bitch called Selcan. I will regret your birth, Yiva.
What he did to me. the game will pay very heavy penalty.
Bana yaptığı
oyunun cezasını çok ağır ödeyecek.
What he did to me. the game will pay very heavy penalty.
I'm gonna breathe like a deadline.
Ecel gibi ensesinde soluyacağım.
Selcan's game is over, sir.
Selcan'ın oyunu biter mi beyim?
It's like a flame ball.
Alev topu gibi gezer obada.
Flame of fire wherever he wants.
Nerede isterse orada harlar alevi.
My name is Kurdoğlu.
Benim adım da Kurdoğlu'ysa
I know how to turn that flame into ashes.
o alevi küle döndürmesini bilirim.
Those two living bitches. You will take a life, Yiva.
O iki canlı kancığın
bir canını alacaksın Yiva.
Those two living bitches. You will take a life, Yiva.
Unable to hold the child in your belly.
Karnındaki çocuğu kucağına alamadan,
I gave the grandchildren to the gentleman.
bey soyuna torun verdim diye salınamadan
that baby will die.
o bebek ölecek!
Get out of here.
Çekil şuradan!
Hennaed.
Kınalı!
I brought you water, get up.
Sana su getirdim, kalk!
My father ,.
Babamı,
Did you kill Baybora?
Baybora'yı sen mi öldürdün?
Here you go, girl.
Al bakalım kızım.
Good luck with.
Kolay gelsin!
Easy, baby sister.
Kolay gele bacım.
By Allah's leave, we are ready, Mr. Gundogdu.
Allah'ın izniyle biz hazırız Gündoğdu Bey.
No, sir.
Hayırdır beyim?
Disgusting.
Yüreğini bulandıran,
Is there something bothering you?
canını sıkan bir şey mi var?
Dangerous Crazy Iron around.
Etraf tehlikeli Deli Demir.
You get off the road. I give reliable alps when leaving.
Siz obadan yola
çıkarken güvenilir alpleri yanına veririm.
You get off the road. I give reliable alps when leaving.
You're a son.
Bey oğlusun.
Dursun Bey.
Beysin.
Of course everything to me. you dont have to say.
Elbet bana her şeyi
söylemek zorunda değilsin.
Of course everything to me. you dont have to say.
But it's me. If there is something I need to know.
Ama benim
bilmem gereken bir şey varsa
But it's me. If there is something I need to know.
Tell me, don't you, mister?
söylersin değil mi beyim?
Always. I say it's good to be cautious, sir.
Her daim
temkinli olmak iyidir derim beyim.
Always. I say it's good to be cautious, sir.
Now blowing the cloud above us. we can't even trust the wind.
Artık tepemizdeki buluta, esen
rüzgâra bile güvenemez olduk.
Now blowing the cloud above us. we can't even trust the wind.
Come on, you too. Start your own preparations.
Hadi neyse, sen de
kendi hazırlıklarına başla.
Come on, you too. Start your own preparations.
Don't say that, sir.
Öyle deme beyim.
Man like me. What about preparation?
Benim gibi adamın
hazırlığından ne olacak ki?
Man like me. What about preparation?
I just need to say goodbye to someone.
Sadece birisiyle vedalaşmam lazım.
I'll get him out of the way.
Vakit varken ben de onu aradan çıkarayım.
Valiant.
Yiğit!
Ah.
Valiant.
Yiğit!
Hayti.
Hayt!
You killed my father, Baybora?
Babamı, Baybora'yı sen mi öldürdün?
Baybora was like my brother.
Baybora benim kardeşim gibiydi.
Your father for this obada principality. those who saw us in danger killed us.
Babanı bu obada beyliği için
bizi tehlike görenler öldürdü.
Your father for this obada principality. those who saw us in danger killed us.
What do you mean?.
Ne demek istiyorsun?
Understand.
Anlasana artık!
The murderer of your father is Süleyman Şah.
Babanın katili Süleyman Şah'tır.
The gentleman, the king knows. What we crowned on our heads.
Bey deyip, şah bilip
başımıza taç ettiklerimiz
The gentleman, the king knows. What we crowned on our heads.
Will it mean to us, Father?
canımıza kasıt eder mi baba?
But if I'm your son. I won't put this with them.
Ama ben de senin oğlunsam
bunu onlarını yanına koymam.
But if I'm your son. I won't put this with them.
Euzu billahi is a goodlooking demon. Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
Euzu billahi mineş şeytanir racim.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
Euzu billahi is a goodlooking demon. Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
Amine.
Âmin.
I'm leaving, Aybala.
Ben gidiyorum Aybala'm.
I will migrate again.
Yine göç olacak.
The caravan's straight.
Kervan düzüldü bile.
But this time.
Ama bu sefer
You will not be in this caravan.
bu kervanda sen olmayacaksın.
You'll never see our new home.
Yeni yurdumuzu hiç göremeyeceksin.
The first job, when Oba was established. We will marry Aykız.
Oba kurulduğunda ilk iş,
Aykız'ımızı evlendireceğiz.
The first job, when Oba was established. We will marry Aykız.
That day.
O gün
I.
ben
I'll secretly cry in a nook corner.
gizlice bir kuytu köşede ağlayacağım.
Because you're not with me.
Sen yanımda olmadığın için
You won't wipe my tears.
gözyaşımı silemeyeceksin.
When the day comes. She 's gonna give me a grandchild.
Aykız günü geldiğinde
bana bir torun verecek.
When the day comes. She 's gonna give me a grandchild.
You're that baby. You can't keep your hands on the bump.
Sen o bebenin
yamru yumru ellerini tutamayacaksın.
You're that baby. You can't keep your hands on the bump.
Just me.
Benim
harp seen ,.
harp görmüş,
I've seen my heart.
garp görmüş yüreğim
he'll be even more tired than you.
sensizlikten daha da yorulacak.
But no one.
Ama hiç kimse...
Come on, Master Demir.
...hadi Demir Usta,
stand up,.
kalk ayağa,
If you're not this oba. who pusatlar alpine.
sen olmazsan bu obanın
alplerini kim pusatlandırır
If you're not this oba. who pusatlar alpine.
I will not say.
demeyecek.
But this is the world itself. Isn't it a temporary barracks?
Ama bu cihanın kendisi de
geçici bir kışla değil mi Aybala'm?
But this is the world itself. Isn't it a temporary barracks?
I also emigrate when the day comes and time is reached.
Günü gelip vakit eriştiğinde ben de göç
I will meet with the caravan in the real homeland.
kervanıyla hakiki yurda kavuşacağım.
We'll get it that day.
O gün kavuşacağız ya,
That's enough to know, Aybala.
bunu bilmek yeter Aybala'm.
I saw an eye open.
Göz açıp da gördüğüm,
love and love chick.
gönül verip sevdiğim hatun.
Until then, you. Under this cold soil.
O zamana kadar sen
bu soğuk toprağın altındayken...
Until then, you. Under this cold soil.
I'm out of the iron. I will be cold even in the face.
...ben harlı demir ocağının
karşısında dahi üşüyor olacağım.
I'm out of the iron. I will be cold even in the face.
. I wanted to know that you entrust to Allah.
Bunu bil istedim. Allah'a emanet ol.
My condolences, son.
Başın sağ olsun evlat.
. The state of the world, the twodoor inn.
Dünya hâli işte, iki kapılı han.
Thank you Iron Master.
Eyvallah Demir Usta.
World innkeeper, we passengers.
Dünya hancı, biz yolcu.
The food bite will take. Breathing ends entering the black soil.
Yiyecek lokması, alacak
nefesi biten giriyor kara toprağın altına.
The food bite will take. Breathing ends entering the black soil.
You're right, Bozok.
Haklısın Bozok.
May Allah increase your patience.
Allah sabrını artırsın.
Anyway, I'll see you at the barracks.
Neyse, kışlakta görüşürüz.
Soundly.
Selametle.
You will be well, Master Demir.
Sağlıcakla Demir Usta.
You have a nice way.
Yolunuz açık olsun.
Valiant. Approach.
-Yiğit!
- Yaklaşma!
Valiant. Approach.
Drop the ax, I'll cut the boy's throat.
Bırak baltayı, keserim çocuğun gırtlağını!
.
Connect.
Bağlayın!
Home.
Ho!
We need to accelerate, prince.
Hızlanmamız lazım şehzadem.
Shaken on a horse. Bleeding is increasing Ertugrul.
At üstünde sarsıldıkça
kanaması artıyor Ertuğrul.
Shaken on a horse. Bleeding is increasing Ertugrul.
Let's stop over there.
Şurada duralım.
Ihr.
Ih!
Ertugrul on ,.
Ertuğrullar,
you've caught them.
onları yakaladınız...
is not it?.
...değil mi?
Sir, Ertugrullar.
Efendim, Ertuğrullar...
Did you lose them?
Onları elinizden kaçırdınız mı?
Sir, have mercy.
Efendim, merhamet edin.
Ah.
.
Gokce.
Those ointments are easy. Put my daughter on the road.
Şu merhemleri kolay bir yere
koy kızım, yolda oyalamasın elimizi.
Those ointments are easy. Put my daughter on the road.
OK.
Tamam.
Selcan Heavy lifting girl.
Selcan! Ağır kaldırma kızım.
God forbid, you already have pain.
Allah korusun, sancın var zaten.
You know what I thought?
Bak ben ne düşündüm biliyor musun?
With your pregnancy. It's not right for you to stay at the caravan.
Senin bu gebe hâlinle
kervana kalman hiç doğru değil.
With your pregnancy. It's not right for you to stay at the caravan.
Keep moving with us, huh?
Göçe bizimle devam et, ha?
Thank you, mother.
Sağ olasın ana.
I don't know what Gündoğdu would say.
Bilmem ki Gündoğdu ne der.
I don't think he's gonna stand up.
Karşı durmaz herhâlde ama
You're right, the brain is, of course, ask.
haklısın, beyindir tabii, bir sor.
You take that gun.
Siz de şu silahlığı alın hele.
I Gündoğdu'nun.
Gündoğdu'm!
Hayme Ana says my eye. Don't stay behind, you come with us.
Hayme Ana der ki gözüm
arkada kalmasın, sen de bizimle gel.
Hayme Ana says my eye. Don't stay behind, you come with us.
He was worried after last night.
Dün geceden sonra endişelenirmiş.
It is no?.
Hayırdır?
What happened last night?
Dün gece ne olmuş da endişelenirmiş?
I'm in pain.
Sancım tuttu ya!
I get tired in the caravan, baby. thought something would happen to her.
Kervanda yorulurum, bebemin
başına bir şey gelir diye düşünürmüş.
I get tired in the caravan, baby. thought something would happen to her.
You're staying here.
Sen de burada kalıyorsun.
From last night. then I worry.
Dün geceden
sonra ben de endişelenirim.
From last night. then I worry.
I always want to be in front of me.
Hep gözümün önünde ol isterim.
So you'll worry about your son. Let us be with you.
Oğlun için endişelenirsin demek.
Yanında olalım istersin.
So you'll worry about your son. Let us be with you.
Whatever you say, Gündoğdu.
Sen ne dersen Gündoğdu'm.