Where do you come and go? We'il come from Hayy and go to Hu.
-Nereden gelip nereye gidersin?
-Hayy'dan gelip, Hu'ya gideriz.
Where do you come and go? We'il come from Hayy and go to Hu.
What about you?.
Ya sen?
We'il go to Aleppo.
Halep'e gideriz.
So keep your eyes open. Do not feed the bird to the wolf.
Öyleyse, hep gözünüz açık olsun.
Kurda kuşa yem olmayın.
So keep your eyes open. Do not feed the bird to the wolf.
The air around here. Don't get lost in the dust.
Buraların havası
pusludur. Pusta kaybolmayın.
The air around here. Don't get lost in the dust.
Will you forgive me your name?
Bana ismini bağışlar mısın?
Ibn 's of Andalusia.
Endülüslü İbnü'l-Arabî.
It is time.
Vakit geldi.
Horses ?.
Atlar?
The horses are ready.
Atlar hazır.
I buried his saddles under the haystack. We'il saddle up and leave immediately.
Eyerlerini samanlığın altına gömdüm.
Eyerleyip hemen yola çıkacağız.
I buried his saddles under the haystack. We'il saddle up and leave immediately.
There's no guards.
Başlarında nöbetçi yok.
Can you hold on, Dad?
Dayanabilecek misin baba?
We have to do this.
Bunu yapmak zorundayız.
Let the road clear Sun. Don't let your skin get cold .
Yolun açık olsun. Güneş
tenini yakmasın. Yağmur canını üşütmesin.
Let the road clear Sun. Don't let your skin get cold .
Don't let a stone touch your feet Go like water.
Ayağına taş değmesin. Su gibi git
turn to water like obana.
su gibi dön obana.
The Bams.
Is it fits?.
uyuyor mu?
No, Halime thinks about my sister.
Yok. Halime bacımı düşünüyor.
Speak slowly, slow.
Yavaş konuş, yavaş.
You don't talk to me like that.
Ulan bak benimle böyle konuşma.
Enough of silence.
Yeter! Susun.
Come on, sleep now.
Hadi uyuyun artık. Susun!
Relax, Titus.
Rahatla biraz Titus.
Before I was born yesterday.
Dün doğmadan
we're both going to get what we want.
ikimiz de istediğimizi elde edeceğiz.
Enmity, enemies. Black Lark.
Düşmanları küçük görmek,
aptallara mahsustur Kara Toygar.
Enmity, enemies. Black Lark.
From an ingenious ambush.
Ustaca hazırlanmış bir pusudan
no one can survive Titus.
kimse kurtulamaz Titus.
No one.
Hiç kimse.
I'il take care of Crazy Iron. You finish the job quietly.
Deli Demir'i ben hallederim.
Siz işi sessizce bitirin.
I'il take care of Crazy Iron. You finish the job quietly.
Let's.
Hadi.
Turgut.
The boy is dead.
Çocuk öldü.
Yigit Alp.
Yiğit Alp!
Leave them both. Or I'il kill you all.
Ya ikisini de bırakın
ya da hepinizi öldürürüm.
Leave them both. Or I'il kill you all.
Did you think we were stupid? Get out of our way.
Sen bizi aptal mı zannettin?
Çekil yolumuzdan.
Did you think we were stupid? Get out of our way.
I couldn't tell you.
Anlatamadım herhâlde.
You can either leave them both. Or I'il kill you all.
Ya ikisini de bırakırsınız
ya da hepinizi öldürürüm.
You can either leave them both. Or I'il kill you all.
Let me cut the sword. Get out of our way.
Bırak kılıcı. Kızı keserim.
Çekil yolumuzdan.
Let me cut the sword. Get out of our way.
Let me tell you one last time.
Son kez söylüyorum. Bırak!
As Friend Send Yiğit Alp a Message View Yiğit Alp 's Friends.
Yiğit Alp! Yiğit Alp! Yiğit Alp.
Faint, faint.
Bayıl, bayıl.
Love it.
Bayıl.
Who are you?.
Kimsin?
Afshar's.
Afşin.
I'm Deli.
Ben de Deli.
Look at it, man. How does it joke.
Allameye bak be
Nasıl cenk ediyor.
Look at it, man. How does it joke.
But Allen. mallame but makes it sound.
Allame
mallame ama öttürüyor.
But Allen. mallame but makes it sound.
Brother, how is your wound?
Kardeşim, Yaran nasıl?
The arrow remained inside the tip.
Okun ucu içinde kaldı.
Let's get him out now.
Hemen çıkartalım şunu.
We won't be here. Others may come.
Burada olmaz. Hemen gitmeliyiz.
Başkaları da gelebilir.
We won't be here. Others may come.
Ok, it's holding the blood. We'il cut it somewhere else.
Ok, kanı tutuyor.
Başka bir yerde kesip biçeriz.
Ok, it's holding the blood. We'il cut it somewhere else.
These are Black Lark's dirt.
Kara Toygar'ın pislikleri bunlar.
Lets go.
Gidelim.
You screwed this up.
Bu işi berbat ettin.
Your knights first. Then my soldiers.
Önce senin şövalyelerin.
Ardından benim askerlerim.
Your knights first. Then my soldiers.
Killed like a mosquito.
Bir sivrisinek gibi öldürdü.
You and me, Ertugrul. we have made a big mistake in seeing small.
Sen de ben de Ertuğrul'u
küçük görmekle büyük hata yaptık.
You and me, Ertugrul. we have made a big mistake in seeing small.
Never again, to me.
Bir daha bana asla,
Never try to assume command.
asla komutanlık taslamaya kalkma.
I'm doing this. I'll handle it as I know it.
Bu işi ben
bildiğim gibi halledeceğim.
I'm doing this. I'll handle it as I know it.
Not on my land, Titus.
Benim topraklarımda olmaz Titus.
Sultan Alaeddin. if it goes to your ear.
Sultan Alâeddin'in
kulağına giderse
Sultan Alaeddin. if it goes to your ear.
all our plan collapses.
bütün planımız çöker.
I said, &quot;I'm gonna take care of this.&quot;
Bu işi ben halledeceğim dedin. Peki dedim.
You got it in your face.
Eline, yüzüne bulaştırdın.
You missed Ertuğrul.
Ertuğrul'u elinden kaçırdın.
I'm doing this. I will do as I know.
Bu işi ben
bildiğim gibi yapacağım.
I'm doing this. I will do as I know.
My door. Titus always open to you.
Benim kapım
size her zaman açık Titus.
My door. Titus always open to you.
But I say it again.
Ama tekrar söylüyorum.
If you go hunting on my land.
Benim topraklarımda kelle avına çıkarsanız
you are your head.
kellenizden olursunuz.
What about Aleppo?
Ya Halep'te?
What did you think? Every corner of the Islamic world. we have talented feeds from you.
Ne sanmıştın? İslam âleminin her köşesinde
senden yetenekli beslemelerimiz var.
What did you think? Every corner of the Islamic world. we have talented feeds from you.
And know this, Kara Toygar.
Şunu da bil Kara Toygar
Master Azam's dog. I would have already killed you if you weren't.
Üstad-ı Azam'ın köpeği
olmasan seni çoktan öldürürdüm.
Master Azam's dog. I would have already killed you if you weren't.
Hey, big Gundogdu.
Hey gidi koca Gündoğdu.
What about Selcan Hatun?
Ya Gördün mü Selcan Hatun?
Gundogdu like this. You've learned.
Gündoğdu'yu da böyle
terbiye ederler işte. Öğrenmiş oldun.
Gundogdu like this. You've learned.
You don't get angry, you don't get angry. What the hell is this?
Sinirlenmezsin, öfkelenmezsin.
Ne bu hâl Gündoğdu?
You don't get angry, you don't get angry. What the hell is this?
Only. I wait your time, babe.
Sadece
zamanını beklerim hatun.
Only. I wait your time, babe.
Oh Thank God Thank you for your hands health.
Oh Şükür. Ellerine sağlık. Sağ ol.
Enjoy your meal.
Afiyet olsun.
What's on your mind? You won't tell me either?
Ne var aklında?
Bana da mı söylemeyeceksin?
What's on your mind? You won't tell me either?
Babe, I was wrong when I was right.
Hatun, haklıyken haksız duruma düştüm.
Look, I got a punishment on top of that.
Bak, üstüne üstlük bir de ceza aldım.
I don't digest this, babe. When time is come.
Ben bunu hazmetmem hatun.
Zamanı gelince
I don't digest this, babe. When time is come.
all oba Gündoğdu's. who will know who you are.
bütün oba Gündoğdu'nun
kim olduğunu belleyecek.
all oba Gündoğdu's. who will know who you are.
Anger, don't let him get in your head.
Öfken, aklının önüne geçmesin ne olur.
Selcan look, Winter will come at the door.
Selcan bak, kış kapıda. Geldi gelecek.
Kara Lark made his first move.
Kara Toygar ilk hamlesini yaptı.
Do not say; This is Kayi. The people could not even protect their trust, Ha ?.
Demezler mi; bu Kayı
halkı, emanetini bile koruyamadı. Ha?
Do not say; This is Kayi. The people could not even protect their trust, Ha ?.
They won't.
Demezler mi?
Had it not been the merchant's man. We could not even protect our trust.
Tüccarın adamı olmasaydı,
emanetimize bile sahip çıkamayacaktık.
Had it not been the merchant's man. We could not even protect our trust.
You know what that means? What do you mean, Gundogdu ?.
- Bu ne demek biliyor musun sen?
-Ne demek Gündoğdu?
You know what that means? What do you mean, Gundogdu ?.
So this is oba. derelict
Demek ki bu oba
sahipsiz, beysiz, kimsesiz.
So this is oba. derelict
So what?
Ne olacak peki?
Unless I keep quiet.
Sesimi çıkartmıyorsam
If I'm not messing around. of course there is a reason for this.
ortalığı yıkmıyorsam,
bunun bir sebebi var elbet.
If I'm not messing around. of course there is a reason for this.
For now, it's my patience.
Şimdilik bana ya sabır demek düşer.
Come on, babe.
Hadi müsaadenle hatun.
The safety of the oba. I told you to increase.
Sana obanın emniyetini
arttırmanı söylemiştim.
The safety of the oba. I told you to increase.
What did you do? No.
Sen ne yaptın? Hiç.
Because of your incompetence. He pushed the guys into our obo.
Beceriksizliğin yüzünden
o itin adamları obamıza kadar sızdı.
Because of your incompetence. He pushed the guys into our obo.
You've broken your honor and oba.
Obanın da benim de onurumu çiğnettin.
I've maximized the measures. So how did they leak?
-Tedbirleri en üst seviyeye çıkarttım.
-Öyleyse nasıl sızdılar ha?
I've maximized the measures. So how did they leak?
How?.
Nasıl?
Unless someone inside helps. They couldn't leak.
İçeriden biri yardım etmese,
sızamazlardı beyim.
Unless someone inside helps. They couldn't leak.
What does that mean?
Ne demek bu?
Is such a thing possible?
Böyle bir şey mümkün mü Kurdoğlu?
He'il make such a scoundrel. There is no one in our obama.
Böyle bir alçaklığı yapacak
kimse yoktur obamızda beyim.
He'il make such a scoundrel. There is no one in our obama.
Yaverin struggles to save himself.
Yaverin kendini kurtarmak için çırpınır.
Out of your mouth. has become too small to hear.
Ağzından çıkanı
duyamayacak kadar küçülmüştür.
Out of your mouth. has become too small to hear.
You're no longer my friend.
Artık yaverim değilsin.
Gather the guards last night. Wait for my punishment.
Dün geceki nöbetçileri de meydana topla.
Vereceğim cezayı bekleyin.
Gather the guards last night. Wait for my punishment.
Yes, sir.
Emredersin beyim.
Black Lark, hit my obam.
Kara Toygar, obamı basıp
enough to miss our guests. if he dares.
misafirlerimizi kaçıracak kadar
kendinde cüret buluyorsa
enough to miss our guests. if he dares.
Who knows what tomorrow will do?
yarın kim bilir daha neler yapar?
Guys I ,.
Beyim,
Allow ,.
izin ver,
Let me go one more time.
bir kere daha gidip konuşayım.
What happened?
Gittin de ne oldu?
He made a fool out of you.
Seni ahmak yerine koydu.
You still want me to go talk to her.
Hâlâ gidip konuşayım dersin bana.
He's got the size, sir. All the men he sent are dead.
Boyunun ölçüsünü aldı beyim.
Gönderdiği adamların hepsi öldü.
He's got the size, sir. All the men he sent are dead.
Now he'il understand. I can speak language.
Şimdi onun anlayacağı
dilden konuşabilirim.
Now he'il understand. I can speak language.
The language he understands. I know very well.
Onun anlayacağı dili
ben çok iyi biliyorum.
The language he understands. I know very well.
Load your dead on horses and send them back.
Ölülerini atlara yükleyip geri gönderin.
From now on he'il understand. we will speak in language.
Bundan sonra onun anlayacağı
dilden konuşacağız.
From now on he'il understand. we will speak in language.
Master, the entire Seljuk army. What can we do against?
Beyim, koca Selçuklu ordusuna
karşı elimizden ne gelir?
Master, the entire Seljuk army. What can we do against?
Stop saying the army, Kurdoğlu.
Ordu deyip durma, Kurdoğlu.
Kara Toygar's army in Erzincan. it takes days to pack up.
Kara Toygar'ın Erzincan'daki orduyu
toparlayıp gelmesi günler alır.
Kara Toygar's army in Erzincan. it takes days to pack up.
Whereas.
Kaldı ki
Not if Black Lark was a tail pain.
Kara Toygar'ın bir kuyruk acısı olmasa
so far it would have already taken action.
şimdiye kadar çoktan harekete geçerdi.
The deal I made with the Sultan. chewing, going upright.
Sultanla yaptığım anlaşmayı
çiğneyip, kafasının dikine gidiyor.
The deal I made with the Sultan. chewing, going upright.
Whereas. next to a few hundred.
Halbuki
yanındaki birkaç yüz
Whereas. next to a few hundred.
I'm gonna chew on your soldier. enough to know.
askerini çiğneyip geçeceğimi
bilecek kadar asker.
I'm gonna chew on your soldier. enough to know.
And then?.
Ya sonra?
The post depends on Ertuğrul's success.
Sonrası Ertuğrul'un başarısına bağlı.
In one way or another,. whatever he says will be done.
Öyle ya da böyle,
töre ne diyorsa yerine getirilecektir.
In one way or another,. whatever he says will be done.
What about Akcakoca ?.
Ne olacak Akçakoca?
That'il take all the pus of the wound.
Yaranın tüm irinini alır bu.
The thesis is in time. provides healing.
Tez vakitte
iyileşmesini sağlar.
The thesis is in time. provides healing.
Here you go. God willing.
- Al bakalım.
-İnşallah.
Here you go. God willing.
How's he doing? This didn't work out when I was recovering.
-Durumu nasıl peki?
-Tam iyileşirken bu hiç de iyi olmadı.
How's he doing? This didn't work out when I was recovering.
But there's nothing to be afraid of. Do not worry.
Ama korkacak bir şey yok.
Merak etme.
But there's nothing to be afraid of. Do not worry.
A few more days. You'll have trouble.
Birkaç gün daha
sıkıntı çekersin o kadar.
A few more days. You'll have trouble.
When you feel good.
Kendini iyi hissettiğinde
Get out, go, walk ,. Good for a little walk around.
çık dışarı, gez, yürü,
dolaş biraz. İyi gelir.
Get out, go, walk ,. Good for a little walk around.
And this ointment three times a day. Do not forget to put the wound.
Bu merhemi de günde üç defa
yaraya sürmeyi ihmal etmeyin.
And this ointment three times a day. Do not forget to put the wound.
All right, girl?
Tamam mı kızım?
Ah. Thanks Akcakoca.
-Ah
-Sağ olasın Akçakoca.
Ah. Thanks Akcakoca.
Come on, trust in Allah. Thanks Akcakoca.
-Hadi Allah'a emanet olun.
-Sağ olasın Akçakoca.
Come on, trust in Allah. Thanks Akcakoca.
Don't ever bother. Get past being uncomfortable at all.
Hiç rahatsız olma.
Hiç rahatsız olma. Geçmiş olsun.
Don't ever bother. Get past being uncomfortable at all.
Take these, too. eat plenty of father.
Şunları da al,
babaya bol bol yedir.
Take these, too. eat plenty of father.
He should recover, get up.
Hemen iyileşsin, ayağa kalksın.
Not a soul to you. I owe three lives.
Sana bir can değil,
üç can borçluyum.
Not a soul to you. I owe three lives.
Do not mention it.
Estağfurullah.
If you donate your name to me.
Eğer bana adını bağışlarsan
I know the guy I'm grateful for.
minnettar olduğum adamı tanımış olurum.
Come on, lad.
Yaklaş bakalım delikanlı.
What is this?. This necklace belongs to your family.
-Bu ne?
- Bu kolye senin ailene ait.
What is this?. This necklace belongs to your family.
Seljuk dynasty.
Selçuklu hanedanına.
Dogan, Bamsi, get him down now.
Doğan, Bamsı, indirin hemen.
I've had it, sir.
Yettim beyim.
Come on, bro.
Hadi kardeşim.
Ah.
Brother Turgut. Born, Bamsy, Collect wood.
- Turgut kardeş...
- Doğan, Bamsı, odun toplayın.
Brother Turgut. Born, Bamsy, Collect wood.
Come on, drink it.
Hadi iç şunu.
He's lost a lot of blood.
Çok kan kaybetmiş.
Come on, brother, raise your head. Come on, brother.
- Hadi kardeşim. Kaldır başını.
- Hadi kardeş.
Come on, brother, raise your head. Come on, brother.
What happened, son?
Ne oldu evlat?
We've been attacked.
Saldırıya uğradık.
Didn't I tell you, &quot;Be careful, it's misty around here.&quot;
Demedim mi ben sana, "dikkatli ol,
buraların havası pusludur" diye?
Didn't I tell you, &quot;Be careful, it's misty around here.&quot;
Dervish, open the saddle.
Derviş, heybeyi aç.
This blood, I need to stop the thesis.
Bu kanı, tez durdurmak gerek.
Some of the arrow remained inside. We need to get him out first.
Okun bir kısmı içeride kaldı.
İlk önce onu çıkarmamız lazım.
Some of the arrow remained inside. We need to get him out first.
We'il do it, dear.
Hallederiz evelallah.
Who is that?
Kim bu ya?
Hang on, bro.
Dayan kardeşim.
Come on, Bismillah.
Hadi Bismillah.
I hope he lives. Shame, don't open it.
- İnşallah yaşar.
-Bamsı, açma şom ağzını.
I hope he lives. Shame, don't open it.
Don't rush. It would protect you from death.
Telaş etmeyin.
İnsanı ölümden eceli korurmuş.
Don't rush. It would protect you from death.
Your little brother Melik. I served under Rükneddin.
Küçük kardeşiniz Melik
Rükneddin'in emrinde görev yaptım.
Your little brother Melik. I served under Rükneddin.
My name is Şemsettin Afşin Bey.
İsmim de Şemsettin Afşin Bey'dir.
Your brother died in my arms.
Kardeşiniz kollarımda öldü.
The necklace is his necklace.
Kolye de onun kolyesidir.
So you're Afşin Bey.
Demek sen Afşin Bey'sin.
That's right, prince.
Doğrudur şehzadem.
I've heard your name.
Adını duymuşluğum çoktur.
You're a good commander. Do not mention it.
-İyi bir komutanmışsın.
-Estağfurullah.
You're a good commander. Do not mention it.
But how do I know it's you?
Ama senin o olduğunu nereden bileceğim?
Or Sultan Alaeddin. that it is not a game ?.
Ya da Sultan Alâeddin'in
bir oyunu olmadığını?
Or Sultan Alaeddin. that it is not a game ?.
Afşin Bey, why. You risked your life for us ?.
Afşin Bey, neden
bizim için hayatını tehlikeye attın?
Afşin Bey, why. You risked your life for us ?.
Your brother was my prince. But more important than that.
Kardeşiniz benim şehzademdi.
Ama bundan daha önemlisi
Your brother was my prince. But more important than that.
Your attitude towards Sultan Alaeddin.
Sultan Alâeddin'e karşı olan tutumunuz.
With him. you did not enter a war of power.
Onunla
bir iktidar savaşına girmediniz.
With him. you did not enter a war of power.
You were loyal to the state.
Devlete sadık kaldınız.
It will overshadow his achievements. you have avoided movements.
Onun başarılarını gölgeleyecek
hareketlerden kaçındınız.
It will overshadow his achievements. you have avoided movements.
Seljuk with the ambition of power. you did not overshadow its bright days.
İktidar hırsıyla Selçuklunun
parlak günlerine gölge düşürmediniz.
Seljuk with the ambition of power. you did not overshadow its bright days.
That's why I have every respect. You deserve so much, sir.
Bu yüzden her türlü saygıyı
fazlasıyla hak ediyorsunuz efendim.
That's why I have every respect. You deserve so much, sir.
If you'il excuse me.
Müsaadeniz olursa
Get rid of Black Lark. I want to help, sir.
Kara Toygar'dan kurtulmanıza
yardım etmek istiyorum efendim.
Get rid of Black Lark. I want to help, sir.
How? Obviously someone. He paved the way for oboe to Kara Toygar.
Nasıl? Belli ki birisi
Kara Toygar'a obanın yolunu açmış.
How? Obviously someone. He paved the way for oboe to Kara Toygar.
Or your hands and your arms. They couldn't get into shaking obaya.
Yoksa böyle ellerini kollarını
sallayarak giremezlerdi obaya.
Or your hands and your arms. They couldn't get into shaking obaya.
I do not know who you are. But I know what to do.
Kim olduğunu bilmiyorum
ama ne yapacağımı iyi biliyorum.
I do not know who you are. But I know what to do.
Halime.
Hullo.
Maşallah.
May Allah give you peace of mind.
Allah, gönül ferahlığı versin.
Thanks, girl, come here.
Sağ ol kızım. Gel, buyur.
I'il never bother you. I'm your uncle You rest.
Hiç rahatsız etmeyeyim
ben amcacığım. Siz dinlenin.
I'il never bother you. I'm your uncle You rest.
If you'il excuse me, I'm Halime. I'll take a while from you.
Müsaadeniz olursa ben Halime'yi
sizden bir süre ayıracağım.
If you'il excuse me, I'm Halime. I'll take a while from you.
Mother Hayme wondered about you.
Hayme Ana'm merak etti sizleri.
Something to ask. Of course.
- Bir hâl hatır sormak ister.
- Hay hay.
Something to ask. Of course.
Permission is yours.
Müsaade sizin.
Hayme Ana me. asked to see why Aykız ?.
Hayme Ana beni
neden görmek istedi Aykız?
Hayme Ana me. asked to see why Aykız ?.
I don't know either.
Vallahi ben de bilmiyorum.
But there's nothing to worry about, Halime.
Ama tedirgin olacak bir şey yok Halime.
Because of U.S. They're flogging, aren't they?
Bizim yüzümüzden
kırbaçlanıyorlar değil mi?
Because of U.S. They're flogging, aren't they?
They punish this. They deserve more.
Onlar bu cezayı
fazlasıyla hak ettiler Halime.
They punish this. They deserve more.
One of us's honor. is the honor of all of us.
Birimizin namusu,
hepimizin namusudur.
One of us's honor. is the honor of all of us.
Come on.
Hadi gel.
We killed. Muslims had the effect we wanted.
Öldürdüğümüz
Müslümanlar istediğimiz etkiyi yaptı.
We killed. Muslims had the effect we wanted.
All Islam. the world has risen.
Tüm İslam
dünyası ayağa kalkmış durumda.
All Islam. the world has risen.
Soon to Christians. start to attack.
Yakında Hristiyanlara
saldırmaya başlarlar.
Soon to Christians. start to attack.
In Europe, there will be no audience.
Avrupa da buna seyirci kalmayacaktır.
Master, upon us. What will we do when they arrive?
Üstat, bizim üzerimize
geldiklerinde ne yapacağız?
Master, upon us. What will we do when they arrive?
The number of knights and soldiers is certain.
Şövalyeler ve askerlerimizin sayısı belli.
We'il attack them.
Biz de onlara saldıracağız.
I built such an army.
Öyle bir ordu kurdum ki
no army will stand against it.
hiçbir ordu, karşısında duramayacak.
Palestine to Basra. From Baghdad to Aleppo.
Filistin'den Basra'ya,
Bağdat'tan Halep'e kadar her yanı
Palestine to Basra. From Baghdad to Aleppo.
will cover the smell of burned bodies.
yanmış cesetlerin kokusu kaplayacak.
The guests you've been waiting for, sir.
Beklediğiniz misafirler geldi efendim.
Beautiful.
Güzel.
Let me show you my mighty army.
Gelin. Size kudretli ordumu göstereyim.
Gentlemen's son. That's how it happens.
Bey oğlu dediğin,
böyle olur işte.
Gentlemen's son. That's how it happens.
Hamza.
The cost of exceeding my limits. I'm paying emmi.
Haddimi aşmamın bedelini
ödüyorum emmi. Hepsi bu.
The cost of exceeding my limits. I'm paying emmi.
Good for my niece.
Aferin yeğenime.
Last night's bust.
Dün geceki baskın...
It was obvious that Kara Toygar would not be comfortable.
Kara Toygar'ın rahat durmayacağı belliydi.
Your raid last night. Have you heard, emmi ?.
Senin dün geceki baskından
haberin var mı emmi?
Your raid last night. Have you heard, emmi ?.
Who even doubts sucking for his father.
Babası için emmisinden bile şüphe eden
even in the eye. questioning him.
üstelik gözünün içine
baka baka, onu sorgulayan
even in the eye. questioning him.
we have a gentleman, thank goodness.
bir bey oğlumuz var, çok şükür.
Our lord is in the same doubt.
Beyimiz de aynı şüphe içindedir.
We thought our guests were. more valuable.
Misafirlerimiz sandığımızdan
daha değerliymiş meğer.
We thought our guests were. more valuable.
Come to my tent in the evening.
Akşam çadırıma gel. Orada konuşalım.
Without all the trouble. we owe our neck to get out of this.
Dört yanımızı bela sarmadan
bu işten kurtulmak boynumuzun borcu.
Without all the trouble. we owe our neck to get out of this.
Is Hayme Home Destur easy to come ?. Come have my daughter.
-Kolay gele Hayme Ana. Destur var mı?
-Var kızım var. Gel.
Is Hayme Home Destur easy to come ?. Come have my daughter.
Come here. my beautiful girls.
Gelin bakalım
benim güzel kızlarım.
Come here. my beautiful girls.
Get well, girl.
Geçmiş olsun kızım.
Thank God nobody happened.
Çok şükür kimseye bir şey olmamış.
Thank God, Mother.
Çok şükür Hayme Ana.
When my father says he's recovering. but this wound was not good.
Babam tam iyileşiyor derken
bu yara iyi olmadı ama
When my father says he's recovering. but this wound was not good.
thank goodness.
buna da şükür.
Well, these devil nobles. Why are they haunting you ?.
Peki bu şeytan soylular
niye size musallat oldular?
Well, these devil nobles. Why are they haunting you ?.
My father is a merchant.
Babam tacirdir.
Bring goods from the Mediterranean. Crusaders were taken captive while taking them.
Akdeniz'den mal getirip
götürürken Haçlılara esir düştük.
Bring goods from the Mediterranean. Crusaders were taken captive while taking them.
They are us. They wanted to sell it to Kara Toygar.
Onlar da bizi
Kara Toygar'a satmak istediler.
They are us. They wanted to sell it to Kara Toygar.
With all this trouble.
Başınıza bu kadar bela gelmişken
None of you, nobody. is not there? Which boy are you?
sizin hiç kiminiz, kimseniz
yok mu? Siz hangi boydansınız?
None of you, nobody. is not there? Which boy are you?
We're from Kınık Boyu.
Kınık Boyu'ndanız.
You're from Kınık Boyu.
Kınık Boyu'ndansınız.
Founding the Seljuk State. You're a brain strain, huh?
Selçuklu Devleti'ni kuran
beyin soyundansınız, öyle mi?
Founding the Seljuk State. You're a brain strain, huh?
So, who are you in the Kınık Boy?
Peki, Kınık Boyu'nda kimlerdensiniz?
Do you have destur? Come Selcan, girl.
-Destur var mı Hayme Ana'm?
- Var Selcan. Gel kızım.
Do you have destur? Come Selcan, girl.
Did you bring them? I brought it, Ana.
- Getirdin mi basmaları?
- Getirdim ana.
Did you bring them? I brought it, Ana.
The colors are very faded.
Renkler çok soluk.
What did you miss, Selcan ?.
Neyi eksik kullandınız Selcan?
There's not enough weed out because of the drought.
Kuraklık yüzünden yeterince ot bitmiyor.
We paint. had to dilute.
Biz de boyayı
sulandırmak zorunda kaldık.
We paint. had to dilute.
We're trying to get started. but that's it.
Canla başla uğraşıyoruz
ama anca bu kadar oluyor.
We're trying to get started. but that's it.
Indigo leaves. Have you tried the roots ?.
Çivit otunun yapraklarıyla
köklerini denediniz mi?
Indigo leaves. Have you tried the roots ?.
Our merchant daughter knows how much.
Tüccar kızımız ne kadar çok şey biliyor.
Mountain hillside. learned a lot.
Dağ bayır geze geze
çok şey öğrenmiş.
Mountain hillside. learned a lot.
But he forgot he didn't run out of drought.
Ama kuraklıkta ot bitmediğini unutmuş.
Anyway, we would.
Olsa zaten, biz yapardık.
Selcan's right, girl. We need to find another way.
Selcan haklı kızım.
Başka bir çare bulmalıyız.
Selcan's right, girl. We need to find another way.
We have very little time left.
Çok az vaktimiz kaldı.
Take them away before the migration. We need to sell in the market.
Göçten önce, bunları götürüp
pazarda satmamız lazım.
Take them away before the migration. We need to sell in the market.
But we have it. There is no single push to sell.
Ama elimizde
satacak tek bir basma yok.
But we have it. There is no single push to sell.
Selcan, do your best.
Selcan, elinizden geleni yapın.
You can go.
Gidebilirsiniz.
Don't interfere with things that aren't your duty.
Üstüne vazife olmayan şeylere karışma.
You to God's paradise. you are the most beloved servants.
Sizler, tanrının cennetine
gidecek en sevgili kullarsınız.
You to God's paradise. you are the most beloved servants.
Jesus is merciful. You will find peace in your arms.
İsa'nın merhametli
kollarında huzuru bulacaksınız.
Jesus is merciful. You will find peace in your arms.
You've tasted death in life.
Yaşarken ölümü tattınız.
And all your sins when you die. You will taste the peace of purification.
Ölürken de tüm günahlarınızdan
arınmanın huzurunu tadacaksınız.
And all your sins when you die. You will taste the peace of purification.
.
Amen.
Marion.
Rachelle, my dear girl, the peace you seek.
Rachelle, sevgili kızım, aradığın huzuru
you will find in heaven of god.
tanrının cennetinde bulacaksın.
You know how much I trust your intelligence.
Zekâna ne kadar güvendiğimi bilirsin.
I gave you the hardest job for him.
Onun için sana en zor görevi verdim.
Your mission will be the obesity of the apricots.
Senin görev yerin, Kayıların obası olacak.
My two knights. will accompany you.
İki şövalyem
sana eşlik edecek.
My two knights. will accompany you.
My whole life. Passed in agony, sir.
Bütün hayatım
ıstırap içinde geçti efendim.
My whole life. Passed in agony, sir.
But my death. He will be honored by the love of Jesus Christ.
Ama ölümüm,
Yüce İsa'nın aşkıyla şerefli olacak.
But my death. He will be honored by the love of Jesus Christ.
My innocent lambs, keep your path clear.
Masum kuzularım, yolunuz açık olsun.
What you're trying to do. We couldn't understand, sir.
Ne yapmaya çalıştığınızı
anlayamadık efendim.
What you're trying to do. We couldn't understand, sir.
The plague, my dear knight.
Veba, sevgili şövalyem.
This mighty little army.
Bu küçük kudretli ordum
to the whole Islamic world. will spread the curse of the devil.
tüm İslam dünyasına
şeytanın lanetini yayacak.
to the whole Islamic world. will spread the curse of the devil.
Stop, stop, don't bother.
Dur dur, dur hele. Sıkma canını.
There is a way Come, sit down.
Var bir yolu. Gel, otur şöyle.
Look, girl.
Bak kızım,
palace years ago. old
yıllar önce sarayın
yaşlı kadınlarından biri
palace years ago. old
to make the colors look more vivid.
renkler daha canlı görünsün diye
had done something.
bir şey yapmıştı.
The whole palace was stunned.
Bütün saray şaşırıp kalmıştı bu işe.
Even the grandfather of the late sultan what menem. a job he was interested in.
Rahmetli sultan deden bile ne menem
bir iş diye ilgilenmişti olan bitenle.
Even the grandfather of the late sultan what menem. a job he was interested in.
Everyone opposed the poor woman.
Herkes karşı çıkmıştı zavallı kadına.
He kept it so beautiful. tint
O kadar güzel tutmuştu ki
basmanın boyası--
He kept it so beautiful. tint
Tell me what he did, Dad.
Ne yaptı baba, anlat.
That's years ago.
İşte böyle. Seneler evvel
We left from Andalusia, that exit.
Endülüs'ten bir çıktık, çıkış o çıkış.
What made you from your country, dervish?
Sizi yurdunuzdan eden neydi derviş?
A dream.
Bir rüya.
He's been calling me for years. chasing the divine call.
Beni senelerdir diyar diyar
dolaştıran ilahi çağrının peşindeyim.
He's been calling me for years. chasing the divine call.
An Andalusian. There is a boy, Dogan brother ?.
Endülüs diye bir
boy mu vardır, Doğan kardeş?
An Andalusian. There is a boy, Dogan brother ?.
You never heard of Andalusia, Bame?
Endülüs'ü hiç duymadın mı Bamsı?
No sister. I swear.
-Hiç kardeş.
- Vallahi mi?
No sister. I swear.
Am I gonna lie? Sometimes it's his head.
- Yalan mı söyleyeceğim lan?
-Bazen o başını
Am I gonna lie? Sometimes it's his head.
I think why you carry. Doesn't he put weight on his body?
niye taşıyorsun diye düşünüyorum.
O vücuduna ağırlık yapmıyor mu?
I think why you carry. Doesn't he put weight on his body?
Come on.
Hadi oradan!
And you son? Why Aleppo?
Ya siz evlat? Halep neden?
We were sent as an ambassador to Emir El Aziz.
Emir El Aziz'e elçi olarak gönderildik.
Well somehow we can't go.
De bir türlü gidemezük.
I hope you'il go.
Gidersiniz inşallah.
The friend of the Prophet,. Hazrat Abu Bakr.
Hazreti Peygamber'in dostu,
Hazreti Ebu Bekir
The friend of the Prophet,. Hazrat Abu Bakr.
while taking refuge in a cave. The polytheists are after them.
hicret ederken bir mağaraya sığınır.
Müşrikler de peşindedir.
while taking refuge in a cave. The polytheists are after them.
They find the path to the cave.
Mağaraya giden yolun izini bulurlar.
The companion of the Prophet. Abu Bakr is anxious.
Peygamberin yol arkadaşı,
Ebu Bekir tedirgindir.
The companion of the Prophet. Abu Bakr is anxious.
The Prophet says to him:. &quot;Fear not, Abu Bakr Allah is with us&quot;.
Peygamber efendimiz ona der ki:
"Korkma ya Ebu Bekir. Allah bizimledir."
The Prophet says to him:. &quot;Fear not, Abu Bakr Allah is with us&quot;.
There's a tiny spider. weave them the most protected armor in the world.
Orada küçücük bir örümcek,
onlara dünyanın en korunaklı zırhını örer.
There's a tiny spider. weave them the most protected armor in the world.
So that's the point.
Yani mesele
God the way we lead ourselves. Did we act or not?
Allah'ı kendimize yol dostu
eyledik mi, eylemedik mi?
God the way we lead ourselves. Did we act or not?
If we act ,. every road opens, every road leads.
Eylediysek,
her yol açılır, her yol gidilir.
If we act ,. every road opens, every road leads.
September were unable ,. our comrade becomes the devil.
Eylemediysek,
yoldaşımız şeytan olur.
September were unable ,. our comrade becomes the devil.
Esselamu alikum.
Esselamü aleyküm.
Oh, the devil.
Aha şeytan.
What about a hush, without you?
Ya bir sus, densiz.
And alikumselam.
Ve aleykümselam.
We saw the fire, we came.
Ateşi gördük geldik. Müsaade var mıdır?
Come to our table.
Buyurun, gelin soframıza.
Black Lark ,. Since he can attack obaya so easily.
Kara Toygar,
obaya bu kadar rahat saldırabildiğine göre
Black Lark ,. Since he can attack obaya so easily.
There must be a spy inside.
içeride bir casusu olmalı.
Nobody in the skies.
Kayı obasında hiç kimse
He wouldn't risk it for Kara Lark.
Kara Toygar için bunu göze almaz.
What did you talk to Kara Toygar?
Siz ne konuştunuz Kara Toygar'la?
I asked him for respite. To convince Suleyman Shah.
Ondan mühlet istedim.
Süleyman Şah'ı ikna etmek için.
I asked him for respite. To convince Suleyman Shah.
He attacked before his deadline was over.
Verdiği mühlet bitmeden saldırıya geçti.
People who took refuge in us. even unable to protect.
Bize sığınan insanları
bile korumaktan aciziz.
People who took refuge in us. even unable to protect.
Old age,. He left Solomon Shah unwarranted.
İhtiyarlık,
Süleyman Şah'ı mecalsiz bıraktı.
Old age,. He left Solomon Shah unwarranted.
The obity of the oba and. union is going to hand.
Obanın dirliği ve
birliği elden gidiyor Gündoğdu.
The obity of the oba and. union is going to hand.
If we don't take precautions, the big Belongs will fall apart.
Önlem almazsak, koca Kayı Boyu dağılacak.
He's my father.
O benim babamdır.
But the future of the neck is more important.
Ama boyun geleceği daha önemli.
What's on your mind?
Nedir kafandan geçen?
Ertuğrul's from Aleppo. I will wait for him to return.
Ertuğrul'un Halep'ten
dönmesini bekleyeceğim.
Ertuğrul's from Aleppo. I will wait for him to return.
You emptyhanded. If it turns, I won't stop for a moment.
Eğer eli boş
dönerse, bir an bile durmam.
You emptyhanded. If it turns, I won't stop for a moment.
What about your father?
Peki ya baban?
My father is my life, my blood.
Babam canımdır, kanımdır.
But Oguz ceremony. Whatever he says, I do.
Ama Oğuz töresi
neyi söylerse, onu yaparım.
But Oguz ceremony. Whatever he says, I do.
Oguz ceremony, to hear. He knows a lot, son.
Oğuz töresi, duymasını
bilene çok şey söyler evlat.
Oguz ceremony, to hear. He knows a lot, son.
Hungry for days. We are miserable.
Günlerdir aç bitap
yollardayız. Perişan olduk.
Hungry for days. We are miserable.
But thank God,. brought you out.
Ama şükür Allah'ıma,
sizleri karşımıza çıkardı.
But thank God,. brought you out.
It's unclear where the fortune comes from.
Kısmetin nereden çıkacağı belli olmazmış.
I swear.
Vallahi
Where the trouble comes from.
belanın da nereden geleceği.
What's up?. Something bad happened to you?
Hayırdır?
Başınıza kötü bir şey mi geldi?
What's up?. Something bad happened to you?
Crusaders carrying goods in my caravan.
Kervanımda mal taşırken, Haçlılar...
I was attacked by those Templars.
Şu Tapınakçıların saldırısına uğradım.
They found the square empty. they are haunted everywhere.
Bunlar da meydanı boş buldular,
her yere dadanır oldular.
They found the square empty. they are haunted everywhere.
Last time a mockery. We crushed the Crusader.
Geçen sefer bir alay
dolusu Haçlıyı tepeledik.
Last time a mockery. We crushed the Crusader.
We killed their regiment.
Alayını geberttik hepsinin.
Health in your hands.
Ellerine sağlık.
These Crusaders.
Bu Haçlılar
They also took courage from Muslims. sword shakes on the territory.
kimden cesaret aldılar da Müslüman
topraklarında kılıç sallar oldular?
They also took courage from Muslims. sword shakes on the territory.
Those gavurlar.
O gâvurlar
a new Crusade. They were in preparation.
yeni bir Haçlı Seferi
hazırlığı içindeymişler.
a new Crusade. They were in preparation.
The whole Christian world. To draw to Jerusalem.
Bütün Hristiyan dünyasını
Kudüs'e çekmek için
The whole Christian world. To draw to Jerusalem.
activated.
harekete geçirmişler.
I hear he's a Muslim. important managers of states.
Duyduğum kadarıyla Müslüman
devletlerin önemli yöneticilerini
I hear he's a Muslim. important managers of states.
kill one by one.
birer birer öldürüp...
lifeless bodies city. squares.
...cansız bedenlerini şehir
meydanlarına bırakmışlar.
lifeless bodies city. squares.
You know, we're a feast.
Desene bize şenlik çıktı.
We also have a welcome at that time. We will prepare them, huh?
Biz de o zaman bir karşılama
hazırlayacağız onlara ha?
We also have a welcome at that time. We will prepare them, huh?
Divine lord.
İlahi beyim.
How will that be?
Bu senin dediğin nasıl olacak?
Muslims only draw swords to each other.
Müslümanlar ancak birbirine kılıç çeker
kill each other.
birbirlerini öldürürler.
Up worry.
Tasalanma.
Allah will bring forth a valiant. Under the banner unites the whole world.
Allah bir yiğit çıkarır, onun
sancağı altında tüm âlemi birleştirir.
Allah will bring forth a valiant. Under the banner unites the whole world.
Both his sons and Constantine. conquers, takes Jerusalem,.
Onun evlatları da Konstantiniyye'yi de
fetheder, Kudüs'ü de alır,
Both his sons and Constantine. conquers, takes Jerusalem,.
It also serves Mecca and Medina.
Mekke'yle Medine'ye de hizmet eder.
I hope we do too. Thank you under the banner of that brave.
İnşallah biz de
o yiğidin sancağı altında cenk ederiz.
I hope we do too. Thank you under the banner of that brave.
God willing.
İnşallah.
I hope you're right.
İnşallah haklısınızdır.
Hopefully, my Lord, that brave moment. we will relax before we send.
İnşallah Rabb'im o yiğidi bir an
evvel gönderir de biz de rahatlarız.
Hopefully, my Lord, that brave moment. we will relax before we send.
He shared his bite to me.
Bana lokmasını paylaşan
this is more valuable than each other. I want to know your friends of Allah.
bu birbirinden değerli
Allah dostlarını tanımak isterim.
this is more valuable than each other. I want to know your friends of Allah.
I am Ibn 's from Andalusia.
Ben Endülüslü İbnü'l-Arabî.
Ertuğrul by the neck.
Kayı boyundan Ertuğrul.